Are	O
tourists	O
enticed	O
by	O
these	O
attractions	O
threatening	O
their	O
very	O
existence	O
?	O

The	O
two	O
young	O
sea-lions	O
took	O
not	O
the	O
slightest	O
interest	O
in	O
our	O
arrival	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
playing	O
on	O
the	O
jetty	O
,	O
rolling	O
over	O
and	O
tumbling	O
into	O
the	O
water	O
together	O
,	O
entirely	O
ignoring	O
the	O
human	O
beings	O
edging	O
awkwardly	O
round	O
them	O
.	O

Our	O
party	O
then	O
had	O
to	O
step	O
gingerly	O
over	O
hundreds	O
of	O
marine	O
iguanas	O
basking	O
on	O
the	O
rocks	O
,	O
strange	O
creatures	O
with	O
richly	O
coloured	O
velvet	O
coats	O
,	O
looking	O
like	O
something	O
between	O
a	O
giant	O
lizard	O
and	O
a	O
miniature	O
dinosaur	O
,	O
and	O
found	O
nowhere	O
else	O
on	O
earth	O
except	O
here	O
in	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
.	O

A	O
little	O
further	O
on	O
were	O
the	O
blue-footed	O
boobies	O
,	O
birds	O
with	O
brilliant	O
china-blue	O
feet	O
,	O
again	O
unique	O
.	O

And	O
then	O
there	O
were	O
the	O
flightless	O
cormorants	O
,	O
birds	O
with	O
vestigial	O
wings	O
who	O
,	O
over	O
the	O
generations	O
,	O
have	O
lost	O
the	O
ability	O
to	O
fly	O
because	O
the	O
nutrients	O
at	O
the	O
shoreline	O
are	O
so	O
rich	O
they	O
have	O
no	O
need	O
to	O
leave	O
.	O

The	O
island	O
of	O
Fernandina	B-LOC
lies	O
at	O
the	O
far	O
western	O
edge	O
of	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
archipelago	O
,	O
dominated	O
by	O
a	O
volcano	O
that	O
last	O
erupted	O
only	O
six	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
and	O
home	O
to	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
remarkable	O
wildlife	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
late	O
afternoon	O
on	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
last	O
days	O
of	O
the	O
year	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
had	O
come	O
ashore	O
to	O
scramble	O
round	O
the	O
rough	O
dark	O
lava	O
rocks	O
of	O
Punta	B-LOC
Espinosa	I-LOC
on	O
the	O
island	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
golden	O
afternoon	O
light	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
moon	O
rising	O
above	O
the	O
volcanoes	O
on	O
Isabela	B-LOC
Island	I-LOC
across	O
the	O
strait	O
,	O
we	O
could	O
be	O
forgiven	O
for	O
thinking	O
that	O
we	O
were	O
guests	O
in	O
paradise	O
.	O

The	O
creatures	O
you	O
see	O
in	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
are	O
remarkable	O
in	O
their	O
rarity	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
even	O
more	O
so	O
for	O
their	O
lack	O
of	O
fear	O
.	O

They	O
do	O
n't	O
run	O
away	O
.	O

They	O
carry	O
on	O
basking	O
or	O
playing	O
or	O
mating	O
or	O
incubating	O
their	O
eggs	O
or	O
fighting	O
for	O
territory	O
with	O
blissful	O
disregard	O
for	O
human	O
beings	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
as	O
if	O
you	O
are	O
walking	O
into	O
a	O
David	B-PER
Attenborough	I-PER
programme	O
,	O
and	O
finding	O
that	O
the	O
real	O
thing	O
is	O
even	O
better	O
than	O
you	O
ever	O
imagined	O
.	O

The	O
closeness	O
of	O
the	O
living	O
natural	O
world	O
,	O
in	O
this	O
environment	O
of	O
volcanic	O
rock	O
and	O
sweeping	O
beaches	O
and	O
sparse	O
vegetation	O
,	O
makes	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
experience	O
special	O
.	O

The	O
colours	O
help	O
,	O
too	O
.	O

The	O
intense	O
black	O
of	O
the	O
rock	O
,	O
the	O
startling	O
blue	O
of	O
sea	O
and	O
sky	O
,	O
the	O
crimson	O
of	O
the	O
mating	O
frigate-birds	O
,	O
the	O
yellow	O
of	O
the	O
warblers	O
,	O
the	O
brilliant	O
orange	O
of	O
the	O
American	O
oyster-catchers	O
,	O
the	O
glistening	O
silver	O
of	O
hundreds	O
of	O
dolphins	O
swooping	O
round	O
your	O
ship	O
in	O
the	O
dawn	O
light	O
.	O

We	O
spent	O
eight	O
days	O
in	O
all	O
,	O
aboard	O
a	O
boat	O
called	O
Tropic	O
Sun	O
,	O
visiting	O
all	O
parts	O
of	O
the	O
islands	O
.	O

We	O
lived	O
,	O
ate	O
and	O
slept	O
on	O
the	O
boat	O
and	O
went	O
ashore	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
times	O
a	O
day	O
,	O
to	O
walk	O
the	O
trails	O
,	O
see	O
the	O
wildlife	O
,	O
and	O
snorkel	O
in	O
the	O
sea	O
.	O

The	O
boat	O
was	O
hardly	O
the	O
most	O
luxurious	O
experience	O
we	O
'd	O
ever	O
had	O
,	O
and	O
was	O
certainly	O
not	O
a	O
centre	O
of	O
gastronomic	O
excellence	O
.	O

But	O
that	O
really	O
was	O
n't	O
the	O
point	O
.	O

It	O
took	O
us	O
to	O
the	O
places	O
we	O
wanted	O
to	O
see	O
;	O
and	O
the	O
expert	O
guide	O
we	O
had	O
,	O
who	O
led	O
us	O
round	O
the	O
trails	O
and	O
explained	O
the	O
flora	O
and	O
fauna	O
to	O
us	O
,	O
was	O
the	O
best	O
we	O
could	O
possibly	O
have	O
wanted	O
.	O

You	O
need	O
not	O
be	O
an	O
inveterate	O
birdwatcher	O
or	O
naturalist	O
to	O
be	O
captivated	O
by	O
what	O
you	O
see	O
.	O

You	O
simply	O
can	O
not	O
help	O
being	O
taken	O
over	O
by	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
wonder	O
at	O
this	O
different	O
and	O
special	O
world	O
.	O

Darwin	B-PER
's	O
visit	O
,	O
in	O
1835	O
,	O
aboard	O
HMS	O
Beagle	O
lasted	O
five	O
times	O
longer	O
.	O

He	O
marvelled	O
at	O
the	O
tortoises	O
and	O
the	O
iguanas	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
was	O
the	O
tiny	O
finches	O
that	O
jolted	O
his	O
imagination	O
most	O
vividly	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
still	O
called	O
Darwin	B-PER
's	O
Finches	O
in	O
his	O
honour	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
13	O
different	O
species	O
of	O
the	O
finches	O
across	O
the	O
islands	O
(	O
our	O
group	O
managed	O
to	O
see	O
five	O
or	O
six	O
)	O
.	O

The	O
fascination	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
beaks	O
.	O

Each	O
species	O
on	O
each	O
island	O
has	O
,	O
over	O
time	O
,	O
developed	O
a	O
differently	O
shaped	O
beak	O
,	O
adapted	O
to	O
the	O
vegetation	O
and	O
the	O
competition	O
in	O
that	O
particular	O
location	O
.	O

These	O
tiny	O
birds	O
with	O
tiny	O
distinctions	O
helped	O
to	O
produce	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
greatest	O
ever	O
advances	O
in	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
scientific	O
thought	O
.	O

Since	O
Darwin	B-PER
called	O
,	O
these	O
islands	O
on	O
the	O
Equator	B-LOC
have	O
struggled	O
to	O
maintain	O
the	O
fragile	O
balance	O
of	O
their	O
ecology	O
.	O

Over	O
the	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
indigenous	O
animal	O
population	O
has	O
been	O
under	O
increasing	O
threat	O
,	O
from	O
wayward	O
fishermen	O
,	O
or	O
from	O
feral	O
dogs	O
,	O
goats	O
and	O
rats	O
escaping	O
from	O
human	O
settlements	O
or	O
boats	O
.	O

Recently	O
the	O
Ecuador	B-LOC
authorities	O
started	O
trying	O
to	O
eradicate	O
the	O
invading	O
species	O
,	O
and	O
have	O
now	O
succeeded	O
in	O
freeing	O
some	O
entire	O
islands	O
from	O
non-native	O
creatures	O
.	O

A	O
giant	O
tortoise	O
breeding	O
programme	O
is	O
in	O
place	O
,	O
rearing	O
infants	O
in	O
a	O
protected	O
environment	O
at	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
they	O
are	O
at	O
greatest	O
risk	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
returning	O
them	O
to	O
the	O
wild	O
.	O

And	O
there	O
are	O
strict	O
laws	O
now	O
in	O
place	O
against	O
harming	O
or	O
destroying	O
the	O
wildlife	O
-	O
though	O
only	O
recently	O
a	O
group	O
of	O
12	O
slain	O
tortoises	O
was	O
discovered	O
killed	O
apparently	O
for	O
the	O
Japanese	O
aphrodisiac	O
market	O
.	O

The	O
most	O
serious	O
ecological	O
threat	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
is	O
posed	O
by	O
the	O
greatest	O
economic	O
boon	O
the	O
islands	O
have	O
ever	O
had	O
:	O
tourism	O
.	O

Ninety	O
boats	O
,	O
ranging	O
in	O
size	O
from	O
12	O
passengers	O
to	O
100	O
,	O
do	O
the	O
rounds	O
of	O
the	O
islands	O
.	O

And	O
on	O
the	O
whole	O
,	O
the	O
schedules	O
are	O
managed	O
well	O
.	O

The	O
itineraries	O
are	O
staggered	O
,	O
so	O
that	O
at	O
most	O
two	O
or	O
three	O
boats	O
might	O
appear	O
at	O
one	O
location	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
.	O

When	O
you	O
go	O
ashore	O
you	O
have	O
to	O
be	O
with	O
a	O
guide	O
,	O
you	O
can	O
not	O
stray	O
from	O
the	O
marked	O
trails	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
can	O
not	O
touch	O
the	O
wildlife	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
passengers	O
on	O
our	O
boat	O
was	O
roundly	O
and	O
rightly	O
chastised	O
for	O
stroking	O
a	O
young	O
sea-lion	O
-	O
an	O
action	O
with	O
potentially	O
fatal	O
consequences	O
for	O
the	O
sea-lion	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
rejection	O
by	O
the	O
mother	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
country	O
as	O
poor	O
as	O
Ecuador	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
temptation	O
to	O
increase	O
the	O
numbers	O
of	O
tourists	O
is	O
always	O
there	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
told	O
there	O
's	O
been	O
a	O
recent	O
request	O
for	O
permission	O
for	O
a	O
much	O
larger	O
boat	O
to	O
travel	O
round	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
,	O
carrying	O
some	O
500	O
passengers	O
.	O

I	O
shudder	O
to	O
think	O
what	O
might	O
happen	O
if	O
such	O
a	O
boat	O
arrived	O
at	O
Punta	B-LOC
Espinosa	I-LOC
and	O
disgorged	O
everyone	O
on	O
to	O
Fernandina	B-LOC
Island	I-LOC
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
.	O

Not	O
only	O
would	O
the	O
shock	O
of	O
a	O
thousand	O
tramping	O
feet	O
endanger	O
the	O
rock	O
,	O
the	O
sand	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
teeming	O
wildlife	O
that	O
depends	O
on	O
it	O
;	O
but	O
it	O
would	O
seriously	O
degrade	O
the	O
quality	O
of	O
the	O
visitors	O
'	O
own	O
experience	O
.	O

Herein	O
lies	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
oldest	O
dilemmas	O
about	O
the	O
evolution	O
of	O
tourism	O
.	O

We	O
value	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
want	O
to	O
visit	O
,	O
the	O
unique	O
and	O
fragile	O
environments	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Yet	O
in	O
visiting	O
we	O
risk	O
destroying	O
the	O
very	O
qualities	O
that	O
render	O
those	O
places	O
so	O
enticing	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
especially	O
TRUE	O
where	O
the	O
rarity	O
of	O
the	O
place	O
is	O
quite	O
so	O
marked	O
as	O
it	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
.	O

Responsible	O
tourism	O
lies	O
in	O
absolute	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
location	O
and	O
its	O
inhabitants	O
.	O

It	O
lies	O
in	O
treading	O
carefully	O
wherever	O
we	O
go	O
.	O

It	O
lies	O
in	O
ensuring	O
that	O
the	O
economic	O
contribution	O
we	O
make	O
by	O
going	O
helps	O
to	O
conserve	O
rather	O
than	O
to	O
destroy	O
.	O

And	O
it	O
lies	O
in	O
developing	O
the	O
international	O
networks	O
protecting	O
endangered	O
species	O
and	O
world	O
heritage	O
so	O
that	O
they	O
can	O
make	O
a	O
difference	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
.	O

Fortunately	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
Galapagos	B-LOC
,	O
Charles	B-PER
Darwin	I-PER
would	O
recognise	O
much	O
of	O
what	O
he	O
saw	O
if	O
he	O
returned	O
today	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
our	O
duty	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
he	O
would	O
recognise	O
it	O
again	O
,	O
another	O
two	O
centuries	O
hence	O
.	O

``	O
For	O
the	O
last	O
three	O
weeks	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
an	O
utterly	O
inexplicable	O
rise	O
in	O
the	O
prison	O
population	O
of	O
about	O
600	O
prisoners	O
a	O
week	O
.	O
''	O

The	O
words	O
of	O
Martin	B-PER
Narey	I-PER
,	O
the	O
director-general	O
of	O
the	O
Prison	B-ORG
Service	I-ORG
,	O
ought	O
to	O
prompt	O
more	O
than	O
the	O
customary	O
political	O
panic	O
.	O

By	O
this	O
morning	O
the	O
prison	O
population	O
,	O
which	O
seemed	O
to	O
have	O
stabilised	O
at	O
around	O
45,000	O
in	O
the	O
late	O
1980s	O
and	O
early	O
1990s	O
,	O
will	O
have	O
passed	O
the	O
70,000	O
mark	O
.	O

Although	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
the	O
surge	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
three	O
weeks	O
have	O
baffled	O
those	O
who	O
might	O
know	O
,	O
the	O
underlying	O
trend	O
,	O
a	O
rise	O
in	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
prisoners	O
of	O
5,000	O
since	O
this	O
time	O
last	O
year	O
,	O
is	O
utterly	O
explicable	O
,	O
and	O
indeed	O
was	O
predicted	O
.	O

Prison	O
policy	O
in	O
the	O
UK	B-LOC
has	O
been	O
an	O
uphill	O
slalom	O
for	O
the	O
past	O
half-century	O
.	O

Politicians	O
,	O
under	O
pressure	O
to	O
do	O
something	O
about	O
crime	O
,	O
pass	O
laws	O
and	O
write	O
guidelines	O
requiring	O
more	O
criminals	O
to	O
be	O
imprisoned	O
for	O
more	O
crimes	O
for	O
longer	O
.	O

Every	O
now	O
and	O
then	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
crisis	O
as	O
the	O
walls	O
of	O
our	O
prisons	O
begin	O
to	O
bow	O
under	O
the	O
weight	O
of	O
numbers	O
contained	O
therein	O
.	O

Politicians	O
then	O
scrabble	O
around	O
for	O
``	O
tough	O
''	O
alternatives	O
to	O
jail	O
,	O
which	O
they	O
try	O
to	O
sell	O
to	O
a	O
sceptical	O
public	O
,	O
educated	O
only	O
in	O
a	O
simple	O
lock-'em-up	O
logic	O
that	O
reached	O
its	O
conclusion	O
in	O
the	O
bone-jarring	O
stupidity	O
of	O
Michael	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
's	O
``	O
prison	O
works	O
''	O
slogan	O
.	O

The	O
prison-building	O
programme	O
then	O
catches	O
up	O
with	O
the	O
prison	O
population	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
resume	O
the	O
zig-zag	O
which	O
has	O
given	O
us	O
the	O
least	O
successful	O
prison	O
policy	O
in	O
Europe	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
election	O
of	O
a	O
Labour	B-ORG
government	I-ORG
committed	O
to	O
being	O
tough	O
on	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
crime	O
was	O
a	O
chance	O
to	O
break	O
this	O
self-	O
defeating	O
sequence	O
.	O

Unfortunately	O
,	O
Tony	B-PER
Blair	I-PER
's	O
first	O
Home	O
Secretary	O
,	O
Jack	B-PER
Straw	I-PER
,	O
lacked	O
the	O
courage	O
to	O
seize	O
it	O
.	O

David	B-PER
Blunkett	I-PER
is	O
a	O
more	O
adventurous	O
figure	O
and	O
shows	O
some	O
signs	O
of	O
being	O
willing	O
to	O
challenge	O
the	O
assumptions	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
,	O
but	O
he	O
still	O
poses	O
too	O
often	O
for	O
the	O
unitive	O
gallery	O
.	O

At	O
least	O
he	O
will	O
have	O
no	O
difficulty	O
in	O
rejecting	O
a	O
demand	O
from	O
the	O
Prison	B-ORG
Governors	I-ORG
'	I-ORG
Association	I-ORG
to	O
take	O
away	O
from	O
magistrates	O
altogether	O
the	O
power	O
to	O
hand	O
down	O
custodial	O
sentences	O
.	O

But	O
will	O
he	O
use	O
this	O
crisis	O
to	O
ask	O
deeper	O
questions	O
about	O
why	O
so	O
many	O
people	O
are	O
in	O
prison	O
,	O
and	O
whether	O
they	O
should	O
be	O
?	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
the	O
rise	O
in	O
the	O
prison	O
population	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
seven	O
years	O
has	O
been	O
the	O
growth	O
of	O
illegal	O
drug	O
use	O
,	O
with	O
crack	O
cocaine	O
a	O
particular	O
problem	O
.	O

This	O
week	O
's	O
suggestion	O
that	O
shock	O
tactics	O
should	O
be	O
used	O
to	O
discourage	O
young	O
people	O
from	O
trying	O
heroin	O
is	O
off	O
the	O
point	O
.	O

Information	O
is	O
important	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
interplay	O
between	O
the	O
desire	O
to	O
escape	O
reality	O
and	O
addiction	O
is	O
more	O
complex	O
than	O
a	O
simple	O
Pavlovian	O
model	O
.	O

Medicalising	O
addiction	O
rather	O
than	O
keeping	O
it	O
in	O
the	O
criminal	O
underworld	O
offers	O
the	O
best	O
hope	O
both	O
of	O
controlling	O
hard-drug	O
use	O
and	O
of	O
limiting	O
the	O
effect	O
on	O
crime	O
.	O

If	O
people	O
who	O
have	O
problems	O
with	O
illegal	O
drugs	O
,	O
alcohol	O
or	O
mental	O
health	O
were	O
taken	O
out	O
of	O
our	O
prisons	O
,	O
there	O
would	O
be	O
hardly	O
anyone	O
left	O
.	O

When	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
the	O
wider	O
causes	O
of	O
crime	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
best	O
places	O
to	O
start	O
is	O
prison	O
itself	O
.	O

With	O
58	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
inmates	O
recorded	O
as	O
reoffending	O
within	O
two	O
years	O
of	O
release	O
,	O
prison	O
clearly	O
does	O
not	O
work	O
.	O

A	O
brave	O
Home	O
Secretary	O
would	O
conclude	O
that	O
prison	O
obviously	O
reinforces	O
many	O
of	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
crime	O
.	O

It	O
breaks	O
up	O
families	O
and	O
usually	O
gives	O
prisoners	O
nothing	O
better	O
to	O
do	O
than	O
plan	O
how	O
not	O
to	O
get	O
caught	O
next	O
time	O
.	O

All	O
parties	O
welcomed	O
the	O
Woolf	O
report	O
of	O
1991	O
,	O
yet	O
none	O
has	O
acted	O
on	O
it	O
to	O
improve	O
the	O
education	O
service	O
in	O
prison	O
.	O

If	O
schoolchildren	O
can	O
have	O
life	O
coaches	O
,	O
why	O
not	O
prisoners	O
?	O

Instead	O
,	O
education	O
,	O
anger-management	O
courses	O
and	O
anything	O
constructive	O
are	O
often	O
the	O
first	O
things	O
to	O
be	O
cut	O
when	O
governors	O
come	O
under	O
pressure	O
to	O
save	O
money	O
.	O

Our	O
prison	O
system	O
is	O
an	O
affront	O
to	O
a	O
civilised	O
society	O
,	O
as	O
is	O
witnessed	O
by	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
legal	O
actions	O
brought	O
by	O
prisoners	O
under	O
the	O
Human	O
Rights	O
Act	O
.	O

Even	O
if	O
the	O
voters	O
did	O
not	O
care	O
about	O
that	O
,	O
they	O
should	O
care	O
that	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
very	O
expensive	O
way	O
of	O
training	O
criminals	O
for	O
more	O
crime	O
.	O

Many	O
of	O
the	O
alternatives	O
to	O
prison	O
may	O
not	O
result	O
in	O
much	O
better	O
reoffending	O
rates	O
,	O
but	O
at	O
least	O
they	O
are	O
cheaper	O
.	O

Mr	O
Blunkett	B-PER
should	O
make	O
the	O
radically	O
pragmatic	O
case	O
for	O
the	O
humane	O
treatment	O
of	O
the	O
nation	O
's	O
criminals	O
as	O
a	O
first	O
step	O
in	O
tackling	O
the	O
causes	O
of	O
crime	O
.	O

Here	O
's	O
something	O
to	O
chew	O
over	O
when	O
pondering	O
the	O
growing	O
problem	O
of	O
obese	O
children	O
.	O

The	O
fattest	O
child	O
in	O
my	O
daughter	O
's	O
primary	O
school	O
class	O
was	O
also	O
the	O
cleverest	O
.	O

Her	O
mother	O
came	O
from	O
Kuala	B-LOC
Lumpur	I-LOC
and	O
latched	O
onto	O
me	O
as	O
a	O
fellow	O
Eurasian	O
when	O
we	O
waited	O
to	O
collect	O
our	O
children	O
after	O
school	O
.	O

Far	O
from	O
being	O
worried	O
or	O
embarrassed	O
by	O
Hannah	B-PER
's	O
Humpty	O
Dumpty	O
physique	O
-	O
at	O
seven	O
her	O
daughter	O
weighed	O
close	O
to	O
10	O
stone	O
-	O
she	O
was	O
obviously	O
proud	O
of	O
what	O
she	O
called	O
Hannah	B-PER
's	O
``	O
very	O
good	O
size	O
''	O
.	O

At	O
break	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
others	O
played	O
football	O
,	O
Hannah	B-PER
sat	O
on	O
a	O
bench	O
absorbed	O
in	O
the	O
Reader	O
's	O
Digest	O
or	O
the	O
Ladybird	O
Guide	O
to	O
the	O
Solar	O
System	O
steadily	O
working	O
her	O
way	O
through	O
a	O
family	O
size	O
pack	O
of	O
mini	O
Mars	O
bars	O
.	O

She	O
came	O
to	O
tea	O
once	O
and	O
explained	O
why	O
,	O
although	O
the	O
individual	O
galaxies	O
were	O
constricting	O
,	O
the	O
universe	O
itself	O
was	O
expanding	O
.	O

She	O
wanted	O
to	O
be	O
an	O
astronaut	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
just	O
come	O
back	O
from	O
a	O
press	O
trip	O
to	O
Hawaii	B-LOC
where	O
one	O
morning	O
all	O
of	O
us	O
,	O
apart	O
from	O
a	O
Midlands	B-LOC
radio	O
presenter	O
called	O
Kenny	B-PER
,	O
had	O
been	O
taken	O
by	O
helicopter	O
to	O
see	O
some	O
spectacular	O
waterfalls	O
.	O

Kenny	B-PER
could	O
n't	O
come	O
because	O
the	O
tour	O
guide	O
said	O
he	O
was	O
too	O
fat	O
and	O
would	O
upset	O
the	O
balance	O
of	O
the	O
helicopter	O
.	O

I	O
'd	O
told	O
the	O
children	O
about	O
Kenny	B-PER
and	O
hoped	O
they	O
would	O
n't	O
bring	O
it	O
up	O
.	O

They	O
did	O
n't	O
because	O
,	O
believe	O
it	O
or	O
not	O
,	O
they	O
really	O
had	O
n't	O
noticed	O
Hannah	B-PER
was	O
overweight	O
.	O

``	O
Hannah	O
the	O
clever	O
one	O
,	O
''	O
they	O
'd	O
say	O
,	O
not	O
``	O
Hannah	B-PER
she	O
's	O
fat	O
.	O
''	O

I	O
wish	O
this	O
story	O
had	O
a	O
happy	O
ending	O
for	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
reason	O
why	O
stories	O
about	O
fat	O
people	O
should	O
n't	O
.	O

Take	O
Kenny	B-PER
.	O

From	O
the	O
neck	O
down	O
he	O
looked	O
like	O
Mr	O
Blobby	B-PER
but	O
he	O
had	O
a	O
surprisingly	O
lean	O
,	O
mean	O
profile	O
and	O
a	O
devastatingly	O
sexy	O
voice	O
.	O

Women	O
in	O
the	O
Midlands	B-LOC
wrote	O
in	O
every	O
week	O
to	O
tell	O
Kenny	B-PER
how	O
much	O
they	O
fancied	O
him	O
.	O

When	O
we	O
got	O
back	O
from	O
our	O
waterfall	O
trip	O
,	O
we	O
found	O
him	O
on	O
the	O
hotel	O
terrace	O
drinking	O
beer	O
and	O
dealing	O
with	O
his	O
fan	O
mail	O
.	O

Hannah	B-PER
,	O
I	O
'm	O
sure	O
,	O
could	O
have	O
ended	O
up	O
as	O
content	O
as	O
Kenny	B-PER
,	O
but	O
at	O
12	O
she	O
was	O
screwed	O
up	O
by	O
the	O
therapist	O
her	O
mother	O
got	O
hold	O
of	O
to	O
help	O
her	O
lose	O
weight	O
.	O

Please	O
note	O
it	O
was	O
n't	O
Hannah	B-PER
who	O
wanted	O
to	O
look	O
like	O
Kate	B-PER
Moss	I-PER
,	O
it	O
was	O
her	O
mother	O
forcing	O
her	O
.	O

From	O
being	O
a	O
bright	O
,	O
happy	O
,	O
clever	O
fat	O
girl	O
,	O
Hannah	B-PER
became	O
a	O
depressed	O
neurotic	O
anorexic	O
teenager	O
who	O
only	O
read	O
books	O
about	O
fashion	O
and	O
diets	O
.	O

I	O
bumped	O
into	O
her	O
mother	O
the	O
other	O
day	O
outside	O
the	O
Post	B-ORG
Office	I-ORG
.	O

``	O
How	O
's	O
Hannah	B-PER
?	O
''	O
I	O
said	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
at	O
a	O
health	O
clinic	O
in	O
Portugal	B-LOC
doing	O
alternate	O
sessions	O
of	O
meditation	O
and	O
colonic	O
irrigation	O
,	O
said	O
her	O
mother	O
.	O

Since	O
the	O
obesity	O
report	O
came	O
out	O
,	O
parents	O
have	O
been	O
swamped	O
with	O
advice	O
about	O
how	O
to	O
control	O
their	O
children	O
's	O
diets	O
and	O
lifestyle	O
.	O

The	O
older	O
I	O
get	O
,	O
the	O
less	O
I	O
'm	O
convinced	O
that	O
we	O
poor	O
parents	O
have	O
any	O
control	O
over	O
our	O
children	O
at	O
all	O
.	O

This	O
depressing	O
opinion	O
was	O
confirmed	O
by	O
Sir	O
Richard	B-PER
Doll	I-PER
,	O
the	O
first	O
doctor	O
to	O
discover	O
the	O
link	O
between	O
cancer	O
and	O
smoking	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
on	O
Desert	O
Island	O
Discs	O
,	O
and	O
when	O
Sue	B-PER
Lawley	I-PER
asked	O
plaintively	O
what	O
parents	O
could	O
do	O
to	O
stop	O
their	O
children	O
smoking	O
,	O
Sir	O
Richard	B-PER
said	O
:	O
``	O
Absolutely	O
nothing	O
.	O
''	O

In	O
fact	O
,	O
he	O
opined	O
,	O
the	O
more	O
parents	O
nagged	O
at	O
children	O
not	O
to	O
smoke	O
,	O
the	O
more	O
likely	O
it	O
was	O
that	O
they	O
would	O
.	O

As	O
long	O
as	O
they	O
stopped	O
in	O
their	O
mid-thirties	O
,	O
they	O
would	O
n't	O
die	O
of	O
lung	O
cancer	O
,	O
he	O
thought	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
very	O
strong	O
chance	O
they	O
would	O
stop	O
smoking	O
as	O
adults	O
having	O
weighed	O
up	O
all	O
the	O
evidence	O
against	O
it	O
.	O

I	O
'm	O
sure	O
the	O
same	O
argument	O
applies	O
to	O
obesity	O
.	O

Keep	O
nagging	O
at	O
children	O
to	O
stop	O
snacking	O
,	O
switch	O
off	O
the	O
television	O
and	O
take	O
exercise	O
,	O
the	O
more	O
they	O
will	O
guzzle	O
and	O
slump	O
.	O

Waiting	O
outside	O
the	O
fitting	O
rooms	O
of	O
a	O
Kings	B-LOC
Road	I-LOC
shop	O
the	O
other	O
day	O
,	O
I	O
was	O
surprised	O
and	O
dismayed	O
not	O
by	O
how	O
fat	O
kids	O
are	O
these	O
days	O
but	O
how	O
unhealthily	O
skinny	O
they	O
are	O
,	O
especially	O
teenage	O
girls	O
.	O

The	O
ones	O
trying	O
on	O
crop	O
tops	O
and	O
trousers	O
looked	O
less	O
like	O
nubile	O
young	O
women	O
than	O
scaffolding	O
.	O

If	O
you	O
want	O
to	O
see	O
serious	O
obesity	O
,	O
go	O
to	O
Miami	B-LOC
airport	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
more	O
obvious	O
out	O
there	O
because	O
everyone	O
is	O
wearing	O
shorts	O
.	O

The	O
entire	O
airport	O
smells	O
of	O
cinnamon	O
,	O
the	O
preferred	O
topping	O
for	O
all	O
those	O
doughnuts	O
they	O
're	O
selling	O
.	O

You	O
see	O
entire	O
families	O
sitting	O
at	O
doughnut	O
stalls	O
with	O
buckets	O
of	O
doughnuts	O
between	O
their	O
knees	O
.	O

Now	O
that	O
's	O
obesity	O
.	O

Tony	B-PER
Blair	I-PER
is	O
engaged	O
in	O
low	O
politics	O
on	O
fox-hunting	O
.	O

The	O
timing	O
of	O
this	O
,	O
his	O
third	O
initiative	O
,	O
seems	O
to	O
have	O
been	O
influenced	O
by	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
get	O
Stephen	B-PER
Byers	I-PER
through	O
his	O
trial	O
by	O
ordeal	O
in	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Commons	I-ORG
on	O
Tuesday	O
.	O

Not	O
only	O
did	O
it	O
reward	O
Labour	B-ORG
backbenchers	O
for	O
their	O
show	O
of	O
loyalty	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
helped	O
move	O
the	O
media	O
caravan	O
on	O
from	O
the	O
semantics	O
of	O
lying	O
by	O
presenting	O
them	O
with	O
a	O
new	O
-	O
or	O
,	O
rather	O
,	O
renewed	O
-	O
controversy	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
Labour	B-ORG
backbenchers	O
are	O
not	O
so	O
stupid	O
that	O
they	O
can	O
be	O
bought	O
off	O
with	O
yet	O
another	O
meaningless	O
vote	O
that	O
allows	O
them	O
to	O
express	O
their	O
opinions	O
and	O
is	O
then	O
forgotten	O
.	O

Equally	O
,	O
public	O
opinion	O
,	O
which	O
on	O
this	O
issue	O
is	O
wrong	O
but	O
unmistakable	O
,	O
would	O
not	O
easily	O
understand	O
another	O
marching	O
of	O
the	O
abolitionist	O
troops	O
up	O
the	O
hill	O
only	O
for	O
them	O
to	O
be	O
marched	O
down	O
again	O
.	O

Most	O
people	O
think	O
that	O
hunting	O
with	O
dogs	O
is	O
cruel	O
,	O
that	O
it	O
should	O
be	O
banned	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
Government	B-ORG
should	O
get	O
on	O
with	O
it	O
.	O

The	O
real	O
low	O
politics	O
of	O
Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
's	O
return	O
to	O
this	O
subject	O
,	O
therefore	O
,	O
is	O
that	O
of	O
reaching	O
a	O
compromise	O
with	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Lords	I-ORG
.	O

Whatever	O
the	O
presentational	O
value	O
with	O
his	O
own	O
party	O
of	O
occasional	O
confrontations	O
with	O
the	O
``	O
forces	O
of	O
conservatism	O
''	O
in	O
red	O
coats	O
and	O
on	O
horseback	O
,	O
the	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
is	O
unlikely	O
to	O
want	O
to	O
provoke	O
another	O
full-dress	O
showdown	O
with	O
the	O
``	O
countryside	O
''	O
lobby	O
.	O

The	O
last	O
time	O
he	O
picked	O
a	O
fight	O
with	O
them	O
,	O
the	O
Deputy	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
and	O
a	O
protester	O
had	O
to	O
be	O
prised	O
apart	O
in	O
a	O
flower-bed	O
in	O
Rhyl	B-LOC
in	O
the	O
middle	O
of	O
a	O
general	O
election	O
campaign	O
.	O

On	O
18	O
March	O
,	O
the	O
Commons	B-ORG
will	O
undoubtedly	O
vote	O
,	O
overwhelmingly	O
again	O
,	O
for	O
a	O
complete	O
ban	O
on	O
hunting	O
.	O

If	O
left	O
to	O
themselves	O
,	O
the	O
Lords	B-ORG
would	O
just	O
as	O
overwhelmingly	O
vote	O
to	O
leave	O
things	O
as	O
they	O
are	O
.	O

Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
may	O
hope	O
that	O
the	O
threat	O
of	O
the	O
Parliament	O
Act	O
-	O
which	O
requires	O
the	O
will	O
of	O
the	O
Commons	B-ORG
ultimately	O
to	O
prevail	O
over	O
that	O
of	O
the	O
upper	O
House	B-ORG
-	O
will	O
encourage	O
the	O
Lords	O
to	O
opt	O
for	O
the	O
compromise	O
instead	O
.	O

Getting	O
the	O
Lords	B-ORG
to	O
decide	O
that	O
the	O
``	O
Middle	O
Way	O
''	O
compromise	O
scheme	O
is	O
the	O
lesser	O
of	O
two	O
evils	O
depends	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
credibility	O
of	O
the	O
threat	O
to	O
use	O
the	O
Parliament	O
Act	O
.	O

The	O
Lords	B-ORG
could	O
call	O
Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
's	O
bluff	O
if	O
they	O
judge	O
that	O
he	O
really	O
would	O
not	O
want	O
to	O
have	O
the	O
so-called	O
countryside	O
march	O
on	O
Whitehall	B-ORG
again	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
no	O
way	O
to	O
decide	O
an	O
issue	O
of	O
principle	O
.	O

The	O
majority	O
of	O
people	O
in	O
Britain	B-LOC
confuse	O
their	O
distaste	O
for	O
a	O
minority	O
pursuit	O
with	O
the	O
instinct	O
that	O
``	O
there	O
ought	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
law	O
against	O
it	O
''	O
.	O

There	O
should	O
not	O
be	O
,	O
just	O
as	O
there	O
should	O
be	O
no	O
law	O
against	O
the	O
rather	O
more	O
popular	O
sport	O
of	O
angling	O
.	O

The	O
undue	O
attention	O
devoted	O
to	O
one	O
particular	O
means	O
of	O
culling	O
animals	O
owes	O
too	O
much	O
to	O
the	O
perceived	O
class	O
connotations	O
of	O
``	O
country	O
sports	O
''	O
and	O
sanctimony	O
about	O
humans	O
deriving	O
pleasure	O
from	O
it	O
.	O

What	O
requires	O
legislation	O
is	O
the	O
less	O
visible	O
cruelty	O
towards	O
factory-farmed	O
chickens	O
and	O
pigs	O
,	O
and	O
towards	O
other	O
animals	O
in	O
transit	O
,	O
not	O
to	O
mention	O
cruel	O
and	O
unnecessary	O
experiments	O
on	O
primates	O
.	O

A	O
compromise	O
between	O
a	O
ban	O
on	O
hunting	O
and	O
no	O
ban	O
is	O
dishonest	O
.	O

The	O
idea	O
of	O
licensed	O
or	O
regulated	O
cruelty	O
makes	O
no	O
sense	O
.	O

It	O
would	O
be	O
better	O
if	O
the	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
and	O
all	O
those	O
MPs	O
who	O
vote	O
for	O
a	O
ban	O
simply	O
to	O
earn	O
easy	O
applause	O
from	O
a	O
vocal	O
and	O
passionate	O
minority	O
of	O
their	O
constituents	O
were	O
courageous	O
enough	O
to	O
explain	O
to	O
the	O
voters	O
that	O
,	O
while	O
some	O
activities	O
may	O
offend	O
our	O
sensibilities	O
,	O
they	O
should	O
not	O
all	O
be	O
banned	O
.	O

The	O
Middle	O
Way	O
is	O
a	O
classic	O
Blairite	O
fudge	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
unlikely	O
to	O
satisfy	O
either	O
side	O
-	O
although	O
the	O
anti-hunters	O
are	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
more	O
disappointed	O
,	O
because	O
hunting	O
would	O
continue	O
,	O
with	O
only	O
some	O
of	O
its	O
more	O
repellent	O
excesses	O
curtailed	O
.	O

The	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
would	O
earn	O
a	O
great	O
deal	O
more	O
respect	O
if	O
he	O
said	O
what	O
he	O
really	O
thought	O
and	O
explained	O
and	O
defended	O
that	O
,	O
instead	O
of	O
trying	O
to	O
fix	O
his	O
way	O
out	O
of	O
a	O
political	O
problem	O
.	O

Today	O
in	O
the	O
European	B-ORG
Parliament	I-ORG
's	O
chamber	O
in	O
Brussels	B-LOC
,	O
105	O
men	O
and	O
women	O
from	O
28	O
European	O
nations	O
will	O
gather	O
to	O
begin	O
discussing	O
a	O
constitutional	O
settlement	O
for	O
Europe	B-ORG
.	O

Europe	B-ORG
has	O
a	O
constitution	O
now	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
but	O
,	O
in	O
its	O
various	O
official	O
languages	O
,	O
it	O
runs	O
into	O
literally	O
millions	O
of	O
pages	O
of	O
legislation	O
,	O
council	O
decisions	O
and	O
commission	O
directives	O
,	O
known	O
collectively	O
as	O
the	O
``	O
acquis	O
''	O
-	O
not	O
exactly	O
a	O
household	O
term	O
in	O
Europe	B-LOC
's	O
salons	O
and	O
saunas	O
.	O

This	O
tangle	O
of	O
laws	O
and	O
regulations	O
has	O
long	O
cried	O
out	O
to	O
be	O
formulated	O
into	O
a	O
few	O
simple	O
rules	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
paramount	O
aim	O
of	O
bringing	O
Europe	B-ORG
closer	O
to	O
its	O
people	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
jargon	O
goes	O
.	O

The	O
question	O
is	O
whether	O
the	O
Constitutional	B-ORG
Convention	I-ORG
,	O
now	O
assembled	O
under	O
the	O
leadership	O
of	O
the	O
former	O
French	O
president	O
Val‚ry	B-PER
Giscard	I-PER
d'Estaing	I-PER
,	O
is	O
an	O
appropriate	O
vehicle	O
to	O
deliver	O
a	O
new	O
constitutional	O
settlement	O
.	O

Certainly	O
the	O
choice	O
of	O
Mr	O
Giscard	B-PER
to	O
run	O
things	O
does	O
n't	O
inspire	O
a	O
great	O
deal	O
of	O
confidence	O
.	O

The	O
fact	O
that	O
he	O
is	O
old	O
should	O
be	O
no	O
obstacle	O
,	O
although	O
his	O
slightly	O
sleazy	O
past	O
(	O
remember	O
the	O
Bokassa	B-PER
diamonds	O
scandal	O
?	O
)	O
detracts	O
a	O
little	O
from	O
his	O
dignity	O
.	O

The	O
more	O
serious	O
drawback	O
with	O
Mr	O
Giscard	B-PER
is	O
simply	O
the	O
suspicion	O
that	O
he	O
will	O
guide	O
the	O
convention	O
in	O
a	O
direction	O
that	O
reflects	O
the	O
traditional	O
French	O
approach	O
to	O
governance	O
-	O
not	O
so	O
much	O
libert‚	O
,	O
fraternit‚	O
,	O
egalit‚	O
as	O
‚litisme	O
,	O
dirigisme	O
,	O
technocratie	O
.	O

That	O
trinity	O
was	O
,	O
in	O
fact	O
,	O
very	O
much	O
the	O
foundation	O
of	O
the	O
institutions	O
of	O
the	O
original	O
European	B-ORG
Community	I-ORG
as	O
set	O
out	O
in	O
the	O
Treaty	O
of	O
Rome	B-LOC
of	O
1957	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
the	O
vision	O
of	O
Jean	B-PER
Monnet	I-PER
and	O
Robert	B-PER
Schumann	I-PER
,	O
the	O
French	O
founding	O
fathers	O
of	O
the	O
community	O
,	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
Comit‚	B-ORG
d'Action	I-ORG
pour	I-ORG
les	I-ORG
Etats-Unis	I-ORG
d'Europe	I-ORG
that	O
they	O
founded	O
.	O

These	O
arrangements	O
worked	O
well	O
for	O
the	O
small	O
community	O
of	O
the	O
Six	O
,	O
but	O
in	O
a	O
union	O
of	O
15	O
they	O
are	O
distinctly	O
creaky	O
.	O

All	O
agree	O
that	O
in	O
a	O
union	O
of	O
25	O
or	O
30	O
-	O
the	O
position	O
we	O
could	O
easily	O
be	O
in	O
before	O
the	O
decade	O
is	O
out	O
-	O
such	O
arrangements	O
would	O
be	O
unsustainable	O
.	O

The	O
danger	O
is	O
that	O
Mr	O
Giscard	B-PER
,	O
a	O
typical	O
product	O
of	O
the	O
French	O
‚lite	O
,	O
will	O
simply	O
want	O
to	O
give	O
us	O
``	O
more	O
of	O
the	O
same	O
''	O
,	O
but	O
with	O
a	O
much	O
stronger	O
centre	O
.	O

That	O
would	O
mean	O
a	O
stronger	O
Commission	B-ORG
and	O
a	O
``	O
leadership	O
''	O
role	O
for	O
the	O
big	O
five	O
(	O
France	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
UK	B-LOC
,	O
Germany	B-LOC
,	O
Italy	B-LOC
and	O
Spain	B-LOC
)	O
to	O
cope	O
with	O
the	O
demands	O
of	O
a	O
30-state	O
union	O
.	O

Indeed	O
,	O
worries	O
about	O
expansion	O
leading	O
to	O
a	O
wider	O
but	O
looser	O
EU	B-ORG
underlay	O
the	O
French	B-ORG
government	I-ORG
's	O
past	O
resistance	O
to	O
welcoming	O
new	O
members	O
from	O
Scandinavia	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
east	O
.	O

Still	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
reasons	O
to	O
be	O
optimistic	O
.	O

Mr	O
Giscard	B-PER
will	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
have	O
things	O
all	O
his	O
own	O
way	O
in	O
a	O
105-member	O
commission	O
,	O
especially	O
as	O
the	O
British	O
are	O
providing	O
its	O
chief	O
executive	O
in	O
the	O
form	O
of	O
Sir	O
John	B-PER
Kerr	I-PER
,	O
a	O
supermandarin	O
and	O
diplomat	O
.	O

And	O
the	O
Laeken	O
Declaration	O
that	O
set	O
up	O
the	O
convention	O
declared	O
that	O
``	O
European	O
institutions	O
must	O
be	O
brought	O
closer	O
to	O
citizens	O
.	O

They	O
want	O
them	O
to	O
be	O
less	O
unwieldy	O
and	O
more	O
efficient	O
and	O
open	O
.	O
''	O

That	O
can	O
not	O
be	O
ignored	O
.	O

By	O
far	O
the	O
best	O
way	O
of	O
ensuring	O
that	O
Europe	B-ORG
is	O
brought	O
closer	O
to	O
its	O
people	O
is	O
to	O
provide	O
for	O
a	O
stronger	O
European	B-ORG
Parliament	I-ORG
.	O

Until	O
that	O
is	O
done	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
very	O
little	O
chance	O
of	O
a	O
truly	O
pan-European	O
party	O
system	O
developing	O
and	O
,	O
with	O
that	O
,	O
a	O
European	O
level	O
of	O
debate	O
.	O

More	O
sessions	O
of	O
the	O
European	B-ORG
Council	I-ORG
should	O
be	O
open	O
to	O
the	O
cameras	O
and	O
the	O
public	O
.	O

And	O
,	O
most	O
importantly	O
,	O
there	O
should	O
be	O
a	O
much	O
stronger	O
formal	O
commitment	O
to	O
the	O
principle	O
of	O
subsidiarity	O
,	O
with	O
more	O
decision-making	O
devolved	O
to	O
national	O
,	O
regional	O
and	O
local	O
levels	O
.	O

More	O
than	O
ever	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
union	O
of	O
30	O
states	O
,	O
Europe	B-ORG
should	O
concentrate	O
on	O
performing	O
the	O
tasks	O
-	O
in	O
the	O
economic	O
,	O
environmental	O
and	O
even	O
defence	O
fields	O
-	O
where	O
it	O
can	O
make	O
a	O
difference	O
.	O

Surely	O
Mr	O
Giscard	B-PER
has	O
to	O
understand	O
that	O
.	O

The	O
prospect	O
of	O
meeting	O
an	O
old	O
but	O
long-separated	O
schoolfriend	O
can	O
trigger	O
far	O
more	O
fear	O
than	O
joy	O
.	O

Did	O
the	O
charismatic	O
soul	O
who	O
thrilled	O
your	O
teenage	O
self	O
evolve	O
into	O
a	O
bore	O
,	O
a	O
prig	O
,	O
an	O
oaf	O
?	O

Worse	O
,	O
did	O
they	O
never	O
possess	O
the	O
virtues	O
you	O
innocently	O
pinned	O
to	O
them	O
?	O

What	O
applies	O
to	O
people	O
applies	O
,	O
in	O
spades	O
,	O
to	O
literature	O
.	O

To	O
re-read	O
a	O
favourite	O
author	O
of	O
one	O
's	O
youth	O
is	O
to	O
court	O
incredulity	O
,	O
and	O
even	O
self-disgust	O
.	O

How	O
could	O
I	O
have	O
rated	O
that	O
pretentious	O
garbage/sentimental	O
schlock	O
?	O

Around	O
the	O
age	O
of	O
15	O
,	O
I	O
adored	O
John	B-PER
Steinbeck	I-PER
's	O
The	O
Grapes	O
of	O
Wrath	O
almost	O
more	O
than	O
any	O
other	O
novel	O
.	O

Soon	O
enough	O
,	O
I	O
learnt	O
this	O
was	O
an	O
inadmissible	O
affection	O
.	O

Too	O
folksy	O
,	O
too	O
naturalistic	O
,	O
stylistically	O
immature	O
,	O
politically	O
na‹ve	O
:	O
the	O
hit	O
squads	O
of	O
academic	O
criticism	O
had	O
dropped	O
down	O
hard	O
on	O
Steinbeck	B-PER
even	O
before	O
his	O
death	O
in	O
1968	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
born	O
-	O
in	O
Salinas	B-LOC
,	O
California	B-LOC
-	O
on	O
27	O
February	O
1902	O
,	O
and	O
next	O
week	O
Allen	B-PER
Lane	I-PER
publishes	O
an	O
ample	O
selection	O
of	O
his	O
non-fiction	O
to	O
mark	O
the	O
centenary	O
:	O
Of	O
Men	O
and	O
their	O
Making	O
,	O
edited	O
by	O
Susan	B-PER
Shillinglaw	I-PER
and	O
Jackson	B-PER
J	I-PER
Benson	I-PER
(	O
œ	O
25	O
)	O
.	O

Of	O
course	O
,	O
I	O
opened	O
it	O
with	O
trepidation	O
.	O

Would	O
Steinbeck	B-PER
prove	O
as	O
cringingly	O
embarrassing	O
as	O
every	O
other	O
15-year-old	O
crush	O
?	O

I	O
need	O
not	O
have	O
worried	O
.	O

Of	O
Men	O
and	O
their	O
Making	O
is	O
a	O
constant	O
delight	O
,	O
a	O
generous	O
,	O
open-hearted	O
vaudeville	O
show	O
of	O
a	O
book	O
that	O
switches	O
from	O
elegantly	O
crafted	O
memoirs	O
to	O
frivolous	O
pieces	O
on	O
fishing	O
or	O
Fords	O
,	O
from	O
thrilling	O
reportage	O
to	O
sinewy	O
meditations	O
on	O
politics	O
and	O
culture	O
.	O

Not	O
all	O
of	O
it	O
is	O
perfect	O
,	O
or	O
profound	O
.	O

Steinbeck	B-PER
wrote	O
reams	O
of	O
journalism	O
over	O
three	O
decades	O
,	O
and	O
one	O
leading	O
item	O
on	O
the	O
academic	O
charge-sheet	O
states	O
that	O
he	O
squandered	O
too	O
much	O
talent	O
on	O
ephemera	O
.	O

But	O
,	O
all	O
in	O
all	O
,	O
his	O
praise	O
for	O
Mark	B-PER
Twain	I-PER
's	O
``	O
incredible	O
ear	O
and	O
eye	O
and	O
sense	O
of	O
form	O
''	O
as	O
a	O
subjective	O
observer	O
goes	O
for	O
Steinbeck	B-PER
,	O
too	O
.	O

Here	O
is	O
the	O
democratic	O
American	O
voice	O
in	O
all	O
its	O
glory	O
:	O
friendly	O
,	O
courageous	O
,	O
compassionate	O
,	O
keen	O
to	O
go	O
everywhere	O
,	O
see	O
everything	O
,	O
and	O
capture	O
it	O
all	O
in	O
pacy	O
,	O
spirited	O
prose	O
that	O
can	O
swing	O
between	O
high	O
ideas	O
and	O
street	O
life	O
without	O
missing	O
a	O
beat	O
.	O

The	O
collection	O
teems	O
with	O
hundreds	O
of	O
images	O
and	O
phrases	O
that	O
kick	O
,	O
and	O
bite	O
,	O
and	O
stay	O
-	O
from	O
the	O
childhood	O
memory	O
of	O
a	O
phonograph	O
that	O
``	O
leaped	O
from	O
a	O
shelf	O
and	O
destroyed	O
itself	O
''	O
in	O
the	O
California	B-LOC
earthquake	O
of	O
1906	O
to	O
the	O
vision	O
of	O
Bob	B-PER
Hope	I-PER
in	O
London	B-LOC
in	O
1943	O
,	O
wisecracking	O
to	O
a	O
hospital	O
ward	O
of	O
maimed	O
soldiers	O
and	O
magically	O
drawing	O
``	O
laughter	O
up	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
black	O
water	O
''	O
.	O

We	O
revisit	O
the	O
beautifully-evoked	O
California	B-LOC
towns	O
of	O
Steinbeck	B-PER
's	O
youth	O
;	O
and	O
we	O
follow	O
him	O
into	O
the	O
itinerant	O
workers	O
'	O
camps	O
of	O
the	O
Dust	O
Bowl	O
years	O
,	O
in	O
articles	O
that	O
mount	O
a	O
ringing	O
defence	O
of	O
the	O
dignity	O
of	O
``	O
economic	O
migrants	O
''	O
.	O

The	O
editors	O
choose	O
some	O
grittily	O
memorable	O
wartime	O
reportage	O
;	O
some	O
charming	O
accounts	O
of	O
postwar	O
Europe	B-LOC
;	O
and	O
portraits	O
of	O
his	O
friends	O
,	O
from	O
Woody	B-PER
Guthrie	I-PER
and	O
Robert	B-PER
Capa	I-PER
to	O
Henry	B-PER
Fonda	I-PER
.	O

(	O
Watching	O
John	B-PER
Ford	I-PER
's	O
fine	O
film	O
of	O
The	O
Grapes	O
of	O
Wrath	O
after	O
20	O
years	O
,	O
Steinbeck	B-PER
is	O
galvanised	O
when	O
this	O
``	O
lean	O
,	O
stringy	O
,	O
dark-faced	O
piece	O
of	O
electricity	O
walked	O
out	O
on	O
the	O
screen	O
''	O
)	O
.	O

Even	O
the	O
1966	O
text	O
of	O
a	O
photo	O
book	O
on	O
America	B-LOC
and	O
Americans	O
,	O
written	O
when	O
he	O
had	O
allegedly	O
gone	O
soft	O
,	O
is	O
typically	O
abrasive	O
about	O
his	O
countrymen	O
's	O
taste	O
for	O
narcissism	O
and	O
racism	O
:	O
``	O
from	O
the	O
first	O
we	O
have	O
treated	O
our	O
minorities	O
abominably	O
,	O
the	O
way	O
the	O
old	O
boys	O
do	O
the	O
new	O
kids	O
in	O
school	O
.	O
''	O

Steinbeck	B-PER
was	O
not	O
always	O
prescient	O
(	O
like	O
many	O
other	O
US	B-LOC
liberals	O
,	O
he	O
supported	O
the	O
early	O
stages	O
of	O
the	O
war	O
in	O
Vietnam	B-LOC
)	O
.	O

Yet	O
these	O
400	O
pages	O
rattle	O
by	O
without	O
a	O
snide	O
thought	O
,	O
a	O
cheap	O
shot	O
or	O
a	O
dead	O
sentence	O
from	O
beginning	O
to	O
end.	O
At	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
establishment	O
America	B-LOC
takes	O
on	O
the	O
sepulchral	O
tones	O
of	O
Donald	B-PER
Rumsfeld	I-PER
(	O
or	O
the	O
silences	O
of	O
Kenneth	B-PER
Lay	I-PER
)	O
,	O
this	O
book	O
could	O
achieve	O
more	O
for	O
the	O
nation	O
's	O
prestige	O
overseas	O
than	O
a	O
hundred	O
extra	O
CIA	B-ORG
recruits	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
list	O
of	O
picture	O
captions	O
you	O
never	O
thought	O
you	O
'd	O
see	O
in	O
the	O
pages	O
of	O
a	O
serious	O
newspaper	O
,	O
``	O
160-million-year-old	O
vomit	O
''	O
is	O
right	O
up	O
there	O
with	O
``	O
Joan	B-PER
Collins	I-PER
and	O
her	O
new	O
husband	O
,	O
also	O
68	O
''	O
.	O

But	O
``	O
160	O
million-year-old	O
vomit	O
''	O
was	O
precisely	O
the	O
caption	O
in	O
Tuesday	O
's	O
papers	O
,	O
relating	O
to	O
the	O
thrilling	O
discovery	O
of	O
fossilised	O
dinosaur	O
puke	O
in	O
a	O
clay	O
quarry	O
near	O
Peterborough	B-LOC
.	O

Let	O
's	O
leave	O
to	O
the	O
panellists	O
of	O
Have	O
I	O
Got	O
News	O
for	O
You	O
the	O
cheap	O
gibe	O
that	O
the	O
Daily	B-ORG
Telegraph	I-ORG
-	O
with	O
a	O
substantial	O
number	O
of	O
fossils	O
and	O
dinosaurs	O
among	O
its	O
readers	O
-	O
was	O
stirring	O
nostalgia	O
rather	O
than	O
publishing	O
bona	O
fide	O
news	O
.	O

Instead	O
,	O
let	O
's	O
consider	O
what	O
a	O
fabulous	O
discovery	O
this	O
is	O
,	O
beyond	O
even	O
Steven	B-PER
Spielberg	I-PER
's	O
wildest	O
dreams	O
.	O

Professor	O
Peter	B-PER
Doyle	I-PER
,	O
of	O
the	O
University	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Greenwich	I-ORG
,	O
believes	O
that	O
the	O
fossils	O
found	O
near	O
Peterborough	B-LOC
are	O
partly-digested	O
shellfish	O
regurgitated	O
by	O
ichthyosaurs	O
,	O
marine	O
reptiles	O
.	O

How	O
he	O
reached	O
this	O
conclusion	O
is	O
not	O
the	O
business	O
of	O
this	O
column	O
,	O
thank	O
God	O
(	O
not	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
Almighty	O
has	O
any	O
place	O
in	O
palaeontology	O
)	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
certainly	O
interesting	O
to	O
dwell	O
on	O
the	O
significance	O
of	O
his	O
conclusion	O
.	O

For	O
one	O
thing	O
,	O
it	O
heaps	O
enviable	O
prestige	O
upon	O
Peterborough	B-LOC
,	O
which	O
until	O
this	O
week	O
had	O
only	O
its	O
handsome	O
Norman	O
cathedral	O
to	O
boast	O
about	O
.	O

But	O
there	O
are	O
n't	O
too	O
many	O
places	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
able	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
proof	O
that	O
an	O
ichthyosaur	O
once	O
chundered	O
somewhere	O
in	O
the	O
vicinity	O
.	O

Thinking	O
about	O
it	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
quite	O
possible	O
that	O
the	O
people	O
of	O
Peterborough	B-LOC
would	O
rather	O
not	O
adopt	O
this	O
as	O
a	O
claim	O
to	O
fame	O
,	O
just	O
as	O
the	O
townsfolk	O
of	O
Slough	B-LOC
tend	O
not	O
to	O
put	O
it	O
about	O
that	O
John	B-PER
Betjeman	I-PER
once	O
wrote	O
a	O
poem	O
about	O
them	O
.	O

As	O
for	O
the	O
vomiting	O
side	O
of	O
the	O
equation	O
,	O
I	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
if	O
you	O
've	O
noticed	O
,	O
but	O
throwing-up	O
has	O
been	O
looming	O
large	O
in	O
popular	O
culture	O
.	O

Billy	B-PER
Connolly	I-PER
was	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
draw	O
attention	O
to	O
it	O
,	O
wondering	O
why	O
drunkards	O
being	O
sick	O
call	O
so	O
despairingly	O
for	O
Ralph	B-PER
and	O
Huey	B-PER
.	O

And	O
although	O
vomiting	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
last	O
human	O
bodily	O
functions	O
to	O
get	O
a	O
regular	O
airing	O
on	O
television	O
,	O
rare	O
is	O
the	O
drama	O
now	O
that	O
does	O
not	O
feature	O
at	O
least	O
one	O
person	O
spewing	O
into	O
a	O
toilet	O
.	O

Certainly	O
,	O
no	O
self-respecting	O
soap	O
lets	O
New	O
Year	O
's	O
Eve	O
go	O
without	O
a	O
character	O
chucking	O
up	O
after	O
too	O
much	O
alcohol	O
;	O
we	O
have	O
even	O
had	O
animated	O
vomit	O
,	O
on	O
The	O
Simpsons	O
.	O

I	O
mention	O
this	O
because	O
,	O
until	O
now	O
,	O
palaeontology	O
has	O
rubbed	O
shoulders	O
with	O
popular	O
culture	O
only	O
in	O
the	O
BBC	B-ORG
series	O
Walking	O
With	O
Dinosaurs	O
-	O
which	O
,	O
as	O
brilliant	O
as	O
it	O
was	O
,	O
tended	O
to	O
drag	O
once	O
you	O
'd	O
marvelled	O
at	O
the	O
special	O
effects	O
for	O
long	O
enough	O
-	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
irritating	O
form	O
of	O
Ross	B-PER
in	O
the	O
sitcom	O
Friends	O
.	O

But	O
Professor	O
Doyle	B-PER
's	O
discovery	O
changes	O
everything	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
a	O
six-year-old	O
son	O
who	O
knows	O
the	O
difference	O
between	O
a	O
protoceratops	O
and	O
a	O
diplodocus	O
like	O
he	O
knows	O
the	O
difference	O
between	O
baked	O
beans	O
and	O
strawberry	O
jam	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
he	O
has	O
been	O
to	O
the	O
Natural	O
History	O
Museum	O
dozens	O
of	O
times	O
and	O
it	O
no	O
longer	O
lights	O
his	O
fire	O
.	O

When	O
I	O
told	O
him	O
about	O
the	O
ichthyosaur	O
pebble-dashing	O
parts	O
of	O
Cambridgeshire	B-LOC
with	O
shellfish	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
he	O
was	O
all	O
ears	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
plainly	O
enthralled	O
by	O
the	O
idea	O
that	O
anything	O
Jurassic	O
might	O
behave	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
way	O
as	O
he	O
did	O
the	O
other	O
night	O
after	O
a	O
tummy	O
bug	O
brought	O
up	O
his	O
spaghetti	O
bolognese	O
.	O

Might	O
behave	O
,	O
better	O
still	O
,	O
like	O
Bart	B-PER
Simpson	I-PER
.	O

What	O
is	O
needed	O
now	O
is	O
for	O
an	O
enterprising	O
children	O
's	O
telly	O
producer	O
,	O
perhaps	O
the	O
person	O
behind	O
that	O
sickeningly	O
cute	O
dinosaur	O
Barney	O
,	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
show	O
about	O
twin	O
ichthyosaurs	O
called	O
Ralph	B-PER
and	O
Huey	B-PER
.	O

And	O
the	O
thought	O
also	O
occurs	O
that	O
some	O
graduate	O
student	O
might	O
want	O
to	O
consider	O
a	O
thesis	O
on	O
the	O
enthralling	O
history	O
of	O
vomit	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
once	O
shown	O
round	O
a	O
vomitorium	O
,	O
where	O
middle-class	O
Romans	O
went	O
to	O
bring	O
back	O
their	O
dinners	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
fascinating	O
.	O

But	O
I	O
ca	O
n't	O
for	O
the	O
life	O
of	O
me	O
remember	O
where	O
it	O
was	O
.	O

For	O
Peterborough	B-ORG
's	O
sake	O
,	O
not	O
there	O
,	O
I	O
hope	O
.	O

The	O
decision	O
of	O
the	O
Human	B-ORG
Fertility	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Embryology	I-ORG
Authority	I-ORG
(	O
HFEA	B-ORG
)	O
to	O
allow	O
a	O
couple	O
to	O
select	O
genetically	O
their	O
next	O
baby	O
was	O
bound	O
to	O
raise	O
concerns	O
that	O
advances	O
in	O
biotechnology	O
are	O
racing	O
ahead	O
of	O
our	O
ability	O
to	O
control	O
the	O
consequences	O
.	O

The	O
couple	O
at	O
the	O
centre	O
of	O
this	O
case	O
have	O
a	O
son	O
who	O
suffers	O
from	O
a	O
potentially	O
fatal	O
disorder	O
and	O
whose	O
best	O
hope	O
is	O
a	O
marrow	O
transplant	O
from	O
a	O
sibling	O
,	O
so	O
the	O
stakes	O
of	O
this	O
decision	O
are	O
particularly	O
high	O
.	O

The	O
HFEA	B-ORG
's	O
critics	O
believe	O
that	O
it	O
sanctions	O
``	O
designer	O
babies	O
''	O
and	O
does	O
not	O
show	O
respect	O
for	O
the	O
sanctity	O
of	O
individual	O
life	O
.	O

Certainly	O
,	O
the	O
authority	O
's	O
backing	O
for	O
Shahana	B-PER
and	O
Raj	B-PER
Hashmi	I-PER
's	O
plea	O
for	O
genetic	O
screening	O
raises	O
fundamental	O
questions	O
about	O
producing	O
one	O
human	O
being	O
to	O
cure	O
another	O
's	O
disease	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
parents	O
'	O
view	O
is	O
simple	O
and	O
compelling	O
.	O

The	O
IVF	O
treatment	O
is	O
available	O
to	O
help	O
produce	O
a	O
baby	O
whose	O
tissue	O
will	O
match	O
his	O
or	O
her	O
elder	O
brother	O
's	O
bone	O
marrow	O
.	O

They	O
require	O
,	O
as	O
Mrs	O
Hashmi	B-PER
puts	O
it	O
,	O
``	O
a	O
helping	O
hand	O
''	O
from	O
the	O
HFEA	B-ORG
.	O

Screening	O
for	O
genetic	O
disorders	O
has	O
been	O
permissible	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
.	O

Those	O
who	O
oppose	O
the	O
treatment	O
on	O
grounds	O
that	O
it	O
echoes	O
destructive	O
eugenics	O
programmes	O
have	O
misplaced	O
their	O
concern	O
.	O

The	O
use	O
of	O
such	O
techniques	O
to	O
weed	O
out	O
genes	O
that	O
might	O
result	O
in	O
a	O
disability	O
does	O
not	O
suggest	O
that	O
disabled	O
people	O
are	O
``	O
defective	O
''	O
.	O

It	O
merely	O
uses	O
progress	O
to	O
prevent	O
a	O
malfunction	O
of	O
nature	O
.	O

They	O
would	O
not	O
reject	O
medical	O
intervention	O
to	O
put	O
right	O
other	O
things	O
that	O
go	O
wrong	O
with	O
the	O
body	O
.	O

Yet	O
they	O
ask	O
that	O
mankind	O
pass	O
up	O
the	O
chance	O
to	O
use	O
scientific	O
advances	O
in	O
biotechnology	O
to	O
prevent	O
unnecessary	O
suffering	O
.	O

The	O
inconsistency	O
is	O
striking	O
and	O
would	O
be	O
cruel	O
if	O
it	O
were	O
allowed	O
to	O
impede	O
a	O
beneficial	O
solution	O
.	O

The	O
HFEA	B-ORG
already	O
backed	O
tissue-type	O
screening	O
in	O
principle	O
in	O
December	O
.	O

This	O
latest	O
move	O
is	O
a	O
logical	O
advance	O
.	O

We	O
can	O
welcome	O
that	O
and	O
still	O
accept	O
the	O
need	O
to	O
maintain	O
the	O
distinction	O
between	O
these	O
and	O
more	O
frivolous	O
or	O
dubious	O
reasons	O
why	O
parents	O
might	O
want	O
to	O
opt	O
for	O
genetic	O
pre-selection	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
why	O
it	O
is	O
also	O
right	O
that	O
the	O
HFEA	B-ORG
continues	O
to	O
reject	O
genetic	O
pre-selection	O
if	O
it	O
helps	O
parents	O
choose	O
gender	O
,	O
let	O
alone	O
more	O
superficial	O
preferences	O
for	O
a	O
certain	O
appearance	O
.	O

Grounds	O
of	O
pure	O
preference	O
are	O
not	O
enough	O
to	O
make	O
parental	O
choice	O
paramount	O
and	O
the	O
authority	O
should	O
resist	O
pressure	O
to	O
give	O
in	O
on	O
this	O
point	O
.	O

The	O
Hashmis	B-PER
'	O
aim	O
is	O
very	O
different	O
.	O

They	O
are	O
concerned	O
with	O
saving	O
a	O
life	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
creating	O
one	O
.	O

They	O
and	O
their	O
doctors	O
may	O
reject	O
other	O
embryos	O
as	O
imperfect	O
matches	O
,	O
but	O
they	O
are	O
not	O
selecting	O
their	O
baby	O
as	O
if	O
it	O
were	O
a	O
designer	O
coat	O
or	O
handbag	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
clear	O
case	O
of	O
maximising	O
benefits	O
and	O
minimising	O
harm	O
.	O

The	O
parents	O
want	O
another	O
child	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
existing	O
son	O
will	O
be	O
the	O
beneficiary	O
.	O

Critics	O
of	O
such	O
technology	O
warn	O
that	O
the	O
child	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
means	O
rather	O
than	O
an	O
end	O
in	O
itself	O
.	O

Instead	O
of	O
being	O
valued	O
for	O
his	O
or	O
her	O
own	O
sake	O
,	O
they	O
say	O
,	O
the	O
next	O
Hashmi	B-PER
baby	O
's	O
raison	O
d'etre	O
will	O
be	O
his	O
life-saving	O
qualities	O
.	O

Yet	O
in	O
wanting	O
their	O
child	O
to	O
serve	O
a	O
certain	O
purpose	O
,	O
this	O
couple	O
is	O
merely	O
following	O
in	O
the	O
footsteps	O
of	O
countless	O
couples	O
before	O
them	O
:	O
couples	O
who	O
have	O
wanted	O
a	O
child	O
to	O
boost	O
their	O
own	O
relationship	O
,	O
or	O
provide	O
their	O
first-born	O
with	O
a	O
sibling	O
.	O

The	O
Hashmis	B-PER
'	O
decision	O
is	O
like	O
that	O
of	O
any	O
other	O
couple	O
who	O
want	O
the	O
best	O
for	O
their	O
child	O
.	O

Shahana	B-PER
and	O
Raj	B-PER
Hashmi	I-PER
will	O
undoubtedly	O
love	O
their	O
next	O
baby	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
their	O
first	O
.	O

As	O
David	B-PER
Beckham	I-PER
discovered	O
to	O
his	O
cost	O
,	O
the	O
manager	O
of	O
Manchester	B-ORG
United	I-ORG
likes	O
to	O
have	O
the	O
last	O
word	O
.	O

Which	O
is	O
why	O
he	O
's	O
signed	O
up	O
for	O
another	O
3	O
years	O
and	O
œ	O
11m	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
defining	O
moments	O
of	O
Sir	O
Alex	B-PER
Ferguson	I-PER
's	O
glorious	O
but	O
often	O
contentious	O
career	O
as	O
manager	O
of	O
Manchester	B-ORG
United	I-ORG
came	O
in	O
February	O
2000	O
when	O
David	B-PER
Beckham	I-PER
,	O
his	O
star	O
player	O
,	O
failed	O
to	O
report	O
for	O
training	O
.	O

Beckham	B-PER
said	O
his	O
baby	O
son	O
was	O
ill	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
he	O
needed	O
to	O
be	O
at	O
home	O
with	O
him	O
.	O

Fair	O
enough	O
.	O

But	O
when	O
Ferguson	B-PER
discovered	O
that	O
Beckham	B-PER
's	O
wife	O
Victoria	B-PER
was	O
out	O
shopping	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
,	O
he	O
hit	O
the	O
roof	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
someone	O
who	O
knows	O
him	O
well	O
,	O
the	O
publicity	O
machine	O
that	O
surrounds	O
the	O
Beckhams	B-PER
has	O
always	O
been	O
intensely	O
irritating	O
to	O
him	O
.	O

Now	O
,	O
by	O
his	O
lights	O
,	O
Beckham	B-PER
was	O
letting	O
the	O
side	O
down	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
Ferguson	B-PER
's	O
book	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
greater	O
sin	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
next	O
match	O
Beckham	B-PER
was	O
kicked	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
team	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
n't	O
even	O
a	O
substitute	O
.	O

It	O
seemed	O
unthinkable	O
to	O
drop	O
Beckham	B-PER
-	O
to	O
put	O
a	O
personal	O
squabble	O
,	O
as	O
some	O
saw	O
it	O
,	O
before	O
the	O
interests	O
of	O
the	O
team	O
.	O

But	O
Ferguson	B-PER
had	O
done	O
it	O
.	O

What	O
the	O
incident	O
really	O
betrayed	O
was	O
a	O
clash	O
of	O
cultures	O
-	O
a	O
21st-century	O
,	O
new-man	O
touchy-feeliness	O
on	O
the	O
one	O
hand	O
,	O
and	O
on	O
the	O
other	O
,	O
the	O
hard	O
,	O
man	O
's	O
world	O
that	O
shaped	O
Ferguson	B-PER
,	O
growing	O
up	O
among	O
the	O
Scottish	O
working	O
class	O
in	O
the	O
1950s	O
.	O

It	O
certainly	O
was	O
n't	O
one	O
in	O
which	O
wives	O
have	O
the	O
definitive	O
say	O
in	O
their	O
husband	O
's	O
lives	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
ironic	O
in	O
the	O
light	O
of	O
what	O
lay	O
behind	O
last	O
week	O
's	O
news	O
that	O
,	O
far	O
from	O
retiring	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
this	O
season	O
,	O
as	O
had	O
previously	O
been	O
announced	O
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
will	O
remain	O
at	O
Old	B-LOC
Trafford	I-LOC
for	O
another	O
three	O
years	O
.	O

Though	O
no	O
great	O
lover	O
of	O
the	O
game	O
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
's	O
wife	O
Cathy	B-PER
knew	O
what	O
it	O
meant	O
to	O
him	O
,	O
and	O
could	O
still	O
mean	O
,	O
and	O
she	O
perhaps	O
did	O
n't	O
relish	O
the	O
prospect	O
of	O
having	O
this	O
great	O
,	O
brooding	O
figure	O
about	O
the	O
house	O
with	O
no	O
outlet	O
for	O
his	O
footballing	O
energies	O
.	O

No	O
matter	O
that	O
he	O
has	O
achieved	O
everything	O
at	O
United	B-ORG
-	O
the	O
European	O
Cup	O
,	O
seven	O
Premier	B-ORG
League	I-ORG
titles	O
,	O
four	O
FA	O
Cups	O
and	O
one	O
League	O
Cup	O
-	O
or	O
that	O
he	O
turned	O
60	O
at	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
2001	O
.	O

Cathy	B-PER
Ferguson	I-PER
could	O
see	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
plenty	O
left	O
in	O
him	O
,	O
and	O
her	O
intervention	O
was	O
crucial	O
.	O

Why	O
not	O
carry	O
on	O
?	O

``	O
As	O
Cathy	B-PER
says	O
,	O
``	O
retire	O
when	O
you	O
feel	O
tired	O
''	O
,	O
''	O
Ferguson	B-PER
said	O
last	O
week	O
.	O

``	O
And	O
I	O
feel	O
strong	O
,	O
young	O
,	O
and	O
fit	O
.	O
''	O

Family	O
has	O
always	O
been	O
important	O
to	O
Ferguson	B-PER
,	O
and	O
so	O
,	O
by	O
extension	O
,	O
have	O
the	O
wider	O
roots	O
of	O
his	O
upbringing	O
.	O

In	O
his	O
case	O
,	O
that	O
was	O
Govan	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
Clydeside	B-LOC
district	O
on	O
the	O
south-western	O
edge	O
of	O
Glasgow	B-LOC
,	O
where	O
his	O
father	O
,	O
Alex	B-PER
snr	O
,	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
100,000	O
or	O
so	O
men	O
who	O
built	O
ships	O
.	O

The	O
sense	O
of	O
community	O
in	O
which	O
Ferguson	B-PER
grew	O
up	O
was	O
palpable	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
a	O
young	O
toolmaker	O
in	O
a	O
Glasgow	B-LOC
factory	O
,	O
he	O
was	O
soon	O
involved	O
in	O
the	O
union	O
.	O

Full-time	O
professional	O
football	O
did	O
not	O
come	O
until	O
he	O
was	O
22	O
,	O
when	O
he	O
joined	O
Dunfermline	B-ORG
.	O

Spells	O
at	O
three	O
other	O
clubs	O
followed	O
.	O

He	O
ran	O
a	O
pub	O
in	O
Glasgow	B-LOC
before	O
taking	O
up	O
his	O
first	O
managerial	O
post	O
,	O
at	O
St	B-ORG
Mirren	I-ORG
.	O

But	O
it	O
was	O
as	O
the	O
manager	O
of	O
Aberdeen	B-ORG
,	O
from	O
1978	O
to	O
1986	O
,	O
that	O
Ferguson	B-PER
made	O
his	O
mark	O
,	O
breaking	O
the	O
hold	O
over	O
Scottish	O
football	O
enjoyed	O
by	O
Rangers	B-ORG
and	O
Celtic	B-ORG
,	O
before	O
moving	O
to	O
Manchester	B-LOC
.	O

United	B-ORG
was	O
a	O
club	O
on	O
which	O
the	O
past	O
bore	O
down	O
.	O

With	O
both	O
the	O
Munich	B-LOC
air	O
disaster	O
of	O
1958	O
and	O
the	O
triumphs	O
of	O
the	O
late	O
1960s	O
,	O
it	O
had	O
a	O
unique	O
legacy	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
struggling	O
to	O
live	O
up	O
to	O
.	O

Since	O
the	O
retirement	O
,	O
in	O
1971	O
,	O
of	O
the	O
great	O
Sir	O
Matt	B-PER
Busby	I-PER
,	O
a	O
succession	O
of	O
managers	O
had	O
come	O
and	O
gone	O
with	O
little	O
to	O
show	O
.	O

Would	O
Ferguson	B-PER
do	O
any	O
better	O
?	O

In	O
the	O
early	O
years	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
touch	O
and	O
go	O
whether	O
he	O
would	O
survive	O
.	O

But	O
he	O
bought	O
some	O
time	O
by	O
winning	O
the	O
FA	O
Cup	O
in	O
1990	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
elusive	O
championship	O
,	O
the	O
club	O
's	O
first	O
for	O
26	O
years	O
,	O
finally	O
arrived	O
in	O
1993	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
inaugural	O
Premier	B-ORG
League	I-ORG
season	O
.	O

Since	O
then	O
,	O
United	B-ORG
have	O
been	O
almost	O
unstoppable	O
,	O
as	O
both	O
a	O
footballing	O
and	O
a	O
commercial	O
force	O
.	O

Ferguson	B-PER
's	O
achievement	O
has	O
been	O
to	O
withstand	O
the	O
pressure	O
that	O
goes	O
with	O
running	O
the	O
world	O
's	O
biggest	O
club	O
,	O
and	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
maintain	O
the	O
attacking	O
tradition	O
of	O
the	O
United	B-ORG
sides	O
of	O
old	O
.	O

Even	O
United	B-ORG
's	O
detractors	O
-	O
the	O
club	O
is	O
fiercely	O
resented	O
for	O
its	O
stranglehold	O
on	O
the	O
English	O
game	O
-	O
have	O
to	O
admit	O
that	O
,	O
under	O
Ferguson	B-PER
,	O
domestic	O
football	O
has	O
been	O
raised	O
to	O
breathtaking	O
new	O
levels	O
.	O

If	O
such	O
erudite	O
Continentals	O
as	O
the	O
England	B-LOC
manager	O
,	O
Sven	B-PER
Goran	I-PER
Eriksson	I-PER
,	O
and	O
ArsŠne	B-PER
Wenger	I-PER
of	O
Arsenal	B-ORG
seem	O
to	O
represent	O
a	O
new	O
studiousness	O
in	O
football	O
,	O
then	O
Ferguson	B-PER
might	O
be	O
seen	O
as	O
a	O
throwback	O
to	O
an	O
age	O
when	O
the	O
sort	O
of	O
men	O
to	O
whom	O
he	O
is	O
heir	O
-	O
tough	O
fellow-Scots	O
such	O
as	O
Bill	B-PER
Shankly	I-PER
and	O
Jock	B-PER
Stein	I-PER
-	O
seethed	O
with	O
a	O
passion	O
for	O
the	O
game	O
,	O
and	O
exuded	O
a	O
sometimes	O
terrifying	O
authority	O
.	O

But	O
you	O
do	O
n't	O
get	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
towering	O
figure	O
that	O
Ferguson	B-PER
has	O
become	O
without	O
the	O
shrewdness	O
,	O
attention	O
to	O
detail	O
and	O
profound	O
understanding	O
of	O
players	O
'	O
personalities	O
which	O
no	O
powers	O
of	O
intimidation	O
can	O
make	O
up	O
for	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
just	O
that	O
,	O
unlike	O
Eriksson	B-PER
and	O
Wenger	B-PER
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
has	O
been	O
known	O
to	O
go	O
into	O
rages	O
in	O
which	O
tables	O
have	O
been	O
kicked	O
and	O
teacups	O
thrown	O
.	O

``	O
There	O
's	O
a	O
difference	O
between	O
old-style	O
and	O
old-fashioned	O
,	O
''	O
says	O
Alastair	B-PER
Campbell	I-PER
,	O
the	O
Downing	B-LOC
Street	I-LOC
press	O
chief	O
who	O
has	O
welcomed	O
Ferguson	B-PER
as	O
a	O
staunch	O
Labour	B-ORG
supporter	O
.	O

``	O
Yes	O
,	O
he	O
's	O
old-	O
style	O
in	O
that	O
he	O
's	O
disciplined	O
and	O
he	O
leads	O
from	O
the	O
top	O
.	O

But	O
what	O
people	O
perhaps	O
do	O
n't	O
understand	O
about	O
Alex	B-PER
is	O
that	O
he	O
has	O
an	O
incredibly	O
acute	O
intelligence	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
to	O
appreciate	O
the	O
importance	O
of	O
diet	O
and	O
training	O
regimes	O
for	O
players	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
he	O
understands	O
that	O
United	B-ORG
is	O
a	O
huge	O
business	O
.	O

I	O
'd	O
say	O
all	O
that	O
puts	O
him	O
in	O
the	O
``	O
new	O
manager	O
''	O
mould	O
.	O
''	O

Few	O
managers	O
form	O
bonds	O
with	O
players	O
as	O
Ferguson	B-PER
does	O
.	O

He	O
has	O
regarded	O
the	O
Welsh	O
winger	O
Ryan	B-PER
Giggs	I-PER
almost	O
as	O
a	O
son	O
ever	O
since	O
he	O
broke	O
into	O
the	O
team	O
as	O
a	O
gifted	O
17-year-old	O
.	O

In	O
Roy	B-PER
Keane	I-PER
,	O
United	B-ORG
's	O
irresistible	O
Irish	O
midfielder	O
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
sees	O
many	O
of	O
his	O
own	O
formidable	O
qualities	O
.	O

And	O
with	O
Eric	B-PER
Cantona	I-PER
,	O
Peter	B-PER
Schmeichel	I-PER
and	O
now	O
the	O
brilliant	O
Dutch	O
striker	O
Ruud	B-PER
van	I-PER
Nistelrooy	I-PER
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
has	O
found	O
his	O
faith	O
in	O
individual	O
genius	O
,	O
with	O
all	O
its	O
attendant	O
pitfalls	O
,	O
spectacularly	O
rewarded	O
.	O

``	O
Ferguson	B-PER
's	O
probably	O
the	O
last	O
manager	O
who	O
can	O
use	O
fear	O
as	O
a	O
weapon	O
to	O
deal	O
with	O
players	O
,	O
''	O
says	O
the	O
sportswriter	O
Ken	B-PER
Jones	I-PER
.	O

``	O
That	O
's	O
very	O
difficult	O
today	O
because	O
the	O
players	O
have	O
so	O
much	O
money	O
that	O
they	O
can	O
just	O
turn	O
round	O
and	O
tell	O
you	O
where	O
to	O
go	O
.	O
''	O

When	O
loyalty	O
to	O
players	O
is	O
not	O
returned	O
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
does	O
not	O
easily	O
forgive	O
.	O

Likewise	O
when	O
he	O
feels	O
press	O
criticism	O
is	O
unjustified	O
.	O

This	O
season	O
has	O
seen	O
a	O
low	O
point	O
in	O
his	O
often	O
turbulent	O
relationship	O
with	O
reporters	O
,	O
with	O
Ferguson	B-PER
cancelling	O
press	O
conferences	O
and	O
haranguing	O
people	O
when	O
he	O
does	O
agree	O
to	O
turn	O
up	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
Ferguson	B-PER
's	O
three	O
sons	O
,	O
Jason	B-PER
,	O
is	O
also	O
his	O
agent	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
questions	O
raised	O
about	O
this	O
arrangement	O
have	O
seriously	O
rankled	O
with	O
him	O
.	O

Does	O
Ferguson	B-PER
bear	O
grudges	O
?	O

``	O
It	O
's	O
more	O
that	O
he	O
always	O
has	O
to	O
have	O
the	O
last	O
word	O
,	O
''	O
says	O
someone	O
close	O
to	O
him	O
.	O

Of	O
course	O
he	O
has	O
mellowed	O
over	O
the	O
years	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
owner	O
of	O
some	O
top-class	O
horses	O
,	O
he	O
derives	O
huge	O
pleasure	O
from	O
racing	O
,	O
often	O
turning	O
up	O
on	O
the	O
gallops	O
early	O
in	O
the	O
morning	O
after	O
a	O
match	O
the	O
night	O
before	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
a	O
time	O
when	O
he	O
felt	O
undervalued	O
at	O
United	B-ORG
.	O

What	O
mattered	O
to	O
him	O
about	O
the	O
big	O
pay	O
increase	O
he	O
secured	O
a	O
few	O
years	O
ago	O
was	O
not	O
what	O
it	O
could	O
buy	O
him	O
but	O
what	O
it	O
said	O
about	O
his	O
worth	O
.	O

At	O
œ	O
11m	O
over	O
three	O
years	O
,	O
Ferguson	B-PER
's	O
new	O
contract	O
makes	O
him	O
comfortably	O
Britain	B-LOC
's	O
highest	O
paid	O
manager	O
.	O

By	O
the	O
crazy	O
standards	O
of	O
the	O
footballing	O
economy	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
money	O
well	O
spent	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
just	O
a	O
week	O
since	O
The	B-ORG
Independent	I-ORG
on	O
Sunday	O
launched	O
its	O
asthma	O
campaign	O
,	O
and	O
already	O
ministers	O
have	O
begun	O
to	O
take	O
action	O
.	O

Shrugging	O
off	O
their	O
officials	O
'	O
instinct	O
to	O
try	O
to	O
kick	O
the	O
issue	O
into	O
the	O
long	O
grass	O
,	O
both	O
Michael	B-PER
Meacher	I-PER
,	O
the	O
Environment	O
minister	O
,	O
and	O
Yvette	B-PER
Cooper	I-PER
,	O
the	O
public	O
health	O
minister	O
,	O
have	O
immediately	O
appreciated	O
its	O
importance	O
.	O

Both	O
have	O
referred	O
the	O
scientific	O
studies	O
,	O
revealed	O
in	O
this	O
newspaper	O
,	O
that	O
indicate	O
that	O
traffic	O
fumes	O
can	O
cause	O
asthma	O
,	O
to	O
the	O
official	O
Committee	B-ORG
on	I-ORG
the	I-ORG
Medical	I-ORG
Effects	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Air	I-ORG
Pollution	I-ORG
.	O

Tomorrow	O
Mr	O
Meacher	B-PER
will	O
press	O
his	O
European	O
ministerial	O
colleagues	O
to	O
impose	O
tougher	O
,	O
continent-wide	O
controls	O
on	O
ozone	O
,	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
main	O
pollutants	O
involved	O
.	O

And	O
Ms	O
Cooper	B-PER
is	O
to	O
send	O
new	O
guidance	O
to	O
doctors	O
on	O
tackling	O
the	O
growing	O
epidemic	O
of	O
the	O
disease	O
in	O
children	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
good	O
as	O
far	O
as	O
it	O
goes	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
ministers	O
-	O
two	O
of	O
the	O
best	O
in	O
a	O
not	O
overtalented	O
Government	B-ORG
-	O
are	O
to	O
be	O
commended	O
for	O
thinking	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
bureaucratic	O
box	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
only	O
a	O
small	O
start	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
take	O
time	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
difference	O
.	O

The	O
pollution	O
committee	O
does	O
not	O
meet	O
until	O
June	O
.	O

The	O
new	O
health	O
guidelines	O
will	O
take	O
two	O
years	O
to	O
produce	O
.	O

And	O
Brussels	B-LOC
notoriously	O
moves	O
at	O
the	O
pace	O
of	O
the	O
snails	O
so	O
delectably	O
served	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
city	O
's	O
restaurants	O
.	O

The	O
urgency	O
of	O
the	O
crisis	O
blighting	O
the	O
lives	O
of	O
one	O
in	O
every	O
seven	O
British	O
children	O
-	O
and	O
their	O
families	O
-	O
requires	O
a	O
much	O
faster	O
response	O
.	O

It	O
also	O
demands	O
a	O
more	O
far-reaching	O
one	O
.	O

Our	O
report	O
today	O
that	O
two-thirds	O
of	O
British	O
schools	O
fail	O
to	O
help	O
their	O
asthmatic	O
pupils	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
hundreds	O
of	O
thousands	O
of	O
sufferers	O
are	O
not	O
properly	O
informed	O
about	O
their	O
condition	O
,	O
show	O
how	O
shamefully	O
the	O
Departments	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Health	I-ORG
and	I-ORG
Education	I-ORG
have	O
neglected	O
the	O
epidemic	O
.	O

Meanwhile	O
the	O
Department	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Transport	I-ORG
-	O
at	O
Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
's	O
specific	O
backseat	O
instruction	O
-	O
is	O
driving	O
policy	O
in	O
the	O
wrong	O
direction	O
,	O
towards	O
more	O
roads	O
,	O
more	O
cars	O
,	O
more	O
pollution	O
and	O
more	O
asthma	O
.	O

The	O
Prime	O
Minister	O
and	O
the	O
Cabinet	B-ORG
ministers	O
in	O
charge	O
of	O
the	O
relevant	O
departments	O
must	O
take	O
on	O
the	O
issue	O
themselves	O
,	O
and	O
institute	O
wholesale	O
changes	O
in	O
policy	O
-	O
or	O
take	O
the	O
blame	O
for	O
continuing	O
child	O
illness	O
and	O
death	O
.	O

The	O
difference	O
between	O
dial-up	O
internet	O
access	O
and	O
a	O
high-speed	O
service	O
that	O
is	O
permanently	O
on	O
is	O
akin	O
to	O
that	O
between	O
a	O
horse-drawn	O
cart	O
and	O
a	O
car	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
why	O
there	O
is	O
usually	O
no	O
going	O
back	O
for	O
people	O
who	O
have	O
graduated	O
from	O
one	O
to	O
the	O
other	O
.	O

So	O
it	O
would	O
be	O
churlish	O
not	O
to	O
applaud	O
the	O
sharp	O
price	O
reduction	O
announced	O
yesterday	O
by	O
BT	B-ORG
for	O
its	O
broadband	O
service	O
.	O

Assuming	O
that	O
the	O
internet	O
service	O
providers	O
pass	O
on	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
cut	O
,	O
an	O
average	O
monthly	O
subscription	O
should	O
come	O
down	O
to	O
around	O
œ	O
25	O
from	O
the	O
œ	O
40	O
or	O
so	O
it	O
currently	O
costs	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
by	O
any	O
measure	O
a	O
swingeing	O
cut	O
,	O
and	O
makes	O
broadband	O
service	O
in	O
Britain	B-LOC
as	O
reasonably	O
priced	O
,	O
if	O
not	O
cheaper	O
,	O
than	O
its	O
equivalent	O
elsewhere	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Whether	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
enough	O
to	O
persuade	O
Britons	O
to	O
sign	O
up	O
for	O
the	O
broadband	O
``	O
revolution	O
''	O
with	O
as	O
much	O
alacrity	O
as	O
Americans	O
or	O
our	O
fellow-	O
Europeans	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
is	O
another	O
matter	O
.	O

Germany	B-LOC
already	O
has	O
2	O
million	O
subscribers	O
,	O
Britain	B-LOC
fewer	O
than	O
150,000	O
.	O

The	O
wonders	O
of	O
broadband	O
are	O
not	O
at	O
issue	O
.	O

The	O
technology	O
allows	O
the	O
same	O
line	O
to	O
be	O
used	O
for	O
Internet	O
access	O
and	O
telephone	O
calls	O
without	O
either	O
capability	O
blocking	O
the	O
other	O
.	O

It	O
enables	O
audio	O
and	O
video	O
files	O
to	O
be	O
transferred	O
almost	O
instantaneously	O
.	O

Whole	O
films	O
can	O
be	O
delivered	O
in	O
minutes	O
.	O

So	O
why	O
has	O
Britain	B-LOC
been	O
so	O
comparatively	O
slow	O
to	O
adopt	O
the	O
new	O
technology	O
?	O

The	O
widely-accepted	O
thesis	O
is	O
that	O
high	O
prices	O
have	O
are	O
the	O
main	O
deterrent	O
.	O

Certainly	O
,	O
œ	O
40	O
a	O
month	O
is	O
steep	O
,	O
and	O
those	O
cable	O
companies	O
that	O
supply	O
high-speed	O
internet	O
access	O
have	O
already	O
attracted	O
more	O
subscribers	O
than	O
BT	B-ORG
,	O
with	O
monthly	O
payments	O
set	O
at	O
œ	O
25	O
.	O

But	O
that	O
is	O
still	O
double	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
many	O
dial-up	O
subscriptions	O
.	O

And	O
for	O
home	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
professional	O
use	O
,	O
dial-up	O
access	O
is	O
adequate	O
.	O

The	O
price	O
cuts	O
announced	O
by	O
BT	B-ORG
mean	O
that	O
the	O
theory	O
of	O
price	O
as	O
the	O
chief	O
obstacle	O
to	O
wider	O
take-up	O
will	O
now	O
be	O
tested	O
.	O

In	O
fact	O
,	O
consumer	O
resistance	O
may	O
lie	O
elsewhere	O
.	O

Even	O
if	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
fast	O
internet	O
access	O
is	O
going	O
down	O
,	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
computers	O
remains	O
static	O
.	O

And	O
,	O
as	O
with	O
mobile	O
phones	O
,	O
there	O
may	O
be	O
a	O
limit	O
to	O
the	O
range	O
of	O
services	O
that	O
people	O
need	O
or	O
want	O
from	O
computers	O
.	O

If	O
they	O
are	O
to	O
conquer	O
the	O
mass	O
market	O
,	O
BT	B-ORG
and	O
the	O
internet	O
service	O
providers	O
must	O
work	O
harder	O
to	O
convince	O
people	O
that	O
their	O
most	O
hi-tech	O
services	O
are	O
not	O
only	O
competitively	O
priced	O
,	O
but	O
relevant	O
to	O
their	O
lives	O
.	O

Decisions	O
on	O
the	O
next	O
phase	O
of	O
the	O
unwisely	O
named	O
war	O
against	O
terrorism	O
are	O
creeping	O
closer	O
,	O
and	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
signs	O
are	O
that	O
George	B-PER
Bush	I-PER
will	O
get	O
them	O
wrong	O
.	O

After	O
he	O
used	O
his	O
State	O
of	O
the	O
Union	O
address	O
to	O
identify	O
the	O
equally	O
unwisely	O
named	O
axis	O
of	O
evil	O
,	O
the	O
pressing	O
question	O
is	O
:	O
what	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
about	O
Iraq	B-LOC
?	O

That	O
something	O
ought	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
about	O
Iraq	B-LOC
should	O
not	O
be	O
in	O
doubt	O
.	O

The	O
question	O
is	O
whether	O
the	O
US	B-LOC
is	O
going	O
to	O
act	O
against	O
its	O
enemies	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
that	O
creates	O
even	O
more	O
enemies	O
.	O

The	O
next	O
question	O
is	O
whether	O
Britain	B-LOC
is	O
going	O
to	O
support	O
whatever	O
President	O
Bush	B-PER
does	O
regardless	O
.	O

Saddam	B-PER
Hussein	I-PER
is	O
still	O
a	O
threat	O
to	O
his	O
neighbours	O
and	O
-	O
potentially	O
-	O
to	O
the	O
US	B-LOC
and	O
its	O
allies	O
.	O

Even	O
if	O
the	O
direct	O
risk	O
to	O
the	O
West	O
from	O
his	O
proven	O
wish	O
to	O
acquire	O
weapons	O
of	O
mass	O
destruction	O
is	O
small	O
,	O
the	O
international	O
community	O
has	O
a	O
responsibility	O
to	O
act	O
.	O

As	O
Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
accepted	O
yesterday	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
not	O
any	O
evidence	O
linking	O
Iraq	B-LOC
with	O
the	O
terrorist	O
attacks	O
of	O
11	O
September	O
.	O

The	O
country	O
must	O
be	O
treated	O
as	O
a	O
problem	O
in	O
its	O
own	O
right	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
issues	O
remain	O
much	O
the	O
same	O
as	O
they	O
were	O
before	O
September	O
last	O
year	O
.	O

The	O
main	O
one	O
is	O
that	O
of	O
sanctions	O
.	O

To	O
his	O
credit	O
,	O
Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
seems	O
to	O
realise	O
that	O
the	O
present	O
sanctions	O
regime	O
plays	O
into	O
Saddam	B-PER
's	O
hands	O
,	O
allowing	O
him	O
to	O
present	O
the	O
Iraqi	O
people	O
as	O
victims	O
of	O
brutal	O
US	B-LOC
imperialism	O
.	O

The	O
British	O
attempt	O
at	O
the	O
United	B-ORG
Nations	I-ORG
last	O
year	O
to	O
lift	O
sanctions	O
on	O
food	O
and	O
most	O
trade	O
foundered	O
on	O
objections	O
by	O
the	O
Russians	O
to	O
the	O
definition	O
of	O
dual-use	O
technology	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
right	O
to	O
pursue	O
a	O
collective	O
approach	O
,	O
through	O
the	O
UN	B-ORG
where	O
possible	O
.	O

The	O
legitimacy	O
of	O
the	O
aerial	O
harassment	O
of	O
Iraq	B-LOC
over	O
the	O
past	O
few	O
years	O
has	O
been	O
weakened	O
by	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
it	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
purely	O
US-British	O
operation	O
.	O

The	O
next	O
phase	O
of	O
the	O
campaign	O
against	O
various	O
forms	O
of	O
international	O
terrorism	O
ought	O
to	O
be	O
conducted	O
through	O
diplomacy	O
,	O
renewing	O
the	O
global	O
coalition	O
-	O
about	O
which	O
Mr	O
Bush	B-PER
seems	O
to	O
have	O
forgotten	O
already	O
-	O
and	O
working	O
for	O
treaties	O
to	O
restrain	O
the	O
proliferation	O
of	O
nuclear	O
,	O
biological	O
and	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
.	O

Instead	O
,	O
the	O
President	O
seems	O
determined	O
to	O
pursue	O
the	O
short-	O
sighted	O
and	O
negative	O
policy	O
of	O
asserting	O
US	B-LOC
might	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
provoke	O
resentment	O
and	O
breed	O
more	O
terrorism	O
.	O

Mr	O
Blair	B-PER
should	O
not	O
be	O
seduced	O
by	O
the	O
collaborationist	O
argument	O
that	O
he	O
will	O
have	O
greater	O
influence	O
over	O
US	B-LOC
policy	O
if	O
he	O
expresses	O
doubts	O
in	O
private	O
.	O

He	O
should	O
say	O
,	O
loud	O
and	O
clear	O
,	O
that	O
US	B-LOC
policy	O
is	O
in	O
danger	O
of	O
becoming	O
counterproductive	O
.	O

Trouble	O
at	O
bank	O
.	O

An	O
abandoned	O
flip	O
chart	O
in	O
the	O
foyer	O
of	O
a	O
Manchester	B-LOC
branch	O
of	O
the	O
Halifax	B-LOC
reveals	O
an	O
innovative	O
policy	O
unusual	O
even	O
in	O
the	O
creative	O
world	O
of	O
finance	O
:	O
they	O
do	O
n't	O
want	O
customers	O
.	O

Specifically	O
,	O
they	O
do	O
n't	O
want	O
new	O
businesses	O
,	O
businesses	O
that	O
deal	O
in	O
coinage	O
:	O
taxi-drivers	O
,	O
window-cleaners	O
,	O
market-traders	O
and	O
shopkeepers	O
.	O

Napoleon	B-PER
would	O
surely	O
have	O
approved	O
.	O

The	O
company	O
might	O
protest	O
that	O
this	O
disinclination	O
is	O
limited	O
to	O
a	O
number	O
of	O
branches	O
,	O
but	O
we	O
doubt	O
it	O
will	O
wash	O
.	O

No	O
business	O
trades	O
on	O
image	O
like	O
a	O
bank	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
Bank	O
That	O
Likes	O
To	O
Say	O
No	O
is	O
splendidly	O
irresistible	O
.	O

Nevertheless	O
,	O
there	O
may	O
well	O
be	O
those	O
who	O
would	O
prefer	O
to	O
bank	O
with	O
a	O
company	O
that	O
refused	O
its	O
facilities	O
to	O
,	O
say	O
,	O
spin	O
doctors	O
,	O
prevaricating	O
politicians	O
,	O
most	O
Antipodean	O
athletes	O
(	O
particularly	O
New	B-LOC
Zealand	I-LOC
cricketers	O
)	O
,	O
anyone	O
associated	O
with	O
the	O
Department	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Transport	I-ORG
,	O
interior	O
designers	O
on	O
TV	O
,	O
Mike	B-PER
Tyson	I-PER
or	O
Lady	O
Victoria	B-PER
Hervey	I-PER
.	O

We	O
,	O
for	O
our	O
part	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
would	O
like	O
to	O
stress	O
and	O
emphasise	O
our	O
intense	O
delight	O
in	O
having	O
you	O
as	O
a	O
customer	O
and	O
look	O
forward	O
to	O
renewing	O
our	O
most	O
rewarding	O
association	O
tomorrow	O
and	O
for	O
many	O
years	O
to	O
come	O
.	O

Thank	O
you	O
.	O

Taxi	O
!	O

The	O
British	O
have	O
never	O
been	O
especially	O
good	O
at	O
providing	O
for	O
their	O
old	O
age	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
current	O
mayhem	O
in	O
the	O
pensions	O
industry	O
can	O
only	O
serve	O
to	O
make	O
matters	O
worse	O
.	O

For	O
much	O
of	O
the	O
second	O
half	O
of	O
the	O
last	O
century	O
this	O
congenital	O
failure	O
to	O
plan	O
ahead	O
did	O
n't	O
matter	O
so	O
much	O
because	O
of	O
two	O
saving	O
graces	O
,	O
now	O
disappearing	O
fast	O
.	O

The	O
first	O
was	O
the	O
state	O
pension	O
;	O
never	O
generous	O
,	O
often	O
inadequate	O
but	O
never	O
means-tested	O
and	O
always	O
available	O
to	O
all	O
.	O

The	O
second	O
was	O
the	O
employer-funded	O
final	O
salary	O
scheme	O
for	O
staff	O
.	O

Most	O
workers	O
may	O
not	O
have	O
even	O
noticed	O
that	O
they	O
were	O
members	O
of	O
such	O
schemes	O
-	O
to	O
which	O
they	O
often	O
made	O
no	O
contribution	O
of	O
their	O
own	O
-	O
until	O
that	O
happy	O
moment	O
when	O
they	O
collected	O
their	O
gold	O
watch	O
and	O
discovered	O
that	O
they	O
would	O
be	O
on	O
a	O
guaranteed	O
income	O
of	O
,	O
say	O
,	O
two-thirds	O
of	O
their	O
final	O
salary	O
for	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
their	O
days	O
,	O
irrespective	O
of	O
the	O
vagaries	O
of	O
the	O
stock	O
market	O
.	O

Now	O
these	O
two	O
pillars	O
are	O
crumbling	O
.	O

The	O
worth	O
of	O
the	O
state	O
pension	O
was	O
eroded	O
after	O
the	O
Thatcher	B-ORG
government	I-ORG
broke	O
the	O
link	O
with	O
average	O
earnings	O
.	O

The	O
abolition	O
of	O
Serps	O
(	O
state	O
earnings-related	O
pension	O
scheme	O
)	O
shortly	O
after	O
also	O
weakened	O
the	O
state	O
's	O
provision	O
.	O

Since	O
Labour	B-ORG
came	O
to	O
power	O
in	O
1997	O
we	O
have	O
seen	O
a	O
move	O
towards	O
means-testing	O
and	O
the	O
prospect	O
of	O
the	O
basic	O
pension	O
withering	O
on	O
the	O
vine	O
.	O

More	O
seriously	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
we	O
now	O
see	O
the	O
move	O
from	O
final	O
salary	O
schemes	O
turn	O
into	O
a	O
stampede	O
.	O

The	O
pensions	O
watchdog	O
Opra	B-ORG
says	O
58,000	O
company	O
schemes	O
have	O
been	O
wound	O
up	O
and	O
30,000	O
of	O
the	O
remaining	O
110,000	O
at	O
risk	O
.	O

Prominent	O
names	O
such	O
as	O
Abbey	B-ORG
National	I-ORG
,	O
Ernst	B-ORG
&	I-ORG
Young	I-ORG
,	O
Marks	B-ORG
&	I-ORG
Spencer	I-ORG
,	O
BT	B-ORG
and	O
J	B-ORG
Sainsbury	I-ORG
have	O
declared	O
their	O
schemes	O
closed	O
to	O
newcomers	O
.	O

The	O
supermarket	O
group	O
Iceland	B-ORG
is	O
even	O
disbanding	O
its	O
scheme	O
for	O
current	O
members	O
,	O
an	O
extraordinary	O
and	O
morally	O
questionable	O
move	O
.	O

This	O
abandonment	O
of	O
final	O
salary	O
schemes	O
is	O
often	O
said	O
by	O
employers	O
to	O
be	O
because	O
of	O
changes	O
in	O
accounting	O
rules	O
(	O
a	O
red	O
herring	O
)	O
;	O
because	O
the	O
schemes	O
are	O
getting	O
expensive	O
(	O
TRUE	O
,	O
but	O
probably	O
not	O
unmanageably	O
so	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
because	O
of	O
the	O
Chancellor	O
,	O
Gordon	B-PER
Brown	I-PER
's	O
``	O
stealth	O
tax	O
''	O
on	O
pension	O
funds	O
.	O

On	O
this	O
last	O
point	O
,	O
at	O
least	O
,	O
the	O
companies	O
are	O
right	O
.	O

Mr	O
Brown	B-PER
took	O
œ	O
5bn	O
a	O
year	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
pensions	O
system	O
in	O
the	O
hope	O
no	O
one	O
would	O
notice	O
-	O
a	O
typically	O
Brownian	O
attempt	O
to	O
pretend	O
that	O
public	O
services	O
can	O
be	O
paid	O
for	O
without	O
pain	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
we	O
now	O
know	O
who	O
will	O
pay	O
for	O
Mr	O
Brown	B-PER
's	O
tax	O
;	O
the	O
young	O
,	O
the	O
pensioners	O
of	O
tomorrow	O
,	O
few	O
of	O
them	O
rich	O
.	O

So	O
without	O
the	O
state	O
or	O
our	O
employers	O
to	O
look	O
after	O
us	O
,	O
what	O
are	O
we	O
to	O
do	O
?	O

The	O
answer	O
to	O
that	O
was	O
provided	O
as	O
long	O
ago	O
as	O
1988	O
when	O
the	O
then	O
Chancellor	O
,	O
Nigel	B-PER
Lawson	I-PER
,	O
introduced	O
personal	O
pensions	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
meant	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
portable	O
answer	O
to	O
the	O
one	O
big	O
drawback	O
with	O
final	O
salary	O
schemes	O
-	O
that	O
few	O
of	O
us	O
remained	O
with	O
one	O
employer	O
for	O
our	O
working	O
lives	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
record	O
has	O
not	O
been	O
happy	O
.	O

High	O
charges	O
,	O
misleading	O
claims	O
and	O
spectacular	O
mis-selling	O
have	O
brought	O
the	O
industry	O
into	O
disrepute	O
.	O

The	O
Government	B-ORG
's	O
``	O
stakeholder	O
''	O
scheme	O
was	O
an	O
attempt	O
to	O
remedy	O
these	O
problems	O
and	O
to	O
encourage	O
the	O
lower	O
paid	O
to	O
take	O
out	O
pensions	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
too	O
has	O
met	O
with	O
a	O
lukewarm	O
response	O
.	O

The	O
outlook	O
,	O
then	O
,	O
is	O
bleak	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
just	O
such	O
very	O
poor	O
savers	O
,	O
now	O
with	O
new	O
excuses	O
about	O
the	O
untrustworthy	O
nature	O
of	O
the	O
financial	O
services	O
industry	O
.	O

The	O
answer	O
would	O
seem	O
to	O
lie	O
in	O
the	O
Government	B-ORG
providing	O
a	O
much	O
more	O
ambitious	O
version	O
of	O
the	O
stakeholder	O
framework	O
that	O
would	O
make	O
private	O
pensions	O
a	O
safer	O
investment	O
,	O
possibly	O
linked	O
to	O
an	O
element	O
of	O
compulsion	O
.	O

And	O
we	O
need	O
to	O
recognise	O
that	O
there	O
will	O
always	O
be	O
those	O
who	O
will	O
never	O
earn	O
enough	O
to	O
secure	O
an	O
adequate	O
income	O
through	O
a	O
private	O
scheme	O
.	O

For	O
their	O
sakes	O
,	O
the	O
state	O
pension	O
can	O
not	O
be	O
allowed	O
to	O
wither	O
away	O
.	O

It	O
seems	O
that	O
Norman	B-PER
Mailer	I-PER
has	O
been	O
uncharacteristically	O
quiet	O
about	O
an	O
event	O
that	O
occurred	O
while	O
he	O
was	O
in	O
England	B-LOC
on	O
a	O
chat	O
tour	O
.	O

Those	O
interviewing	O
the	O
great	O
man	O
about	O
the	O
new	O
mood	O
of	O
Americans	O
were	O
told	O
that	O
``	O
we	O
need	O
our	O
manhood	O
reaffirmed	O
every	O
six	O
seconds	O
''	O
,	O
and	O
this	O
typically	O
Maileresque	O
soundbite	O
has	O
a	O
curious	O
resonance	O
in	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
Jack	B-PER
Henry	I-PER
Abbott	I-PER
,	O
a	O
convicted	O
murderer	O
,	O
who	O
on	O
10	O
February	O
,	O
hung	O
himself	O
in	O
his	O
cell	O
in	O
a	O
Utah	B-LOC
penitentiary	O
.	O

Abbott	B-PER
,	O
it	O
might	O
just	O
be	O
remembered	O
,	O
was	O
briefly	O
famous	O
in	O
1981	O
when	O
he	O
was	O
the	O
hero	O
,	O
then	O
the	O
villain	O
,	O
of	O
a	O
dramatic	O
tale	O
of	O
the	O
literary	O
life	O
.	O

A	O
couple	O
of	O
years	O
previously	O
,	O
after	O
hearing	O
that	O
Norman	B-PER
Mailer	I-PER
was	O
working	O
on	O
a	O
novel	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
life	O
of	O
the	O
executed	O
murderer	O
Gary	B-PER
Gilmore	I-PER
,	O
Abbott	B-PER
had	O
written	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
letters	O
from	O
Marion	B-ORG
Federal	I-ORG
Prison	I-ORG
,	O
Illinois	B-LOC
,	O
about	O
his	O
own	O
miserable	O
life	O
.	O

From	O
the	O
age	O
of	O
13	O
onwards	O
,	O
he	O
had	O
spent	O
all	O
his	O
life	O
,	O
apart	O
from	O
a	O
year	O
on	O
the	O
run	O
in	O
1971	O
,	O
in	O
an	O
institution	O
.	O

Behind	O
bars	O
,	O
he	O
had	O
descended	O
into	O
criminality	O
and	O
was	O
currently	O
serving	O
a	O
sentence	O
for	O
the	O
fatal	O
stabbing	O
of	O
a	O
fellow-inmate	O
.	O

The	O
story	O
that	O
he	O
told	O
,	O
of	O
childhood	O
cruelty	O
and	O
neglect	O
,	O
of	O
woeful	O
judicial	O
prejudice	O
,	O
of	O
survival	O
through	O
violence	O
in	O
the	O
unseen	O
hell	O
of	O
the	O
American	O
penal	O
system	O
,	O
was	O
probably	O
not	O
that	O
unusual	O
.	O

The	O
way	O
that	O
he	O
wrote	O
about	O
it	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
was	O
.	O

``	O
This	O
guy	O
is	O
n't	O
a	O
murderer	O
,	O
he	O
's	O
an	O
artist	O
,	O
''	O
Mailer	B-PER
proclaimed	O
,	O
a	O
trifle	O
rashly	O
under	O
the	O
circumstances	O
.	O

He	O
collected	O
the	O
letters	O
,	O
found	O
a	O
publisher	O
for	O
them	O
and	O
wrote	O
an	O
introduction	O
for	O
the	O
book	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
entitled	O
In	O
the	O
Belly	O
of	O
the	O
Beast	O
.	O

During	O
the	O
fuss	O
surrounding	O
publication	O
,	O
he	O
and	O
other	O
writers	O
and	O
actors	O
began	O
to	O
campaign	O
for	O
Abbott	B-PER
's	O
release	O
on	O
parole	O
.	O

The	O
book	O
came	O
out	O
in	O
1981	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
year	O
,	O
so	O
did	O
its	O
author	O
.	O

Briefly	O
,	O
Abbott	B-PER
became	O
a	O
semi-celebrity	O
in	O
the	O
literary	O
scene	O
.	O

His	O
work	O
was	O
serialised	O
in	O
The	O
New	B-ORG
York	I-ORG
Review	I-ORG
of	I-ORG
Books	I-ORG
.	O

His	O
ferocious	O
,	O
uncompromising	O
prose	O
was	O
acclaimed	O
.	O

The	O
fact	O
that	O
he	O
was	O
walking	O
free	O
,	O
attending	O
book	O
launches	O
and	O
being	O
interviewed	O
on	O
Good	O
Morning	O
America	O
was	O
seen	O
as	O
triumph	O
of	O
writerly	O
solidarity	O
,	O
a	O
victory	O
for	O
literature	O
over	O
life	O
.	O

Foreign	O
rights	O
in	O
the	O
book	O
were	O
sold	O
worldwide	O
,	O
including	O
to	O
Britain	B-LOC
where	O
I	O
,	O
an	O
editor	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
,	O
was	O
the	O
proud	O
publisher	O
.	O

Then	O
,	O
six	O
weeks	O
after	O
Abbott	B-PER
's	O
release	O
,	O
something	O
unfortunate	O
happened	O
.	O

While	O
eating	O
out	O
at	O
a	O
Manhattan	B-LOC
restaurant	O
,	O
the	O
newly	O
famous	O
author	O
became	O
involved	O
in	O
an	O
altercation	O
with	O
Richard	B-PER
Adan	I-PER
,	O
a	O
young	O
waiter	O
-	O
an	O
altercation	O
that	O
ended	O
with	O
Adan	B-PER
being	O
stabbed	O
to	O
death	O
.	O

The	O
literary	O
bandwagon	O
came	O
to	O
a	O
juddering	O
halt	O
.	O

Writers	O
get	O
excited	O
when	O
their	O
quiet	O
existence	O
is	O
enlivened	O
by	O
real	O
events	O
,	O
but	O
that	O
was	O
too	O
real	O
.	O

Mailer	B-PER
,	O
Susan	B-PER
Sarandon	I-PER
and	O
a	O
few	O
others	O
attended	O
Abbott	B-PER
's	O
trial	O
but	O
,	O
where	O
there	O
had	O
been	O
enthusiasm	O
,	O
there	O
was	O
now	O
embarrassment	O
.	O

Those	O
of	O
us	O
who	O
had	O
published	O
the	O
book	O
found	O
ourselves	O
quietly	O
burying	O
it	O
.	O

After	O
his	O
excursion	O
into	O
the	O
world	O
of	O
letters	O
,	O
Jack	B-PER
Henry	I-PER
Abbott	I-PER
resumed	O
a	O
life	O
of	O
obscurity	O
.	O

The	O
incident	O
became	O
accepted	O
as	O
a	O
perfect	O
little	O
parable	O
of	O
liberal	O
naivety	O
,	O
illustrating	O
the	O
dangers	O
incurred	O
by	O
intellectuals	O
who	O
meddled	O
in	O
matters	O
beyond	O
their	O
experience	O
.	O

Opinions	O
of	O
Abbott	B-PER
's	O
talent	O
were	O
quietly	O
revised	O
,	O
with	O
commentators	O
inevitably	O
quoting	O
Humbert	B-PER
Humbert	I-PER
's	O
line	O
from	O
Lolita	O
:	O
``	O
You	O
can	O
always	O
count	O
on	O
a	O
murderer	O
for	O
a	O
fancy	O
prose	O
style	O
.	O
''	O

But	O
perhaps	O
,	O
now	O
that	O
Abbott	B-PER
is	O
dead	O
,	O
it	O
will	O
be	O
seen	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
more	O
to	O
his	O
story	O
than	O
the	O
gullibility	O
of	O
literary	O
types	O
,	O
that	O
its	O
real	O
tragedy	O
lies	O
deep	O
within	O
American	O
society	O
.	O

Evil	O
is	O
the	O
hot	O
,	O
easy	O
subject	O
over	O
there	O
at	O
the	O
moment	O
.	O

Anyone	O
who	O
wants	O
to	O
look	O
beyond	O
the	O
labels	O
and	O
the	O
name-calling	O
could	O
do	O
worse	O
than	O
to	O
read	O
the	O
letters	O
,	O
sent	O
from	O
the	O
belly	O
of	O
the	O
beast	O
,	O
by	O
Abbott	B-PER
.	O

I	O
have	O
,	O
so	O
far	O
as	O
I	O
recall	O
,	O
kept	O
nude	O
photographs	O
of	O
only	O
one	O
author	O
.	O

It	O
happened	O
during	O
the	O
1990s	O
when	O
someone	O
called	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
Wurtzel	I-PER
was	O
in	O
England	B-LOC
promoting	O
her	O
first	O
book	O
,	O
Prozac	O
Nation	O
.	O

While	O
being	O
interviewed	O
for	O
a	O
men	O
's	O
lifestyle	O
magazine	O
,	O
Wurtzel	B-PER
decided	O
to	O
be	O
more	O
self-revealing	O
than	O
is	O
traditional	O
on	O
these	O
occasions	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
photographer	O
turned	O
up	O
,	O
she	O
stripped	O
off	O
for	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
unscheduled	O
candid	O
shots	O
.	O

I	O
found	O
the	O
results	O
rather	O
more	O
interesting	O
than	O
most	O
author	O
profiles	O
,	O
and	O
for	O
several	O
weeks	O
kept	O
them	O
among	O
my	O
papers	O
for	O
occasional	O
reference	O
.	O

This	O
confession	O
,	O
mildly	O
embarrassing	O
as	O
it	O
may	O
be	O
,	O
is	O
not	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
league	O
as	O
the	O
kind	O
of	O
revelation	O
on	O
which	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
(	O
somehow	O
I	O
feel	O
we	O
are	O
on	O
first-name	O
terms	O
)	O
has	O
built	O
her	O
career	O
.	O

In	O
Prozac	O
Nation	O
,	O
she	O
recounted	O
self-destructive	O
adventures	O
with	O
cocaine	O
,	O
men	O
and	O
therapy	O
during	O
her	O
teens	O
and	O
twenties	O
which	O
had	O
led	O
to	O
an	O
addiction	O
to	O
Prozac	O
.	O

The	O
book	O
was	O
written	O
in	O
over-heated	O
but	O
workmanlike	O
prose	O
and	O
,	O
had	O
she	O
been	O
a	O
bloke	O
,	O
or	O
plain	O
,	O
or	O
middle-aged	O
,	O
it	O
would	O
hardly	O
have	O
been	O
publishable	O
.	O

But	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
was	O
a	O
babe	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
prepared	O
to	O
dish	O
intimate	O
details	O
about	O
herself	O
for	O
journalists	O
,	O
give	O
photographers	O
a	O
few	O
literary	O
skin	O
shots	O
.	O

The	O
book	O
became	O
a	O
bestseller	O
and	O
its	O
author	O
was	O
described	O
as	O
``	O
the	O
voice	O
of	O
generation	O
.	O
''	O

The	O
ploy	O
worked	O
so	O
well	O
that	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
appeared	O
,	O
cute	O
as	O
ever	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
cover	O
of	O
her	O
next	O
book	O
Bitch	O
:	O
In	O
Praise	O
of	O
Difficult	O
Women	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
topless	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
but	O
,	O
as	O
a	O
small	O
concession	O
to	O
seriousness	O
,	O
her	O
nipples	O
had	O
been	O
airbrushed	O
out	O
-	O
``	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
does	O
n't	O
have	O
any	O
nipples	O
,	O
''	O
her	O
publisher	O
told	O
a	O
reporter	O
when	O
the	O
publicity	O
wagon	O
began	O
to	O
roll	O
again	O
.	O

The	O
content	O
of	O
Bitch	B-PER
was	O
consistent	O
with	O
its	O
presentation	O
.	O

``	O
Feminist	O
writing	O
has	O
become	O
dry	O
.	O

I	O
want	O
to	O
make	O
it	O
wet	O
again	O
,	O
''	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
announced	O
.	O

After	O
drugs	O
and	O
sex	O
,	O
where	O
does	O
a	O
modern	O
author	O
go	O
?	O

Back	O
to	O
more	O
drugs	O
and	O
sex	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
.	O

This	O
week	O
,	O
a	O
new	O
work	O
from	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
Wurtzel	I-PER
is	O
in	O
the	O
bookshops	O
,	O
recounting	O
her	O
latest	O
addiction	O
,	O
this	O
time	O
to	O
Ritalin	O
,	O
the	O
drug	O
given	O
to	O
hyperactive	O
children	O
.	O

The	O
thought	O
,	O
heartless	O
but	O
irresistible	O
,	O
occurs	O
that	O
professionally	O
this	O
was	O
a	O
neat	O
career	O
move	O
,	O
conforming	O
perfectly	O
to	O
what	O
a	O
publisher	O
wants	O
from	O
an	O
author	O
-	O
the	O
same	O
formula	O
as	O
before	O
,	O
but	O
slightly	O
different	O
.	O

What	O
is	O
interesting	O
about	O
Elizabeth	B-PER
's	O
progress	O
is	O
precisely	O
that	O
her	O
version	O
of	O
emotional	O
porn	O
,	O
the	O
hysterical	O
yet	O
glamorising	O
exploitation	O
of	O
one	O
's	O
own	O
darker	O
secrets	O
,	O
is	O
so	O
sensationally	O
successful	O
.	O

To	O
judge	O
by	O
a	O
lengthy	O
newspaper	O
extract	O
,	O
the	O
new	O
book	O
More	O
,	O
Now	O
,	O
Again	O
is	O
no	O
better	O
written	O
than	O
a	O
promising	O
adolescent	O
's	O
diary	O
,	O
yet	O
its	O
author	O
has	O
been	O
reviewed	O
in	O
Time	B-ORG
magazine	O
and	O
interviewed	O
on	O
CNN	B-ORG
,	O
while	O
her	O
book	O
has	O
been	O
serialised	O
in	O
an	O
allegedly	O
serious	O
British	O
broadsheet	O
.	O

A	O
brief	O
visit	O
to	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
numerous	O
websites	O
devoted	O
to	O
her	O
life	O
and	O
works	O
reveals	O
where	O
her	O
appeal	O
lies	O
.	O

A	O
fan	O
,	O
Heather	B-PER
,	O
writes	O
that	O
``	O
each	O
large	O
paragraph	O
I	O
devour	O
gets	O
me	O
one	O
leap	O
closer	O
to	O
being	O
me	O
.	O
''	O

Another	O
message	O
,	O
headed	O
``	O
A	O
cry	O
for	O
help	O
''	O
,	O
is	O
from	O
Jeanette	B-PER
:	O
``	O
i	O
do	O
n't	O
know	O
why	O
i	O
cry	O
,	O
ca	O
n't	O
sleep	O
or	O
concentrate	O
but	O
i	O
'm	O
getting	O
tired	O
.	O

Slowly	O
i	O
'm	O
dying	O
but	O
i	O
'm	O
still	O
trying	O
at	O
14	O
to	O
find	O
happiness	O
.	O
''	O

This	O
,	O
surely	O
,	O
is	O
a	O
profitable	O
new	O
publishing	O
genre	O
in	O
the	O
making	O
.	O

If	O
Heather	B-PER
and	O
Jeanette	B-PER
are	O
pretty	O
and	O
ambitious	O
,	O
they	O
too	O
might	O
one	O
day	O
turn	O
their	O
intimate	O
secrets	O
into	O
literary	O
gold	O
.	O

If	O
,	O
as	O
seems	O
more	O
likely	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
neither	O
of	O
these	O
things	O
,	O
they	O
will	O
at	O
least	O
have	O
the	O
dubious	O
reassurance	O
that	O
addiction	O
is	O
sexy	O
,	O
that	O
confession	O
,	O
pushed	O
far	O
enough	O
,	O
could	O
make	O
you	O
the	O
voice	O
of	O
a	O
generation	O
.	O

Meanwhile	O
,	O
my	O
former	O
pin-up	O
is	O
offering	O
her	O
views	O
on	O
virtually	O
anything	O
.	O

In	O
Manhattan	B-LOC
during	O
the	O
attack	O
on	O
the	O
World	B-LOC
Trade	I-LOC
Centre	I-LOC
,	O
she	O
later	O
revealed	O
that	O
she	O
felt	O
not	O
the	O
slightest	O
emotional	O
reaction	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
thought	O
,	O
``	O
This	O
is	O
a	O
really	O
strange	O
arts	O
project	O
.	O
''	O
''	O

Those	O
following	O
her	O
career	O
may	O
form	O
the	O
same	O
conclusion	O
.	O

Barrister	O
,	O
war	O
hero	O
,	O
politician	O
.	O

Officially	O
:	O
murdered	O
by	O
Irish	B-ORG
National	I-ORG
Liberation	I-ORG
Army	I-ORG
,	O
30	O
March	O
1979	O
.	O

Unofficially	O
:	O
a	O
spy	O
who	O
knew	O
too	O
much	O
?	O

Unanswered	O
questions	O
:	O
was	O
he	O
involved	O
in	O
dirty	O
tricks	O
and	O
extreme	O
right-wing	O
conspiracies	O
?	O

Why	O
did	O
he	O
have	O
to	O
die	O
?	O

And	O
is	O
the	O
story	O
about	O
to	O
be	O
revealed	O
?	O

As	O
far	O
away	O
as	O
Trafalgar	B-LOC
Square	I-LOC
office-workers	O
felt	O
the	O
shudder	O
.	O

``	O
What	O
was	O
that	O
?	O
''	O
was	O
the	O
question	O
repeated	O
across	O
central	O
London	B-LOC
.	O

Up	O
on	O
the	O
fifth	O
floor	O
of	O
the	O
Ministry	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Defence	I-ORG
,	O
halfway	O
down	O
Whitehall	B-ORG
,	O
someone	O
instantly	O
articulated	O
the	O
answer	O
.	O

``	O
It	O
's	O
a	O
bomb	O
,	O
''	O
the	O
secretaries	O
were	O
told	O
in	O
quiet	O
,	O
chill	O
tones	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
30	O
March	O
1979	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
dull	O
boom	O
was	O
the	O
sound	O
of	O
what	O
was	O
perhaps	O
the	O
most	O
audacious	O
attack	O
ever	O
mounted	O
on	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
the	O
British	O
political	O
establishment	O
in	O
modern	O
times	O
.	O

The	O
bomb	O
,	O
planted	O
by	O
an	O
IRA	B-ORG
splinter	O
group	O
,	O
had	O
exploded	O
in	O
the	O
underground	O
car	O
park	O
inside	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Commons	I-ORG
.	O

A	O
mercury	O
tilt-switch	O
had	O
been	O
activated	O
in	O
the	O
car	O
of	O
the	O
Tory	B-ORG
politician	O
Airey	B-PER
Neave	I-PER
as	O
he	O
drove	O
up	O
the	O
exit	O
ramp	O
.	O

Why	O
Neave	B-PER
?	O

He	O
appeared	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
figure	O
of	O
small	O
consequence	O
.	O

He	O
had	O
last	O
had	O
a	O
post	O
in	O
government	O
in	O
1959	O
,	O
when	O
he	O
was	O
a	O
junior	O
minister	O
in	O
the	O
transport	O
department	O
.	O

In	O
his	O
current	O
position	O
,	O
as	O
opposition	O
spokesmen	O
on	O
Northern	B-LOC
Ireland	I-LOC
,	O
he	O
might	O
have	O
seemed	O
no	O
more	O
a	O
target	O
than	O
the	O
score	O
of	O
other	O
British	O
politicians	O
who	O
had	O
held	O
such	O
a	O
post	O
in	O
recent	O
times	O
.	O

In	O
fact	O
,	O
the	O
life	O
that	O
was	O
brought	O
to	O
an	O
end	O
so	O
violently	O
that	O
day	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
enigmatic	O
in	O
modern	O
politics	O
.	O

For	O
Airey	B-PER
Neave	I-PER
existed	O
in	O
a	O
shadowy	O
world	O
that	O
shifted	O
constantly	O
between	O
the	O
glare	O
of	O
public	O
life	O
and	O
the	O
furtive	O
secrecy	O
of	O
the	O
British	O
intelligence	O
services	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
a	O
man	O
,	O
indeed	O
,	O
who	O
might	O
be	O
said	O
to	O
have	O
not	O
just	O
a	O
double	O
life	O
,	O
but	O
a	O
triple	O
one	O
.	O

Next	O
month	O
,	O
a	O
new	O
biography	O
of	O
the	O
murdered	O
man	O
,	O
Public	O
Servant	O
,	O
Secret	O
Agent	O
,	O
by	O
the	O
political	O
journalist	O
Paul	B-PER
Routledge	I-PER
,	O
is	O
published	O
.	O

It	O
describes	O
Neave	B-PER
as	O
``	O
the	O
ghost	O
in	O
the	O
establishment	O
,	O
faceless	O
and	O
featureless	O
,	O
quietly	O
and	O
decisively	O
fixing	O
the	O
course	O
of	O
events	O
''	O
.	O

But	O
will	O
it	O
unravel	O
the	O
real	O
mystery	O
at	O
the	O
heart	O
of	O
the	O
man	O
?	O

Airey	B-PER
Neave	I-PER
was	O
first	O
thrust	O
into	O
the	O
public	O
eye	O
during	O
the	O
Second	O
World	O
War	O
,	O
when	O
,	O
in	O
1942	O
,	O
he	O
became	O
the	O
first	O
British	O
soldier	O
to	O
escape	O
from	O
the	O
German	O
prisoner-of-war	O
camp	O
in	O
the	O
infamous	O
Colditz	B-ORG
Castle	I-ORG
,	O
which	O
Nazi	B-ORG
propaganda	O
had	O
proclaimed	O
to	O
be	O
``	O
escape-proof	O
''	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
schoolboy	O
tale	O
of	O
derring-do	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
Eton	B-ORG
and	O
Oxford-educated	O
officer	O
-	O
who	O
had	O
already	O
been	O
mentioned	O
in	O
dispatches	O
and	O
awarded	O
the	O
Military	O
Cross	O
for	O
bravery	O
on	O
the	O
battle-field	O
-	O
teamed	O
up	O
with	O
a	O
Dutch	O
officer	O
to	O
stage	O
a	O
daring	O
escape	O
.	O

Dressed	O
in	O
clothes	O
painted	O
to	O
look	O
like	O
German	O
officers	O
'	O
uniforms	O
,	O
with	O
cardboard	O
badges	O
,	O
they	O
wandered	O
into	O
the	O
castle	O
guardroom	O
and	O
then	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
Dutch	O
officer	O
chatting	O
in	O
fluent	O
German	O
,	O
sauntered	O
past	O
the	O
guards	O
whom	O
they	O
ordered	O
to	O
stand	O
to	O
attention	O
,	O
and	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
gate	O
to	O
freedom	O
.	O

From	O
there	O
they	O
made	O
their	O
way	O
through	O
neutral	O
Switzerland	B-LOC
and	O
thence	O
through	O
Vichy	B-LOC
France	I-LOC
to	O
Spain	B-LOC
,	O
Gibraltar	B-LOC
and	O
safety	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
feat	O
that	O
played	O
directly	O
to	O
the	O
cherished	O
wartime	O
stereotype	O
of	O
jaunty	O
British	O
pluck	O
.	O

After	O
the	O
war	O
,	O
newly-qualified	O
as	O
a	O
barrister	O
,	O
Neave	B-PER
was	O
assigned	O
to	O
the	O
British	B-ORG
War	I-ORG
Crimes	I-ORG
Team	I-ORG
at	O
Nuremberg	B-LOC
,	O
where	O
he	O
served	O
the	O
indictments	O
on	O
Goering	B-PER
and	O
the	O
other	O
major	O
Nazi	B-ORG
war	O
criminals	O
.	O

Thereafter	O
he	O
moved	O
into	O
politics	O
,	O
and	O
by	O
1953	O
had	O
become	O
Conservative	B-ORG
MP	O
for	O
the	O
staunch	O
Home	O
Counties	O
seat	O
of	O
Abingdon	B-LOC
.	O

War-hero	O
,	O
lawyer	O
,	O
politician	O
:	O
Lt-Col	O
Airey	B-PER
Neave	I-PER
was	O
,	O
by	O
the	O
age	O
of	O
36	O
,	O
already	O
a	O
man	O
of	O
many	O
parts	O
.	O

Yet	O
that	O
was	O
not	O
all	O
.	O

On	O
his	O
return	O
to	O
Britain	B-LOC
after	O
escaping	O
from	O
Colditz	B-PER
he	O
was	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
strength	O
of	O
his	O
experience	O
,	O
recruited	O
by	O
military	O
intelligence	O
to	O
a	O
division	O
of	O
MI6	B-ORG
known	O
as	O
MI9	B-ORG
,	O
which	O
advised	O
on	O
escape	O
and	O
insurrection	O
in	O
occupied	O
Europe	B-LOC
until	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
war	O
.	O

Neave	B-PER
took	O
part	O
in	O
clandestine	O
operations	O
behind	O
enemy	O
lines	O
,	O
helping	O
other	O
PoWs	O
to	O
escape	O
.	O

So	O
outraged	O
was	O
Hitler	B-PER
by	O
his	O
activities	O
that	O
Neave	B-PER
's	O
London	B-LOC
flat	O
was	O
put	O
on	O
Hitler	B-PER
's	O
target	O
list	O
.	O

Officially	O
,	O
he	O
remained	O
in	O
intelligence	O
until	O
1951	O
.	O

Unofficially	O
,	O
he	O
never	O
left	O
,	O
continuing	O
to	O
be	O
involved	O
in	O
MI6	B-ORG
,	O
as	O
was	O
his	O
wife	O
Diana	B-PER
through	O
her	O
links	O
with	O
the	O
‚migr‚	O
Polish	O
community	O
.	O

(	O
Ironically	O
,	O
the	O
couple	O
did	O
not	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
of	O
their	O
marriage	O
,	O
know	O
about	O
the	O
other	O
's	O
secret	O
life	O
.	O

They	O
found	O
out	O
by	O
chance	O
.	O

``	O
One	O
night	O
,	O
I	O
lost	O
one	O
of	O
my	O
agents	O
,	O
''	O
Diana	B-PER
revealed	O
many	O
years	O
later	O
,	O
``	O
and	O
he	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
Airey	B-PER
's	O
,	O
too	O
,	O
so	O
it	O
all	O
came	O
out	O
over	O
dinner	O
.	O
''	O
)	O

Neave	B-PER
was	O
never	O
to	O
lose	O
his	O
taste	O
for	O
covert	O
manoeuvring	O
,	O
which	O
proved	O
a	O
more-than-useful	O
asset	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
of	O
politics	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
1950s	O
,	O
he	O
had	O
a	O
solid	O
but	O
unremarkable	O
career	O
as	O
a	O
junior	O
minister	O
in	O
the	O
colonial	O
and	O
aviation	O
ministries	O
before	O
falling	O
from	O
favour	O
.	O

He	O
had	O
stood	O
down	O
from	O
his	O
job	O
because	O
of	O
illness	O
,	O
but	O
when	O
he	O
returned	O
in	O
good	O
health	O
and	O
asked	O
for	O
a	O
new	O
job	O
,	O
the	O
then	O
chief	O
whip	O
,	O
Edward	B-PER
Heath	I-PER
,	O
told	O
the	O
right-winger	O
:	O
``	O
You	O
're	O
finished	O
.	O
''	O

For	O
16	O
years	O
,	O
Neave	B-PER
nursed	O
his	O
bitterness	O
;	O
and	O
when	O
,	O
in	O
1975	O
,	O
a	O
challenge	O
was	O
raised	O
to	O
Heath	B-PER
as	O
leader	O
of	O
the	O
Conservative	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
,	O
Neave	B-PER
became	O
campaign	O
manager	O
for	O
the	O
rightist	O
contender	O
,	O
Margaret	B-PER
Thatcher	I-PER
.	O

In	O
a	O
tactical	O
masterstroke	O
,	O
Neave	B-PER
encouraged	O
many	O
backbenchers	O
to	O
think	O
that	O
Thatcher	B-PER
stood	O
little	O
chance	O
of	O
victory	O
.	O

He	O
hinted	O
that	O
MPs	O
who	O
were	O
not	O
themselves	O
on	O
the	O
right	O
of	O
the	O
party	O
,	O
but	O
still	O
felt	O
it	O
was	O
time	O
for	O
Heath	B-PER
to	O
go	O
,	O
should	O
vote	O
Thatcher	B-PER
in	O
the	O
first	O
ballot	O
,	O
thus	O
forcing	O
Heath	B-PER
's	O
resignation	O
and	O
allowing	O
other	O
more	O
likely	O
candidates	O
-	O
such	O
as	O
Willie	B-PER
Whitelaw	I-PER
-	O
to	O
enter	O
the	O
race	O
.	O

Yet	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
event	O
,	O
Thatcher	B-PER
performed	O
so	O
well	O
in	O
the	O
first	O
ballot	O
that	O
she	O
beat	O
Heath	B-PER
,	O
her	O
candidacy	O
gaining	O
so	O
much	O
momentum	O
that	O
none	O
of	O
her	O
rivals	O
could	O
catch	O
her	O
.	O

She	O
won	O
and	O
Neave	B-PER
became	O
the	O
leader	O
of	O
her	O
private	O
office	O
,	O
where	O
his	O
influence	O
-	O
and	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
diaries	O
of	O
the	O
former	O
Tory	B-ORG
minister	O
Alan	B-PER
Clark	I-PER
,	O
his	O
subtlety	O
and	O
insight	O
-	O
were	O
such	O
that	O
Mrs	O
Thatcher	B-PER
said	O
that	O
she	O
had	O
been	O
left	O
feeling	O
``	O
like	O
a	O
puppet	O
whose	O
strings	O
have	O
been	O
cut	O
''	O
.	O

But	O
Neave	B-PER
's	O
manipulations	O
were	O
not	O
restricted	O
to	O
the	O
political	O
arena	O
.	O

Though	O
the	O
Iron	B-PER
Lady	I-PER
,	O
when	O
she	O
became	O
Leader	O
of	O
the	O
Opposition	O
,	O
offered	O
him	O
the	O
chance	O
to	O
shadow	O
any	O
Cabinet	B-ORG
post	O
he	O
wanted	O
-	O
and	O
take	O
on	O
the	O
same	O
job	O
when	O
the	O
Tories	B-ORG
came	O
to	O
power	O
-	O
he	O
chose	O
to	O
forgo	O
the	O
great	O
offices	O
of	O
state	O
and	O
asked	O
for	O
Northern	B-LOC
Ireland	I-LOC
.	O

This	O
meant	O
that	O
,	O
in	O
an	O
era	O
when	O
Ireland	B-LOC
was	O
replacing	O
the	O
Cold	O
War	O
as	O
the	O
chief	O
preoccupation	O
of	O
military	O
intelligence	O
,	O
the	O
security	O
services	O
had	O
one	O
of	O
their	O
men	O
in	O
a	O
pivotal	O
role	O
at	O
a	O
crucial	O
moment	O
in	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
the	O
province	O
.	O

Quite	O
what	O
Neave	B-PER
's	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
secret	O
service	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
years	O
that	O
followed	O
has	O
never	O
become	O
clear	O
.	O

Critics	O
of	O
British	O
policy	O
in	O
Ulster	O
maintained	O
that	O
British	O
intelligence	O
became	O
involved	O
in	O
treasonable	O
policies	O
.	O

In	O
1987	O
,	O
the	O
Labour	B-ORG
MP	O
Ken	B-PER
Livingstone	I-PER
used	O
the	O
cover	O
of	O
parliamentary	O
privilege	O
to	O
suggest	O
in	O
the	O
House	B-ORG
of	I-ORG
Commons	I-ORG
that	O
Airey	B-PER
Neave	I-PER
was	O
a	O
co-	O
conspirator	O
with	O
MI5	B-ORG
and	O
MI6	B-ORG
in	O
disinformation	O
activities	O
involving	O
the	O
controversial	O
whistle-blowing	O
spies	O
Colin	B-PER
Wallace	I-PER
and	O
Peter	B-PER
Wright	I-PER
.	O

He	O
also	O
alleged	O
that	O
,	O
a	O
week	O
before	O
his	O
murder	O
,	O
Neave	B-PER
sought	O
to	O
recruit	O
a	O
former	O
MI6	B-ORG
officer	O
to	O
set	O
up	O
a	O
small	O
group	O
to	O
involve	O
itself	O
in	O
the	O
internal	O
struggles	O
of	O
the	O
Labour	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
.	O

Livingstone	B-PER
's	O
efforts	O
earned	O
him	O
a	O
deluge	O
of	O
condemnation	O
from	O
the	O
British	O
establishment	O
,	O
but	O
there	O
were	O
straws	O
in	O
the	O
wind	O
that	O
induced	O
several	O
security	O
experts	O
to	O
wonder	O
whether	O
something	O
untoward	O
had	O
indeed	O
occurred	O
.	O

These	O
were	O
not	O
the	O
wildest	O
allegations	O
.	O

There	O
were	O
improbable	O
tales	O
about	O
how	O
Neave	B-PER
,	O
and	O
others	O
,	O
had	O
a	O
decade	O
earlier	O
planned	O
to	O
set	O
up	O
an	O
``	O
army	O
of	O
resistance	O
''	O
to	O
the	O
Labour	B-ORG
government	I-ORG
of	O
the	O
Wilson	B-PER
era	O
to	O
``	O
forestall	O
a	O
Communist	O
take-over	O
''	O
and	O
talked	O
of	O
assassinating	O
Tony	B-PER
Benn	I-PER
should	O
he	O
become	O
prime	O
minister	O
.	O

Yet	O
such	O
was	O
the	O
febrile	O
atmosphere	O
of	O
that	O
Cold	O
War	O
epoch	O
that	O
some	O
sceptics	O
gave	O
credibility	O
to	O
the	O
possibility	O
.	O

This	O
was	O
,	O
it	O
must	O
be	O
remembered	O
,	O
the	O
time	O
,	O
about	O
1970	O
,	O
when	O
Auberon	B-PER
Waugh	I-PER
-	O
fed	O
by	O
various	O
sources	O
,	O
including	O
his	O
MI6	B-ORG
agent	O
uncle	O
Auberon	B-PER
Herbert	I-PER
-	O
produced	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
clearly	O
defamatory	O
articles	O
in	O
Private	O
Eye	O
openly	O
alleging	O
that	O
the	O
former	O
prime	O
minister	O
Harold	B-PER
Wilson	I-PER
was	O
a	O
KGB	B-ORG
agent	O
.	O

Even	O
as	O
late	O
as	O
1975	O
,	O
when	O
Mrs	O
Thatcher	B-PER
became	O
leader	O
of	O
the	O
Conservative	B-ORG
Party	I-ORG
,	O
groups	O
of	O
senior	O
Tories	O
were	O
secretly	O
gathering	O
to	O
hear	O
spy-writers	O
such	O
as	O
Chapman	B-PER
Pincher	I-PER
address	O
them	O
on	O
the	O
``	O
grave	O
dangers	O
facing	O
Britain	B-LOC
from	O
the	O
left	O
''	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
such	O
beliefs	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
claims	O
by	O
the	O
anti-fascist	O
magazine	O
Searchlight	O
,	O
that	O
plans	O
for	O
secret	O
armed	O
cells	O
to	O
resist	O
a	O
more	O
left-wing	O
Labour	B-ORG
government	I-ORG
were	O
drawn	O
up	O
by	O
a	O
group	O
that	O
included	O
George	B-PER
Kennedy	I-PER
Young	I-PER
-	O
the	O
ex-deputy	O
director	O
of	O
the	O
British	O
intelligence	O
service	O
MI6	B-ORG
and	O
a	O
notorious	O
racist	O
and	O
anti-Semite	O
-	O
and	O
Airey	B-PER
Neave	I-PER
.	O
