The	O
intense	O
interest	O
aroused	O
in	O
the	O
public	O
by	O
what	O
was	O
known	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
as	O
`	O
The	O
Styles	B-LOC
Case	O
'	O
has	O
now	O
somewhat	O
subsided	O
.	O

Nevertheless	O
,	O
in	O
view	O
of	O
the	O
world-wide	O
notoriety	O
which	O
attended	O
it	O
,	O
I	O
have	O
been	O
asked	O
,	O
both	O
by	O
my	O
friend	O
Poirot	B-PER
and	O
the	O
family	O
themselves	O
,	O
to	O
write	O
an	O
account	O
of	O
the	O
whole	O
story	O
.	O

This	O
,	O
we	O
trust	O
,	O
will	O
effectually	O
silence	O
the	O
sensational	O
rumours	O
which	O
still	O
persist	O
.	O

I	O
will	O
therefore	O
briefly	O
set	O
down	O
the	O
circumstances	O
which	O
led	O
to	O
my	O
being	O
connected	O
with	O
the	O
affair	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
had	O
been	O
invalided	O
home	O
from	O
the	O
Front	O
;	O
and	O
,	O
after	O
spending	O
some	O
months	O
in	O
a	O
rather	O
depressing	O
Convalescent	O
Home	O
,	O
was	O
given	O
a	O
month	O
's	O
sick	O
leave	O
.	O
''	O

Having	O
no	O
near	O
relations	O
or	O
friends	O
,	O
I	O
was	O
trying	O
to	O
make	O
up	O
my	O
mind	O
what	O
to	O
do	O
,	O
when	O
I	O
ran	O
across	O
John	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
.	O

I	O
had	O
seen	O
very	O
little	O
of	O
him	O
for	O
some	O
years	O
.	O

Indeed	O
,	O
I	O
had	O
never	O
known	O
him	O
particularly	O
well	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
a	O
good	O
fifteen	O
years	O
my	O
senior	O
,	O
for	O
one	O
thing	O
,	O
though	O
he	O
hardly	O
looked	O
his	O
forty-five	O
years	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
boy	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
I	O
had	O
often	O
stayed	O
at	O
Styles	B-LOC
,	O
his	O
mother	O
's	O
place	O
in	O
Essex	B-LOC
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
good	O
yarn	O
about	O
old	O
times	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
ended	O
in	O
his	O
inviting	O
me	O
down	O
to	O
Styles	B-LOC
to	O
spend	O
my	O
leave	O
there	O
.	O

The	O
mater	O
will	O
be	O
delighted	O
to	O
see	O
you	O
again	O
...	O
after	O
all	O
those	O
years	O
,	O
he	O
added	O
.	O

Your	O
mother	O
keeps	O
well	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
yes	O
.	O

I	O
suppose	O
you	O
know	O
that	O
she	O
has	O
married	O
again	O
?	O

I	O
am	O
afraid	O
I	O
showed	O
my	O
surprise	O
rather	O
plainly	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
,	O
who	O
had	O
married	O
John	B-PER
's	O
father	O
when	O
he	O
was	O
a	O
widower	O
with	O
two	O
sons	O
,	O
had	O
been	O
a	O
handsome	O
woman	O
of	O
middle-age	O
as	O
I	O
remembered	O
her	O
.	O

She	O
certainly	O
could	O
not	O
be	O
a	O
day	O
less	O
than	O
seventy	O
now	O
.	O

I	O
recalled	O
her	O
as	O
an	O
energetic	O
,	O
autocratic	O
personality	O
,	O
somewhat	O
inclined	O
to	O
charitable	O
and	O
social	O
notoriety	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
fondness	O
for	O
opening	O
bazaars	O
and	O
playing	O
the	O
Lady	O
Bountiful	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
a	O
most	O
generous	O
woman	O
,	O
and	O
possessed	O
a	O
considerable	O
fortune	O
of	O
her	O
own	O
.	O

Their	O
country-place	O
,	O
Styles	B-LOC
Court	I-LOC
,	O
had	O
been	O
purchased	O
by	O
Mr.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
early	O
in	O
their	O
married	O
life	O
.	O

``	O
He	O
had	O
been	O
completely	O
under	O
his	O
wife	O
's	O
ascendancy	O
,	O
so	O
much	O
so	O
that	O
,	O
on	O
dying	O
,	O
he	O
left	O
the	O
place	O
to	O
her	O
for	O
her	O
lifetime	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
larger	O
part	O
of	O
his	O
income	O
;	O
an	O
arrangement	O
that	O
was	O
distinctly	O
unfair	O
to	O
his	O
two	O
sons	O
.	O
''	O

``	O
Their	O
step-mother	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
had	O
always	O
been	O
most	O
generous	O
to	O
them	O
;	O
indeed	O
,	O
they	O
were	O
so	O
young	O
at	O
the	O
time	O
of	O
their	O
father	O
's	O
remarriage	O
that	O
they	O
always	O
thought	O
of	O
her	O
as	O
their	O
own	O
mother	O
.	O
''	O

Lawrence	B-PER
,	O
the	O
younger	O
,	O
had	O
been	O
a	O
delicate	O
youth	O
.	O

``	O
He	O
had	O
qualified	O
as	O
a	O
doctor	O
but	O
early	O
relinquished	O
the	O
profession	O
of	O
medicine	O
,	O
and	O
lived	O
at	O
home	O
while	O
pursuing	O
literary	O
ambitions	O
;	O
though	O
his	O
verses	O
never	O
had	O
any	O
marked	O
success	O
.	O
''	O

John	B-PER
practiced	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
as	O
a	O
barrister	O
,	O
but	O
had	O
finally	O
settled	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
more	O
congenial	O
life	O
of	O
a	O
country	O
squire	O
.	O

He	O
had	O
married	O
two	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
taken	O
his	O
wife	O
to	O
live	O
at	O
Styles	B-LOC
,	O
though	O
I	O
entertained	O
a	O
shrewd	O
suspicion	O
that	O
he	O
would	O
have	O
preferred	O
his	O
mother	O
to	O
increase	O
his	O
allowance	O
,	O
which	O
would	O
have	O
enabled	O
him	O
to	O
have	O
a	O
home	O
of	O
his	O
own	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
,	O
however	O
,	O
was	O
a	O
lady	O
who	O
liked	O
to	O
make	O
her	O
own	O
plans	O
,	O
and	O
expected	O
other	O
people	O
to	O
fall	O
in	O
with	O
them	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
this	O
case	O
she	O
certainly	O
had	O
the	O
whip	O
hand	O
,	O
namely	O
:	O
the	O
purse	O
strings	O
.	O

John	B-PER
noticed	O
my	O
surprise	O
at	O
the	O
news	O
of	O
his	O
mother	O
's	O
remarriage	O
and	O
smiled	O
rather	O
ruefully	O
.	O

Rotten	O
little	O
bounder	O
too	O
!	O

he	O
said	O
savagely	O
.	O

I	O
can	O
tell	O
you	O
,	O
Hastings	B-PER
,	O
it	O
's	O
making	O
life	O
jolly	O
difficult	O
for	O
us	O
.	O

As	O
for	O
Evie	B-PER
...	O
you	O
remember	O
Evie	B-PER
?	O

No	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
I	O
suppose	O
she	O
was	O
after	O
your	O
time	O
.	O

She	O
's	O
the	O
mater	O
's	O
factotum	O
,	O
companion	O
,	O
Jack	B-PER
of	O
all	O
trades	O
!	O

A	O
great	O
sport	O
...	O
old	O
Evie	B-PER
!	O

Not	O
precisely	O
young	O
and	O
beautiful	O
,	O
but	O
as	O
game	O
as	O
they	O
make	O
them	O
.	O

You	O
were	O
going	O
to	O
say	O
...	O
?	O

Oh	O
,	O
this	O
fellow	O
!	O

He	O
turned	O
up	O
from	O
nowhere	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
pretext	O
of	O
being	O
a	O
second	O
cousin	O
or	O
something	O
of	O
Evie	B-PER
's	O
,	O
though	O
she	O
did	O
n't	O
seem	O
particularly	O
keen	O
to	O
acknowledge	O
the	O
relationship	O
.	O

The	O
fellow	O
is	O
an	O
absolute	O
outsider	O
,	O
anyone	O
can	O
see	O
that	O
.	O

He	O
's	O
got	O
a	O
great	O
black	O
beard	O
,	O
and	O
wears	O
patent	O
leather	O
boots	O
in	O
all	O
weathers	O
!	O

But	O
the	O
mater	O
cottoned	O
to	O
him	O
at	O
once	O
,	O
took	O
him	O
on	O
as	O
secretary	O
...	O
you	O
know	O
how	O
she	O
's	O
always	O
running	O
a	O
hundred	O
societies	O
?	O

I	O
nodded	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
the	O
war	O
has	O
turned	O
the	O
hundreds	O
into	O
thousands	O
.	O

No	O
doubt	O
the	O
fellow	O
was	O
very	O
useful	O
to	O
her	O
.	O

But	O
you	O
could	O
have	O
knocked	O
us	O
all	O
down	O
with	O
a	O
feather	O
when	O
,	O
three	O
months	O
ago	O
,	O
she	O
suddenly	O
announced	O
that	O
she	O
and	O
Alfred	B-PER
were	O
engaged	O
!	O

The	O
fellow	O
must	O
be	O
at	O
least	O
twenty	O
years	O
younger	O
than	O
she	O
is	O
!	O

``	O
It	O
's	O
simply	O
bare-faced	O
fortune	O
hunting	O
;	O
but	O
there	O
you	O
are	O
...	O
she	O
is	O
her	O
own	O
mistress	O
,	O
and	O
she	O
's	O
married	O
him	O
.	O
''	O

It	O
must	O
be	O
a	O
difficult	O
situation	O
for	O
you	O
all	O
.	O

Difficult	O
!	O

It	O
's	O
damnable	O
!	O

Thus	O
it	O
came	O
about	O
that	O
,	O
three	O
days	O
later	O
,	O
I	O
descended	O
from	O
the	O
train	O
at	O
Styles	B-LOC
St.	I-LOC
Mary	I-LOC
,	O
an	O
absurd	O
little	O
station	O
,	O
with	O
no	O
apparent	O
reason	O
for	O
existence	O
,	O
perched	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
midst	O
of	O
green	O
fields	O
and	O
country	O
lanes	O
.	O

John	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
was	O
waiting	O
on	O
the	O
platform	O
,	O
and	O
piloted	O
me	O
out	O
to	O
the	O
car	O
.	O

Got	O
a	O
drop	O
or	O
two	O
of	O
petrol	O
still	O
,	O
you	O
see	O
,	O
he	O
remarked	O
.	O

Mainly	O
owing	O
to	O
the	O
mater	O
's	O
activities	O
.	O

The	O
village	O
of	O
Styles	B-LOC
St.	I-LOC
Mary	I-LOC
was	O
situated	O
about	O
two	O
miles	O
from	O
the	O
little	O
station	O
,	O
and	O
Styles	B-LOC
Court	I-LOC
lay	O
a	O
mile	O
the	O
other	O
side	O
of	O
it	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
still	O
,	O
warm	O
day	O
in	O
early	O
July	O
.	O

As	O
one	O
looked	O
out	O
over	O
the	O
flat	O
Essex	B-LOC
country	O
,	O
lying	O
so	O
green	O
and	O
peaceful	O
under	O
the	O
afternoon	O
sun	O
,	O
it	O
seemed	O
almost	O
impossible	O
to	O
believe	O
that	O
,	O
not	O
so	O
very	O
far	O
away	O
,	O
a	O
great	O
war	O
was	O
running	O
its	O
appointed	O
course	O
.	O

I	O
felt	O
I	O
had	O
suddenly	O
strayed	O
into	O
another	O
world	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
turned	O
in	O
at	O
the	O
lodge	O
gates	O
,	O
John	B-PER
said	O
:	O
I	O
'm	O
afraid	O
you	O
'll	O
find	O
it	O
very	O
quiet	O
down	O
here	O
,	O
Hastings	B-PER
.	O

My	O
dear	O
fellow	O
,	O
that	O
's	O
just	O
what	O
I	O
want	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
pleasant	O
enough	O
if	O
you	O
want	O
to	O
lead	O
the	O
idle	O
life	O
.	O

I	O
drill	O
with	O
the	O
volunteers	O
twice	O
a	O
week	O
,	O
and	O
lend	O
a	O
hand	O
at	O
the	O
farms	O
.	O

My	O
wife	O
works	O
regularly	O
`	O
on	O
the	O
land	O
'	O
.	O

She	O
is	O
up	O
at	O
five	O
every	O
morning	O
to	O
milk	O
,	O
and	O
keeps	O
at	O
it	O
steadily	O
until	O
lunchtime	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
a	O
jolly	O
good	O
life	O
taking	O
it	O
all	O
round	O
...	O
if	O
it	O
were	O
n't	O
for	O
that	O
fellow	O
Alfred	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
!	O

He	O
checked	O
the	O
car	O
suddenly	O
,	O
and	O
glanced	O
at	O
his	O
watch	O
.	O

I	O
wonder	O
if	O
we	O
've	O
time	O
to	O
pick	O
up	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

No	O
,	O
she	O
'll	O
have	O
started	O
from	O
the	O
hospital	O
by	O
now	O
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
!	O

That	O
's	O
not	O
your	O
wife	O
?	O

No	O
,	O
Cynthia	B-PER
is	O
a	O
protegee	O
of	O
my	O
mother	O
's	O
,	O
the	O
daughter	O
of	O
an	O
old	O
schoolfellow	O
of	O
hers	O
,	O
who	O
married	O
a	O
rascally	O
solicitor	O
.	O

He	O
came	O
a	O
cropper	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
girl	O
was	O
left	O
an	O
orphan	O
and	O
penniless	O
.	O

My	O
mother	O
came	O
to	O
the	O
rescue	O
,	O
and	O
Cynthia	B-PER
has	O
been	O
with	O
us	O
nearly	O
two	O
years	O
now	O
.	O

She	O
works	O
in	O
the	O
Red	B-ORG
Cross	I-ORG
Hospital	I-ORG
at	O
Tadminster	B-LOC
,	O
seven	O
miles	O
away	O
.	O

As	O
he	O
spoke	O
the	O
last	O
words	O
,	O
we	O
drew	O
up	O
in	O
front	O
of	O
the	O
fine	O
old	O
house	O
.	O

A	O
lady	O
in	O
a	O
stout	O
tweed	O
skirt	O
,	O
who	O
was	O
bending	O
over	O
a	O
flower	O
bed	O
,	O
straightened	O
herself	O
at	O
our	O
approach	O
.	O

Hullo	O
,	O
Evie	B-PER
,	O
here	O
's	O
our	O
wounded	O
hero	O
!	O

Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
...	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
.	O

Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
shook	O
hands	O
with	O
a	O
hearty	O
,	O
almost	O
painful	O
,	O
grip	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
an	O
impression	O
of	O
very	O
blue	O
eyes	O
in	O
a	O
sunburnt	O
face	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
a	O
pleasant-looking	O
woman	O
of	O
about	O
forty	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
deep	O
voice	O
,	O
almost	O
manly	O
in	O
its	O
stentorian	O
tones	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
large	O
sensible	O
square	O
body	O
,	O
with	O
feet	O
to	O
match	O
...	O
these	O
last	O
encased	O
in	O
good	O
thick	O
boots	O
.	O

Her	O
conversation	O
,	O
I	O
soon	O
found	O
,	O
was	O
couched	O
in	O
the	O
telegraphic	O
style	O
.	O

Weeds	O
grow	O
like	O
house	O
afire	O
.	O

Ca	O
n't	O
keep	O
even	O
with	O
'em	O
.	O

Shall	O
press	O
you	O
in	O
.	O

Better	O
be	O
careful	O
.	O

I	O
'm	O
sure	O
I	O
shall	O
be	O
only	O
too	O
delighted	O
to	O
make	O
myself	O
useful	O
,	O
I	O
responded	O
.	O

Do	O
n't	O
say	O
it	O
.	O

Never	O
does	O
.	O

Wish	O
you	O
had	O
n't	O
later	O
.	O

You	O
're	O
a	O
cynic	O
,	O
Evie	B-PER
,	O
said	O
John	B-PER
,	O
laughing	O
.	O

Where	O
's	O
tea	O
today	O
...	O
inside	O
or	O
out	O
?	O

Out	O
.	O

Too	O
fine	O
a	O
day	O
to	O
be	O
cooped	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
house	O
.	O

Come	O
on	O
then	O
,	O
you	O
've	O
done	O
enough	O
gardening	O
for	O
today	O
.	O

`	O
The	O
labourer	O
is	O
worthy	O
of	O
his	O
hire	O
'	O
,	O
you	O
know	O
.	O

Come	O
and	O
be	O
refreshed	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
said	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
,	O
drawing	O
off	O
her	O
gardening	O
gloves	O
,	O
I	O
'm	O
inclined	O
to	O
agree	O
with	O
you	O
.	O

She	O
led	O
the	O
way	O
round	O
the	O
house	O
to	O
where	O
tea	O
was	O
spread	O
under	O
the	O
shade	O
of	O
a	O
large	O
sycamore	O
.	O

A	O
figure	O
rose	O
from	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
basket	O
chairs	O
,	O
and	O
came	O
a	O
few	O
steps	O
to	O
meet	O
us	O
.	O

My	O
wife	O
,	O
Hastings	B-PER
,	O
said	O
John	B-PER
.	O

I	O
shall	O
never	O
forget	O
my	O
first	O
sight	O
of	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
.	O

``	O
Her	O
tall	O
,	O
slender	O
form	O
,	O
outlined	O
against	O
the	O
bright	O
light	O
;	O
the	O
vivid	O
sense	O
of	O
slumbering	O
fire	O
that	O
seemed	O
to	O
find	O
expression	O
only	O
in	O
those	O
wonderful	O
tawny	O
eyes	O
of	O
hers	O
,	O
remarkable	O
eyes	O
,	O
different	O
from	O
any	O
other	O
woman	O
's	O
that	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
known	O
;	O
the	O
intense	O
power	O
of	O
stillness	O
she	O
possessed	O
,	O
which	O
nevertheless	O
conveyed	O
the	O
impression	O
of	O
a	O
wild	O
untamed	O
spirit	O
in	O
an	O
exquisitely	O
civilised	O
body	O
...	O
all	O
these	O
things	O
are	O
burnt	O
into	O
my	O
memory	O
.	O
''	O

I	O
shall	O
never	O
forget	O
them	O
.	O

She	O
greeted	O
me	O
with	O
a	O
few	O
words	O
of	O
pleasant	O
welcome	O
in	O
a	O
low	O
clear	O
voice	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
sank	O
into	O
a	O
basket	O
chair	O
feeling	O
distinctly	O
glad	O
that	O
I	O
had	O
accepted	O
John	B-PER
's	O
invitation	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
gave	O
me	O
some	O
tea	O
,	O
and	O
her	O
few	O
quiet	O
remarks	O
heightened	O
my	O
first	O
impression	O
of	O
her	O
as	O
a	O
thoroughly	O
fascinating	O
woman	O
.	O

An	O
appreciative	O
listener	O
is	O
always	O
stimulating	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
described	O
,	O
in	O
a	O
humorous	O
manner	O
,	O
certain	O
incidents	O
of	O
my	O
Convalescent	B-ORG
Home	I-ORG
,	O
in	O
a	O
way	O
which	O
,	O
I	O
flatter	O
myself	O
,	O
greatly	O
amused	O
my	O
hostess	O
.	O

John	B-PER
,	O
of	O
course	O
,	O
good	O
fellow	O
though	O
he	O
is	O
,	O
could	O
hardly	O
be	O
called	O
a	O
brilliant	O
conversationalist	O
.	O

At	O
that	O
moment	O
a	O
well	O
remembered	O
voice	O
floated	O
through	O
the	O
open	O
French	O
window	O
near	O
at	O
hand	O
:	O
Then	O
you	O
'll	O
write	O
to	O
the	O
Princess	O
after	O
tea	O
,	O
Alfred	B-PER
?	O

I	O
'll	O
write	O
to	O
Lady	B-PER
Tadminster	I-PER
for	O
the	O
second	O
day	O
,	O
myself	O
.	O

Or	O
shall	O
we	O
wait	O
until	O
we	O
hear	O
from	O
the	O
Princess	O
?	O

In	O
case	O
of	O
a	O
refusal	O
,	O
Lady	B-PER
Tadminster	I-PER
might	O
open	O
it	O
the	O
first	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Crosbie	I-PER
the	O
second	O
.	O

Then	O
there	O
's	O
the	O
Duchess	O
...	O
about	O
the	O
school	O
fete	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
the	O
murmur	O
of	O
a	O
man	O
's	O
voice	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
rose	O
in	O
reply	O
:	O
Yes	O
,	O
certainly	O
.	O

After	O
tea	O
will	O
do	O
quite	O
well	O
.	O

You	O
are	O
so	O
thoughtful	O
,	O
Alfred	B-PER
dear	O
.	O

The	O
French	O
window	O
swung	O
open	O
a	O
little	O
wider	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
handsome	O
white-haired	O
old	O
lady	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
somewhat	O
masterful	O
cast	O
of	O
features	O
,	O
stepped	O
out	O
of	O
it	O
on	O
to	O
the	O
lawn	O
.	O

A	O
man	O
followed	O
her	O
,	O
a	O
suggestion	O
of	O
deference	O
in	O
his	O
manner	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
greeted	O
me	O
with	O
effusion	O
.	O

Why	O
,	O
if	O
it	O
is	O
n't	O
too	O
delightful	O
to	O
see	O
you	O
again	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
,	O
after	O
all	O
these	O
years	O
.	O

Alfred	B-PER
,	O
darling	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
...	O
my	O
husband	O
.	O

I	O
looked	O
with	O
some	O
curiosity	O
at	O
`	O
Alfred	B-PER
darling	O
'	O
.	O

He	O
certainly	O
struck	O
a	O
rather	O
alien	O
note	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
not	O
wonder	O
at	O
John	B-PER
objecting	O
to	O
his	O
beard	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
longest	O
and	O
blackest	O
I	O
have	O
ever	O
seen	O
.	O

He	O
wore	O
gold-rimmed	O
pince-nez	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
a	O
curious	O
impassivity	O
of	O
feature	O
.	O

It	O
struck	O
me	O
that	O
he	O
might	O
look	O
natural	O
on	O
a	O
stage	O
,	O
but	O
was	O
strangely	O
out	O
of	O
place	O
in	O
real	O
life	O
.	O

His	O
voice	O
was	O
rather	O
deep	O
and	O
unctuous	O
.	O

He	O
placed	O
a	O
wooden	O
hand	O
in	O
mine	O
and	O
said	O
:	O
This	O
is	O
a	O
pleasure	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
.	O

Then	O
,	O
turning	O
to	O
his	O
wife	O
:	O
Emily	B-PER
dearest	O
,	O
I	O
think	O
that	O
cushion	O
is	O
a	O
little	O
damp	O
.	O

She	O
beamed	O
fondly	O
on	O
him	O
,	O
as	O
he	O
substituted	O
another	O
with	O
every	O
demonstration	O
of	O
the	O
tenderest	O
care	O
.	O

Strange	O
infatuation	O
of	O
an	O
otherwise	O
sensible	O
woman	O
!	O

With	O
the	O
presence	O
of	O
Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
,	O
a	O
sense	O
of	O
constraint	O
and	O
veiled	O
hostility	O
seemed	O
to	O
settle	O
down	O
upon	O
the	O
company	O
.	O

Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
,	O
in	O
particular	O
,	O
took	O
no	O
pains	O
to	O
conceal	O
her	O
feelings	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
,	O
however	O
,	O
seemed	O
to	O
notice	O
nothing	O
unusual	O
.	O

Her	O
volubility	O
,	O
which	O
I	O
remembered	O
of	O
old	O
,	O
had	O
lost	O
nothing	O
in	O
the	O
intervening	O
years	O
,	O
and	O
she	O
poured	O
out	O
a	O
steady	O
flood	O
of	O
conversation	O
,	O
mainly	O
on	O
the	O
subject	O
of	O
the	O
forthcoming	O
bazaar	O
which	O
she	O
was	O
organizing	O
and	O
which	O
was	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
shortly	O
.	O

Occasionally	O
she	O
referred	O
to	O
her	O
husband	O
over	O
a	O
question	O
of	O
days	O
or	O
dates	O
.	O

His	O
watchful	O
and	O
attentive	O
manner	O
never	O
varied	O
.	O

From	O
the	O
very	O
first	O
I	O
took	O
a	O
firm	O
and	O
rooted	O
dislike	O
to	O
him	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
flatter	O
myself	O
that	O
my	O
first	O
judgments	O
are	O
usually	O
fairly	O
shrewd	O
.	O

Presently	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
turned	O
to	O
give	O
some	O
instructions	O
about	O
letters	O
to	O
Evelyn	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
,	O
and	O
her	O
husband	O
addressed	O
me	O
in	O
his	O
painstaking	O
voice	O
:	O
Is	O
soldiering	O
your	O
regular	O
profession	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
?	O

No	O
,	O
before	O
the	O
war	O
I	O
was	O
in	O
Lloyd	B-ORG
's	I-ORG
.	O

And	O
you	O
will	O
return	O
there	O
after	O
it	O
is	O
over	O
?	O

Perhaps	O
.	O

Either	O
that	O
or	O
a	O
fresh	O
start	O
altogether	O
.	O

Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
leant	O
forward	O
.	O

What	O
would	O
you	O
really	O
choose	O
as	O
a	O
profession	O
,	O
if	O
you	O
could	O
just	O
consult	O
your	O
inclination	O
?	O

Well	O
,	O
that	O
depends	O
.	O

No	O
secret	O
hobby	O
?	O

she	O
asked	O
.	O

Tell	O
me	O
...	O
you	O
're	O
drawn	O
to	O
something	O
?	O

Every	O
one	O
is	O
...	O
usually	O
something	O
absurd	O
.	O

You	O
'll	O
laugh	O
at	O
me	O
.	O

She	O
smiled	O
.	O

Perhaps	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
I	O
've	O
always	O
had	O
a	O
secret	O
hankering	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
detective	O
!	O

The	O
real	O
thing	O
...	O
Scotland	B-ORG
Yard	I-ORG
?	O

Or	O
Sherlock	B-PER
Holmes	I-PER
?	O

Oh	O
,	O
Sherlock	B-PER
Holmes	I-PER
by	O
all	O
means	O
.	O

But	O
really	O
,	O
seriously	O
,	O
I	O
am	O
awfully	O
drawn	O
to	O
it	O
.	O

I	O
came	O
across	O
a	O
man	O
in	O
Belgium	B-LOC
once	O
,	O
a	O
very	O
famous	O
detective	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
quite	O
inflamed	O
me	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
a	O
marvellous	O
little	O
fellow	O
.	O

He	O
used	O
to	O
say	O
that	O
all	O
good	O
detective	O
work	O
was	O
a	O
mere	O
matter	O
of	O
method	O
.	O

My	O
system	O
is	O
based	O
on	O
his	O
...	O
though	O
of	O
course	O
I	O
have	O
progressed	O
rather	O
further	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
a	O
funny	O
little	O
man	O
,	O
a	O
great	O
dandy	O
,	O
but	O
wonderfully	O
clever	O
.	O

Like	O
a	O
good	O
detective	O
story	O
myself	O
,	O
remarked	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
.	O

Lots	O
of	O
nonsense	O
written	O
,	O
though	O
.	O

Criminal	O
discovered	O
in	O
last	O
chapter	O
.	O

Every	O
one	O
dumbfounded	O
.	O

Real	O
crime	O
...	O
you	O
'd	O
know	O
at	O
once	O
.	O

There	O
have	O
been	O
a	O
great	O
number	O
of	O
undiscovered	O
crimes	O
,	O
I	O
argued	O
.	O

Do	O
n't	O
mean	O
the	O
police	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
people	O
that	O
are	O
right	O
in	O
it	O
.	O

The	O
family	O
.	O

You	O
could	O
n't	O
really	O
hoodwink	O
them	O
.	O

They	O
'd	O
know	O
.	O

Then	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
much	O
amused	O
,	O
you	O
think	O
that	O
if	O
you	O
were	O
mixed	O
up	O
in	O
a	O
crime	O
,	O
say	O
a	O
murder	O
,	O
you	O
'd	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
spot	O
the	O
murderer	O
right	O
off	O
?	O

Of	O
course	O
I	O
should	O
.	O

Might	O
n't	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
prove	O
it	O
to	O
a	O
pack	O
of	O
lawyers	O
.	O

But	O
I	O
'm	O
certain	O
I	O
'd	O
know	O
.	O

I	O
'd	O
feel	O
it	O
in	O
my	O
fingertips	O
if	O
he	O
came	O
near	O
me	O
.	O

It	O
might	O
be	O
a	O
`	O
she	O
,	O
'	O
I	O
suggested	O
.	O

Might	O
.	O

But	O
murder	O
's	O
a	O
violent	O
crime	O
.	O

Associate	O
it	O
more	O
with	O
a	O
man	O
.	O

Not	O
in	O
a	O
case	O
of	O
poisoning	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
's	O
clear	O
voice	O
startled	O
me	O
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
was	O
saying	O
yesterday	O
that	O
,	O
owing	O
to	O
the	O
general	O
ignorance	O
of	O
the	O
more	O
uncommon	O
poisons	O
among	O
the	O
medical	O
profession	O
,	O
there	O
were	O
probably	O
countless	O
cases	O
of	O
poisoning	O
quite	O
unsuspected	O
.	O

Why	O
,	O
Mary	B-PER
,	O
what	O
a	O
gruesome	O
conversation	O
!	O

cried	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
.	O

It	O
makes	O
me	O
feel	O
as	O
if	O
a	O
goose	O
were	O
walking	O
over	O
my	O
grave	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
there	O
's	O
Cynthia	B-PER
!	O

A	O
young	O
girl	O
in	O
V.	O
A.	O
D.	O
uniform	O
ran	O
lightly	O
across	O
the	O
lawn	O
.	O

Why	O
,	O
Cynthia	B-PER
,	O
you	O
are	O
late	O
today	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
...	O
Miss	B-PER
Murdoch	I-PER
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
Murdoch	I-PER
was	O
a	O
fresh-looking	O
young	O
creature	O
,	O
full	O
of	O
life	O
and	O
vigour	O
.	O

She	O
tossed	O
off	O
her	O
little	O
V.	O
A.	O
D.	O
cap	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
admired	O
the	O
great	O
loose	O
waves	O
of	O
her	O
auburn	O
hair	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
smallness	O
and	O
whiteness	O
of	O
the	O
hand	O
she	O
held	O
out	O
to	O
claim	O
her	O
tea	O
.	O

With	O
dark	O
eyes	O
and	O
eyelashes	O
she	O
would	O
have	O
been	O
a	O
beauty	O
.	O

She	O
flung	O
herself	O
down	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
beside	O
John	B-PER
,	O
and	O
as	O
I	O
handed	O
her	O
a	O
plate	O
of	O
sandwiches	O
she	O
smiled	O
up	O
at	O
me	O
.	O

Sit	O
down	O
here	O
on	O
the	O
grass	O
,	O
do	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
ever	O
so	O
much	O
nicer	O
.	O

I	O
dropped	O
down	O
obediently	O
.	O

You	O
work	O
at	O
Tadminster	B-LOC
,	O
do	O
n't	O
you	O
,	O
Miss	B-PER
Murdoch	I-PER
?	O

She	O
nodded	O
.	O

For	O
my	O
sins	O
.	O

Do	O
they	O
bully	O
you	O
,	O
then	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
,	O
smiling	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
see	O
them	O
!	O

cried	O
Cynthia	B-PER
with	O
dignity	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
got	O
a	O
cousin	O
who	O
is	O
nursing	O
,	O
I	O
remarked	O
.	O

And	O
she	O
is	O
terrified	O
of	O
`	O
Sisters	O
'	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
n't	O
wonder	O
.	O

Sisters	O
are	O
,	O
you	O
know	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
.	O

They	O
simply	O
are	O
!	O

You	O
've	O
no	O
idea	O
!	O

But	O
I	O
'm	O
not	O
a	O
nurse	O
,	O
thank	O
heaven	O
,	O
I	O
work	O
in	O
the	O
dispensary	O
.	O

How	O
many	O
people	O
do	O
you	O
poison	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
,	O
smiling	O
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
smiled	O
too	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
hundreds	O
!	O

she	O
said	O
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
,	O
called	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
,	O
do	O
you	O
think	O
you	O
could	O
write	O
a	O
few	O
notes	O
for	O
me	O
?	O

Certainly	O
,	O
Aunt	B-PER
Emily	I-PER
.	O

She	O
jumped	O
up	O
promptly	O
,	O
and	O
something	O
in	O
her	O
manner	O
reminded	O
me	O
that	O
her	O
position	O
was	O
a	O
dependent	O
one	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
,	O
kind	O
as	O
she	O
might	O
be	O
in	O
the	O
main	O
,	O
did	O
not	O
allow	O
her	O
to	O
forget	O
it	O
.	O

My	O
hostess	O
turned	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

John	B-PER
will	O
show	O
you	O
your	O
room	O
.	O

Supper	O
is	O
at	O
half-past	O
seven	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
given	O
up	O
late	O
dinner	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
now	O
.	O

Lady	B-PER
Tadminster	I-PER
,	O
our	O
Member	O
's	O
wife	O
...	O
she	O
was	O
the	O
late	O
Lord	O
Abbotsbury	B-PER
's	O
daughter	O
...	O
does	O
the	O
same	O
.	O

She	O
agrees	O
with	O
me	O
that	O
one	O
must	O
set	O
an	O
example	O
of	O
economy	O
.	O

``	O
We	O
are	O
quite	O
a	O
war	O
household	O
;	O
nothing	O
is	O
wasted	O
here	O
...	O
every	O
scrap	O
of	O
waste	O
paper	O
,	O
even	O
,	O
is	O
saved	O
and	O
sent	O
away	O
in	O
sacks	O
.	O
''	O

I	O
expressed	O
my	O
appreciation	O
,	O
and	O
John	B-PER
took	O
me	O
into	O
the	O
house	O
and	O
up	O
the	O
broad	O
staircase	O
,	O
which	O
forked	O
right	O
and	O
left	O
half-way	O
to	O
different	O
wings	O
of	O
the	O
building	O
.	O

My	O
room	O
was	O
in	O
the	O
left	O
wing	O
,	O
and	O
looked	O
out	O
over	O
the	O
park	O
.	O

John	B-PER
left	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
few	O
minutes	O
later	O
I	O
saw	O
him	O
from	O
my	O
window	O
walking	O
slowly	O
across	O
the	O
grass	O
arm	O
in	O
arm	O
with	O
Cynthia	B-PER
Murdoch	I-PER
.	O

I	O
heard	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
call	O
Cynthia	B-PER
impatiently	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
girl	O
started	O
and	O
ran	O
back	O
to	O
the	O
house	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
same	O
moment	O
,	O
a	O
man	O
stepped	O
out	O
from	O
the	O
shadow	O
of	O
a	O
tree	O
and	O
walked	O
slowly	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
direction	O
.	O

He	O
looked	O
about	O
forty	O
,	O
very	O
dark	O
with	O
a	O
melancholy	O
clean-shaven	O
face	O
.	O

Some	O
violent	O
emotion	O
seemed	O
to	O
be	O
mastering	O
him	O
.	O

He	O
looked	O
up	O
at	O
my	O
window	O
as	O
he	O
passed	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
recognized	O
him	O
,	O
though	O
he	O
had	O
changed	O
much	O
in	O
the	O
fifteen	O
years	O
that	O
had	O
elapsed	O
since	O
we	O
last	O
met	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
John	B-PER
's	O
younger	O
brother	O
,	O
Lawrence	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
.	O

I	O
wondered	O
what	O
it	O
was	O
that	O
had	O
brought	O
that	O
singular	O
expression	O
to	O
his	O
face	O
.	O

Then	O
I	O
dismissed	O
him	O
from	O
my	O
mind	O
,	O
and	O
returned	O
to	O
the	O
contemplation	O
of	O
my	O
own	O
affairs	O
.	O

``	O
The	O
evening	O
passed	O
pleasantly	O
enough	O
;	O
and	O
I	O
dreamed	O
that	O
night	O
of	O
that	O
enigmatical	O
woman	O
,	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
.	O
''	O

The	O
next	O
morning	O
dawned	O
bright	O
and	O
sunny	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
was	O
full	O
of	O
the	O
anticipation	O
of	O
a	O
delightful	O
visit	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
not	O
see	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
until	O
lunch-time	O
,	O
when	O
she	O
volunteered	O
to	O
take	O
me	O
for	O
a	O
walk	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
spent	O
a	O
charming	O
afternoon	O
roaming	O
in	O
the	O
woods	O
,	O
returning	O
to	O
the	O
house	O
about	O
five	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
entered	O
the	O
large	O
hall	O
,	O
John	B-PER
beckoned	O
us	O
both	O
into	O
the	O
smoking-room	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
at	O
once	O
by	O
his	O
face	O
that	O
something	O
disturbing	O
had	O
occurred	O
.	O

We	O
followed	O
him	O
in	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
shut	O
the	O
door	O
after	O
us	O
.	O

Look	O
here	O
,	O
Mary	B-PER
,	O
there	O
's	O
the	O
deuce	O
of	O
a	O
mess	O
.	O

Evie	B-PER
's	O
had	O
a	O
row	O
with	O
Alfred	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
,	O
and	O
she	O
's	O
off	O
.	O

Evie	B-PER
?	O

Off	O
?	O

John	B-PER
nodded	O
gloomily	O
.	O

``	O
Yes	O
;	O
you	O
see	O
she	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
mater	O
,	O
and	O
...	O
Oh	O
,	O
here	O
's	O
Evie	B-PER
herself	O
.	O
''	O

Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
entered	O
.	O

Her	O
lips	O
were	O
set	O
grimly	O
together	O
,	O
and	O
she	O
carried	O
a	O
small	O
suit-case	O
.	O

She	O
looked	O
excited	O
and	O
determined	O
,	O
and	O
slightly	O
on	O
the	O
defensive	O
.	O

At	O
any	O
rate	O
,	O
she	O
burst	O
out	O
,	O
I	O
've	O
spoken	O
my	O
mind	O
!	O

My	O
dear	O
Evelyn	B-PER
,	O
cried	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
,	O
this	O
ca	O
n't	O
be	O
TRUE	O
!	O

Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
nodded	O
grimly	O
.	O

TRUE	O
enough	O
!	O

Afraid	O
I	O
said	O
some	O
things	O
to	O
Emily	B-PER
she	O
wo	O
n't	O
forget	O
or	O
forgive	O
in	O
a	O
hurry	O
.	O

Do	O
n't	O
mind	O
if	O
they	O
've	O
only	O
sunk	O
in	O
a	O
bit	O
.	O

Probably	O
water	O
off	O
a	O
duck	O
's	O
back	O
,	O
though	O
.	O

I	O
said	O
right	O
out	O
:	O
`	O
You	O
're	O
an	O
old	O
woman	O
,	O
Emily	B-PER
,	O
and	O
there	O
's	O
no	O
fool	O
like	O
an	O
old	O
fool	O
.	O

The	O
man	O
's	O
twenty	O
years	O
younger	O
than	O
you	O
,	O
and	O
do	O
n't	O
you	O
fool	O
yourself	O
as	O
to	O
what	O
he	O
married	O
you	O
for	O
.	O

Money	O
!	O

Well	O
,	O
do	O
n't	O
let	O
him	O
have	O
too	O
much	O
of	O
it	O
.	O

Farmer	O
Raikes	B-PER
has	O
got	O
a	O
very	O
pretty	O
young	O
wife	O
.	O

Just	O
ask	O
your	O
Alfred	B-PER
how	O
much	O
time	O
he	O
spends	O
over	O
there	O
.	O
'	O

She	O
was	O
very	O
angry	O
.	O

Natural	O
!	O

I	O
went	O
on	O
,	O
`	O
I	O
'm	O
going	O
to	O
warn	O
you	O
,	O
whether	O
you	O
like	O
it	O
or	O
not	O
.	O

That	O
man	O
would	O
as	O
soon	O
murder	O
you	O
in	O
your	O
bed	O
as	O
look	O
at	O
you	O
.	O

He	O
's	O
a	O
bad	O
lot	O
.	O

You	O
can	O
say	O
what	O
you	O
like	O
to	O
me	O
,	O
but	O
remember	O
what	O
I	O
've	O
told	O
you	O
.	O

He	O
's	O
a	O
bad	O
lot	O
!	O
'	O

What	O
did	O
she	O
say	O
?	O

Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
made	O
an	O
extremely	O
expressive	O
grimace	O
.	O

Darling	O
Alfred	B-PER
'	O
...	O
`	O
dearest	O
Alfred	B-PER
'	O
...	O
`	O
wicked	O
calumnies	O
'	O
...	O
`	O
wicked	O
lies	O
'	O
...	O
`	O
wicked	O
woman	O
'	O
...	O
to	O
accuse	O
her	O
`	O
dear	O
husband	O
'	O
!	O

The	O
sooner	O
I	O
left	O
her	O
house	O
the	O
better	O
.	O

So	O
I	O
'm	O
off	O
.	O

But	O
not	O
now	O
?	O

This	O
minute	O
!	O

For	O
a	O
moment	O
we	O
sat	O
and	O
stared	O
at	O
her	O
.	O

Finally	O
John	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
,	O
finding	O
his	O
persuasions	O
of	O
no	O
avail	O
,	O
went	O
off	O
to	O
look	O
up	O
the	O
trains	O
.	O

His	O
wife	O
followed	O
him	O
,	O
murmuring	O
something	O
about	O
persuading	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
to	O
think	O
better	O
of	O
it	O
.	O

As	O
she	O
left	O
the	O
room	O
,	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
's	O
face	O
changed	O
.	O

She	O
leant	O
towards	O
me	O
eagerly	O
.	O

Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
,	O
you	O
're	O
honest	O
.	O

I	O
can	O
trust	O
you	O
?	O

I	O
was	O
a	O
little	O
startled	O
.	O

She	O
laid	O
her	O
hand	O
on	O
my	O
arm	O
,	O
and	O
sank	O
her	O
voice	O
to	O
a	O
whisper	O
.	O

Look	O
after	O
her	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
.	O

My	O
poor	O
Emily	B-PER
.	O

They	O
're	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
sharks	O
...	O
all	O
of	O
them	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
I	O
know	O
what	O
I	O
'm	O
talking	O
about	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
n't	O
one	O
of	O
them	O
that	O
's	O
not	O
hard	O
up	O
and	O
trying	O
to	O
get	O
money	O
out	O
of	O
her	O
.	O

I	O
've	O
protected	O
her	O
as	O
much	O
as	O
I	O
could	O
.	O

Now	O
I	O
'm	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
way	O
,	O
they	O
'll	O
impose	O
upon	O
her	O
.	O

Of	O
course	O
,	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
I	O
'll	O
do	O
everything	O
I	O
can	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
'm	O
sure	O
you	O
're	O
excited	O
and	O
overwrought	O
.	O

She	O
interrupted	O
me	O
by	O
slowly	O
shaking	O
her	O
forefinger	O
.	O

Young	O
man	O
,	O
trust	O
me	O
.	O

I	O
've	O
lived	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
rather	O
longer	O
than	O
you	O
have	O
.	O

All	O
I	O
ask	O
you	O
is	O
to	O
keep	O
your	O
eyes	O
open	O
.	O

You	O
'll	O
see	O
what	O
I	O
mean	O
.	O

The	O
throb	O
of	O
the	O
motor	O
came	O
through	O
the	O
open	O
window	O
,	O
and	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
rose	O
and	O
moved	O
to	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

John	B-PER
's	O
voice	O
sounded	O
outside	O
.	O

With	O
her	O
hand	O
on	O
the	O
handle	O
,	O
she	O
turned	O
her	O
head	O
over	O
her	O
shoulder	O
,	O
and	O
beckoned	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

Above	O
all	O
,	O
Mr.	B-PER
Hastings	I-PER
,	O
watch	O
that	O
devil	O
...	O
her	O
husband	O
!	O

There	O
was	O
no	O
time	O
for	O
more	O
.	O

Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
was	O
swallowed	O
up	O
in	O
an	O
eager	O
chorus	O
of	O
protests	O
and	O
good-byes	O
.	O

The	O
Inglethorps	O
did	O
not	O
appear	O
.	O

As	O
the	O
motor	O
drove	O
away	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
suddenly	O
detached	O
herself	O
from	O
the	O
group	O
,	O
and	O
moved	O
across	O
the	O
drive	O
to	O
the	O
lawn	O
to	O
meet	O
a	O
tall	O
bearded	O
man	O
who	O
had	O
been	O
evidently	O
making	O
for	O
the	O
house	O
.	O

The	O
colour	O
rose	O
in	O
her	O
cheeks	O
as	O
she	O
held	O
out	O
her	O
hand	O
to	O
him	O
.	O

Who	O
is	O
that	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
sharply	O
,	O
for	O
instinctively	O
I	O
distrusted	O
the	O
man	O
.	O

That	O
's	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
,	O
said	O
John	B-PER
shortly	O
.	O

And	O
who	O
is	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
?	O

He	O
's	O
staying	O
in	O
the	O
village	O
doing	O
a	O
rest	O
cure	O
,	O
after	O
a	O
bad	O
nervous	O
breakdown	O
.	O

``	O
He	O
's	O
a	O
London	B-LOC
specialist	O
;	O
a	O
very	O
clever	O
man	O
...	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
greatest	O
living	O
experts	O
on	O
poisons	O
,	O
I	O
believe	O
.	O
''	O

And	O
he	O
's	O
a	O
great	O
friend	O
of	O
Mary	B-PER
's	O
,	O
put	O
in	O
Cynthia	B-PER
,	O
the	O
irrepressible	O
.	O

John	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
frowned	O
and	O
changed	O
the	O
subject	O
.	O

Come	O
for	O
a	O
stroll	O
,	O
Hastings	B-PER
.	O

This	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
most	O
rotten	O
business	O
.	O

She	O
always	O
had	O
a	O
rough	O
tongue	O
,	O
but	O
there	O
is	O
no	O
stauncher	O
friend	O
in	O
England	B-LOC
than	O
Evelyn	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
.	O

He	O
took	O
the	O
path	O
through	O
the	O
plantation	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
walked	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
village	O
through	O
the	O
woods	O
which	O
bordered	O
one	O
side	O
of	O
the	O
estate	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
passed	O
through	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
gates	O
on	O
our	O
way	O
home	O
again	O
,	O
a	O
pretty	O
young	O
woman	O
of	O
gipsy	O
type	O
coming	O
in	O
the	O
opposite	O
direction	O
bowed	O
and	O
smiled	O
.	O

That	O
's	O
a	O
pretty	O
girl	O
,	O
I	O
remarked	O
appreciatively	O
.	O

John	B-PER
's	O
face	O
hardened	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Raikes	I-PER
.	O

The	O
one	O
that	O
Miss	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
...	O
.	O

Exactly	O
,	O
said	O
John	B-PER
,	O
with	O
rather	O
unnecessary	O
abruptness	O
.	O

I	O
thought	O
of	O
the	O
white-haired	O
old	O
lady	O
in	O
the	O
big	O
house	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
vivid	O
wicked	O
little	O
face	O
that	O
had	O
just	O
smiled	O
into	O
ours	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
vague	O
chill	O
of	O
foreboding	O
crept	O
over	O
me	O
.	O

I	O
brushed	O
it	O
aside	O
.	O

Styles	B-LOC
is	O
really	O
a	O
glorious	O
old	O
place	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
to	O
John	B-PER
.	O

He	O
nodded	O
rather	O
gloomily	O
.	O

Yes	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
a	O
fine	O
property	O
.	O

It	O
'll	O
be	O
mine	O
some	O
day	O
...	O
should	O
be	O
mine	O
now	O
by	O
rights	O
,	O
if	O
my	O
father	O
had	O
only	O
made	O
a	O
decent	O
will	O
.	O

And	O
then	O
I	O
should	O
n't	O
be	O
so	O
damned	O
hard	O
up	O
as	O
I	O
am	O
now	O
.	O

Hard	O
up	O
,	O
are	O
you	O
?	O

My	O
dear	O
Hastings	B-PER
,	O
I	O
do	O
n't	O
mind	O
telling	O
you	O
that	O
I	O
'm	O
at	O
my	O
wit	O
's	O
end	O
for	O
money	O
.	O

Could	O
n't	O
your	O
brother	O
help	O
you	O
?	O

Lawrence	B-PER
?	O

He	O
's	O
gone	O
through	O
every	O
penny	O
he	O
ever	O
had	O
,	O
publishing	O
rotten	O
verses	O
in	O
fancy	O
bindings	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
we	O
're	O
an	O
impecunious	O
lot	O
.	O

My	O
mother	O
's	O
always	O
been	O
awfully	O
good	O
to	O
us	O
,	O
I	O
must	O
say	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
,	O
up	O
to	O
now	O
.	O

Since	O
her	O
marriage	O
,	O
of	O
course	O
...	O
.	O

he	O
broke	O
off	O
,	O
frowning	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
I	O
felt	O
that	O
,	O
with	O
Evelyn	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
,	O
something	O
indefinable	O
had	O
gone	O
from	O
the	O
atmosphere	O
.	O

Her	O
presence	O
had	O
spelt	O
security	O
.	O

Now	O
that	O
security	O
was	O
removed	O
...	O
and	O
the	O
air	O
seemed	O
rife	O
with	O
suspicion	O
.	O

The	O
sinister	O
face	O
of	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
recurred	O
to	O
me	O
unpleasantly	O
.	O

A	O
vague	O
suspicion	O
of	O
every	O
one	O
and	O
everything	O
filled	O
my	O
mind	O
.	O

Just	O
for	O
a	O
moment	O
I	O
had	O
a	O
premonition	O
of	O
approaching	O
evil	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
arrived	O
at	O
Styles	B-LOC
on	O
the	O
5th	O
of	O
July	O
.	O

I	O
come	O
now	O
to	O
the	O
events	O
of	O
the	O
16th	O
and	O
17th	O
of	O
that	O
month	O
.	O

For	O
the	O
convenience	O
of	O
the	O
reader	O
I	O
will	O
recapitulate	O
the	O
incidents	O
of	O
those	O
days	O
in	O
as	O
exact	O
a	O
manner	O
as	O
possible	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
elicited	O
subsequently	O
at	O
the	O
trial	O
by	O
a	O
process	O
of	O
long	O
and	O
tedious	O
cross-examinations	O
.	O

I	O
received	O
a	O
letter	O
from	O
Evelyn	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
a	O
couple	O
of	O
days	O
after	O
her	O
departure	O
,	O
telling	O
me	O
she	O
was	O
working	O
as	O
a	O
nurse	O
at	O
the	O
big	O
hospital	O
in	O
Middlingham	B-LOC
,	O
a	O
manufacturing	O
town	O
some	O
fifteen	O
miles	O
away	O
,	O
and	O
begging	O
me	O
to	O
let	O
her	O
know	O
if	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
should	O
show	O
any	O
wish	O
to	O
be	O
reconciled	O
.	O

The	O
only	O
fly	O
in	O
the	O
ointment	O
of	O
my	O
peaceful	O
days	O
was	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
's	O
extraordinary	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
for	O
my	O
part	O
,	O
unaccountable	O
preference	O
for	O
the	O
society	O
of	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
.	O

What	O
she	O
saw	O
in	O
the	O
man	O
I	O
can	O
not	O
imagine	O
,	O
but	O
she	O
was	O
always	O
asking	O
him	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
house	O
,	O
and	O
often	O
went	O
off	O
for	O
long	O
expeditions	O
with	O
him	O
.	O

I	O
must	O
confess	O
that	O
I	O
was	O
quite	O
unable	O
to	O
see	O
his	O
attraction	O
.	O

The	O
16th	O
of	O
July	O
fell	O
on	O
a	O
Monday	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
day	O
of	O
turmoil	O
.	O

The	O
famous	O
bazaar	O
had	O
taken	O
place	O
on	O
Saturday	O
,	O
and	O
an	O
entertainment	O
,	O
in	O
connection	O
with	O
the	O
same	O
charity	O
,	O
at	O
which	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
was	O
to	O
recite	O
a	O
War	O
poem	O
,	O
was	O
to	O
be	O
held	O
that	O
night	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
all	O
busy	O
during	O
the	O
morning	O
arranging	O
and	O
decorating	O
the	O
Hall	O
in	O
the	O
village	O
where	O
it	O
was	O
to	O
take	O
place	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
late	O
luncheon	O
and	O
spent	O
the	O
afternoon	O
resting	O
in	O
the	O
garden	O
.	O

I	O
noticed	O
that	O
John	B-PER
's	O
manner	O
was	O
somewhat	O
unusual	O
.	O

He	O
seemed	O
very	O
excited	O
and	O
restless	O
.	O

After	O
tea	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
went	O
to	O
lie	O
down	O
to	O
rest	O
before	O
her	O
efforts	O
in	O
the	O
evening	O
and	O
I	O
challenged	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
to	O
a	O
single	O
at	O
tennis	O
.	O

About	O
a	O
quarter	O
to	O
seven	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
called	O
us	O
that	O
we	O
should	O
be	O
late	O
as	O
supper	O
was	O
early	O
that	O
night	O
.	O

``	O
We	O
had	O
rather	O
a	O
scramble	O
to	O
get	O
ready	O
in	O
time	O
;	O
and	O
before	O
the	O
meal	O
was	O
over	O
the	O
motor	O
was	O
waiting	O
at	O
the	O
door	O
.	O
''	O

The	O
entertainment	O
was	O
a	O
great	O
success	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
recitation	O
receiving	O
tremendous	O
applause	O
.	O

There	O
were	O
also	O
some	O
tableaux	O
in	O
which	O
Cynthia	B-PER
took	O
part	O
.	O

She	O
did	O
not	O
return	O
with	O
us	O
,	O
having	O
been	O
asked	O
to	O
a	O
supper	O
party	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
remain	O
the	O
night	O
with	O
some	O
friends	O
who	O
had	O
been	O
acting	O
with	O
her	O
in	O
the	O
tableaux	O
.	O

``	O
The	O
following	O
morning	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
stayed	O
in	O
bed	O
to	O
breakfast	O
,	O
as	O
she	O
was	O
rather	O
overtired	O
;	O
but	O
she	O
appeared	O
in	O
her	O
briskest	O
mood	O
about	O
12.3	O
,	O
''	O
and	O
swept	O
Lawrence	B-PER
and	O
myself	O
off	O
to	O
a	O
luncheon	O
party	O
.	O

Such	O
a	O
charming	O
invitation	O
from	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Rolleston	I-PER
.	O

Lady	B-PER
Tadminster	I-PER
's	O
sister	O
,	O
you	O
know	O
.	O

The	O
Rollestons	B-PER
came	O
over	O
with	O
the	O
Conqueror	O
...	O
one	O
of	O
our	O
oldest	O
families	O
.	O

Mary	B-PER
had	O
excused	O
herself	O
on	O
the	O
plea	O
of	O
an	O
engagement	O
with	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
pleasant	O
luncheon	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
we	O
drove	O
away	O
Lawrence	B-PER
suggested	O
that	O
we	O
should	O
return	O
by	O
Tadminster	B-LOC
,	O
which	O
was	O
barely	O
a	O
mile	O
out	O
of	O
our	O
way	O
,	O
and	O
pay	O
a	O
visit	O
to	O
Cynthia	B-PER
in	O
her	O
dispensary	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
replied	O
that	O
this	O
was	O
an	O
excellent	O
idea	O
,	O
but	O
as	O
she	O
had	O
several	O
letters	O
to	O
write	O
she	O
would	O
drop	O
us	O
there	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
could	O
come	O
back	O
with	O
Cynthia	B-PER
in	O
the	O
pony-trap	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
detained	O
under	O
suspicion	O
by	O
the	O
hospital	O
porter	O
,	O
until	O
Cynthia	B-PER
appeared	O
to	O
vouch	O
for	O
us	O
,	O
looking	O
very	O
cool	O
and	O
sweet	O
in	O
her	O
long	O
white	O
overall	O
.	O

She	O
took	O
us	O
up	O
to	O
her	O
sanctum	O
,	O
and	O
introduced	O
us	O
to	O
her	O
fellow	O
dispenser	O
,	O
a	O
rather	O
awe-inspiring	O
individual	O
,	O
whom	O
Cynthia	B-PER
cheerily	O
addressed	O
as	O
`	O
Nibs	O
'	O
.	O

What	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
bottles	O
!	O

I	O
exclaimed	O
,	O
as	O
my	O
eye	O
travelled	O
round	O
the	O
small	O
room	O
.	O

Do	O
you	O
really	O
know	O
what	O
's	O
in	O
them	O
all	O
?	O

Say	O
something	O
original	O
,	O
groaned	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

Every	O
single	O
person	O
who	O
comes	O
up	O
here	O
says	O
that	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
really	O
thinking	O
of	O
bestowing	O
a	O
prize	O
on	O
the	O
first	O
individual	O
who	O
does	O
not	O
say	O
:	O
`	O
What	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
bottles	O
!	O
'	O

And	O
I	O
know	O
the	O
next	O
thing	O
you	O
're	O
going	O
to	O
say	O
is	O
:	O
`	O
How	O
many	O
people	O
have	O
you	O
poisoned	O
?	O
'	O

I	O
pleaded	O
guilty	O
with	O
a	O
laugh	O
.	O

If	O
you	O
people	O
only	O
knew	O
how	O
fatally	O
easy	O
it	O
is	O
to	O
poison	O
some	O
one	O
by	O
mistake	O
,	O
you	O
would	O
n't	O
joke	O
about	O
it	O
.	O

Come	O
on	O
,	O
let	O
's	O
have	O
tea	O
.	O

We	O
've	O
got	O
all	O
sorts	O
of	O
secret	O
stories	O
in	O
that	O
cupboard	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
Lawrence	B-PER
...	O
that	O
's	O
the	O
poison	O
cupboard	O
.	O

The	O
big	O
cupboard	O
...	O
that	O
's	O
right	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
a	O
very	O
cheery	O
tea	O
,	O
and	O
assisted	O
Cynthia	B-PER
to	O
wash	O
up	O
afterwards	O
.	O

We	O
had	O
just	O
put	O
away	O
the	O
last	O
tea-spoon	O
when	O
a	O
knock	O
came	O
at	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

The	O
countenances	O
of	O
Cynthia	B-PER
and	O
Nibs	O
were	O
suddenly	O
petrified	O
into	O
a	O
stern	O
and	O
forbidding	O
expression	O
.	O

Come	O
in	O
,	O
said	O
Cynthia	B-PER
,	O
in	O
a	O
sharp	O
professional	O
tone	O
.	O

A	O
young	O
and	O
rather	O
scared	O
looking	O
nurse	O
appeared	O
with	O
a	O
bottle	O
which	O
she	O
proffered	O
to	O
Nibs	O
,	O
who	O
waved	O
her	O
towards	O
Cynthia	B-PER
with	O
the	O
somewhat	O
enigmatical	O
remark	O
:	O
I	O
'm	O
not	O
really	O
here	O
today	O
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
took	O
the	O
bottle	O
and	O
examined	O
it	O
with	O
the	O
severity	O
of	O
a	O
judge	O
.	O

This	O
should	O
have	O
been	O
sent	O
up	O
this	O
morning	O
.	O

Sister	O
is	O
very	O
sorry	O
.	O

She	O
forgot	O
.	O

Sister	O
should	O
read	O
the	O
rules	O
outside	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

I	O
gathered	O
from	O
the	O
little	O
nurse	O
's	O
expression	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
not	O
the	O
least	O
likelihood	O
of	O
her	O
having	O
the	O
hardihood	O
to	O
retail	O
this	O
message	O
to	O
the	O
dreaded	O
`	O
Sister	O
'	O
.	O

So	O
now	O
it	O
ca	O
n't	O
be	O
done	O
until	O
tomorrow	O
,	O
finished	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

Do	O
n't	O
you	O
think	O
you	O
could	O
possibly	O
let	O
us	O
have	O
it	O
tonight	O
?	O

Well	O
,	O
said	O
Cynthia	B-PER
graciously	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
very	O
busy	O
,	O
but	O
if	O
we	O
have	O
time	O
it	O
shall	O
be	O
done	O
.	O

The	O
little	O
nurse	O
withdrew	O
,	O
and	O
Cynthia	B-PER
promptly	O
took	O
a	O
jar	O
from	O
the	O
shelf	O
,	O
refilled	O
the	O
bottle	O
,	O
and	O
placed	O
it	O
on	O
the	O
table	O
outside	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

I	O
laughed	O
.	O

Discipline	O
must	O
be	O
maintained	O
?	O

Exactly	O
.	O

Come	O
out	O
on	O
our	O
little	O
balcony	O
.	O

You	O
can	O
see	O
all	O
the	O
outside	O
wards	O
there	O
.	O

I	O
followed	O
Cynthia	B-PER
and	O
her	O
friend	O
and	O
they	O
pointed	O
out	O
the	O
different	O
wards	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

Lawrence	B-PER
remained	O
behind	O
,	O
but	O
after	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
Cynthia	B-PER
called	O
to	O
him	O
over	O
her	O
shoulder	O
to	O
come	O
and	O
join	O
us	O
.	O

Then	O
she	O
looked	O
at	O
her	O
watch	O
.	O

Nothing	O
more	O
to	O
do	O
,	O
Nibs	O
?	O

No	O
.	O

All	O
right	O
.	O

Then	O
we	O
can	O
lock	O
up	O
and	O
go	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
seen	O
Lawrence	B-PER
in	O
quite	O
a	O
different	O
light	O
that	O
afternoon	O
.	O

Compared	O
to	O
John	B-PER
,	O
he	O
was	O
an	O
astoundingly	O
difficult	O
person	O
to	O
get	O
to	O
know	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
the	O
opposite	O
of	O
his	O
brother	O
in	O
almost	O
every	O
respect	O
,	O
being	O
unusually	O
shy	O
and	O
reserved	O
.	O

Yet	O
he	O
had	O
a	O
certain	O
charm	O
of	O
manner	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
fancied	O
that	O
,	O
if	O
one	O
really	O
knew	O
him	O
well	O
,	O
one	O
could	O
have	O
a	O
deep	O
affection	O
for	O
him	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
always	O
fancied	O
that	O
his	O
manner	O
to	O
Cynthia	B-PER
was	O
rather	O
constrained	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
she	O
on	O
her	O
side	O
was	O
inclined	O
to	O
be	O
shy	O
of	O
him	O
.	O

But	O
they	O
were	O
both	O
gay	O
enough	O
this	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
chatted	O
together	O
like	O
a	O
couple	O
of	O
children	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
drove	O
through	O
the	O
village	O
,	O
I	O
remembered	O
that	O
I	O
wanted	O
some	O
stamps	O
,	O
so	O
accordingly	O
we	O
pulled	O
up	O
at	O
the	O
post	O
office	O
.	O

As	O
I	O
came	O
out	O
again	O
,	O
I	O
cannoned	O
into	O
a	O
little	O
man	O
who	O
was	O
just	O
entering	O
.	O

I	O
drew	O
aside	O
and	O
apologised	O
,	O
when	O
suddenly	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
loud	O
exclamation	O
,	O
he	O
clasped	O
me	O
in	O
his	O
arms	O
and	O
kissed	O
me	O
warmly	O
.	O

Mon	O
ami	O
Hastings	B-PER
!	O

he	O
cried	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
indeed	O
mon	O
ami	O
Hastings	B-PER
!	O

Poirot	B-PER
!	O

I	O
exclaimed	O
.	O

I	O
turned	O
to	O
the	O
pony-trap	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
very	O
pleasant	O
meeting	O
for	O
me	O
,	O
Miss	B-PER
Cynthia	I-PER
.	O

This	O
is	O
my	O
old	O
friend	O
,	O
Monsieur	B-PER
Poirot	I-PER
,	O
whom	O
I	O
have	O
not	O
seen	O
for	O
years	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
we	O
know	O
Monsieur	B-PER
Poirot	I-PER
,	O
said	O
Cynthia	B-PER
gaily	O
.	O

But	O
I	O
had	O
no	O
idea	O
he	O
was	O
a	O
friend	O
of	O
yours	O
.	O

Yes	O
,	O
indeed	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
seriously	O
.	O

I	O
know	O
Mademoiselle	B-PER
Cynthia	I-PER
.	O

It	O
is	O
by	O
the	O
charity	O
of	O
that	O
good	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
that	O
I	O
am	O
here	O
.	O

Then	O
,	O
as	O
I	O
looked	O
at	O
him	O
inquiringly	O
:	O
Yes	O
,	O
my	O
friend	O
,	O
she	O
had	O
kindly	O
extended	O
hospitality	O
to	O
seven	O
of	O
my	O
countrypeople	O
who	O
,	O
alas	O
,	O
are	O
refugees	O
from	O
their	O
native	O
land	O
.	O

We	O
Belgians	O
will	O
always	O
remember	O
her	O
with	O
gratitude	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
was	O
an	O
extraordinary	O
looking	O
little	O
man	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
hardly	O
more	O
than	O
five	O
feet	O
,	O
four	O
inches	O
,	O
but	O
carried	O
himself	O
with	O
great	O
dignity	O
.	O

His	O
head	O
was	O
exactly	O
the	O
shape	O
of	O
an	O
egg	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
always	O
perched	O
it	O
a	O
little	O
on	O
one	O
side	O
.	O

His	O
moustache	O
was	O
very	O
stiff	O
and	O
military	O
.	O

The	O
neatness	O
of	O
his	O
attire	O
was	O
almost	O
incredible	O
.	O

I	O
believe	O
a	O
speck	O
of	O
dust	O
would	O
have	O
caused	O
him	O
more	O
pain	O
than	O
a	O
bullet	O
wound	O
.	O

Yet	O
this	O
quaint	O
dandyfied	O
little	O
man	O
who	O
,	O
I	O
was	O
sorry	O
to	O
see	O
,	O
now	O
limped	O
badly	O
,	O
had	O
been	O
in	O
his	O
time	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
celebrated	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Belgian	O
police	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
detective	O
,	O
his	O
flair	O
had	O
been	O
extraordinary	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
had	O
achieved	O
triumphs	O
by	O
unravelling	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
baffling	O
cases	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
.	O

He	O
pointed	O
out	O
to	O
me	O
the	O
little	O
house	O
inhabited	O
by	O
him	O
and	O
his	O
fellow	O
Belgians	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
promised	O
to	O
go	O
and	O
see	O
him	O
at	O
an	O
early	O
date	O
.	O

Then	O
he	O
raised	O
his	O
hat	O
with	O
a	O
flourish	O
to	O
Cynthia	B-PER
,	O
and	O
we	O
drove	O
away	O
.	O

He	O
's	O
a	O
dear	O
little	O
man	O
,	O
said	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

I	O
'd	O
no	O
idea	O
you	O
knew	O
him	O
.	O

You	O
've	O
been	O
entertaining	O
a	O
celebrity	O
unawares	O
,	O
I	O
replied	O
.	O

And	O
,	O
for	O
the	O
rest	O
of	O
the	O
way	O
home	O
,	O
I	O
recited	O
to	O
them	O
the	O
various	O
exploits	O
and	O
triumphs	O
of	O
Hercule	B-PER
Poirot	I-PER
.	O

We	O
arrived	O
back	O
in	O
a	O
very	O
cheerful	O
mood	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
entered	O
the	O
hall	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
came	O
out	O
of	O
her	O
boudoir	O
.	O

She	O
looked	O
flushed	O
and	O
upset	O
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
it	O
's	O
you	O
,	O
she	O
said	O
.	O

Is	O
there	O
anything	O
the	O
matter	O
,	O
Aunt	B-PER
Emily	I-PER
?	O

asked	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

Certainly	O
not	O
,	O
said	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
sharply	O
.	O

What	O
should	O
there	O
be	O
?	O

Then	O
catching	O
sight	O
of	O
Dorcas	B-PER
,	O
the	O
parlourmaid	O
,	O
going	O
into	O
the	O
dining-room	O
,	O
she	O
called	O
to	O
her	O
to	O
bring	O
some	O
stamps	O
into	O
the	O
boudoir	O
.	O

Yes	O
,	O
m	O
'm	O
.	O

The	O
old	O
servant	O
hesitated	O
,	O
then	O
added	O
diffidently	O
:	O
Do	O
n't	O
you	O
think	O
,	O
m	O
'm	O
,	O
you	O
'd	O
better	O
get	O
to	O
bed	O
?	O

You	O
're	O
looking	O
very	O
tired	O
.	O

Perhaps	O
you	O
're	O
right	O
,	O
Dorcas	B-PER
...	O
yes	O
...	O
no	O
...	O
not	O
now	O
.	O

I	O
've	O
some	O
letters	O
I	O
must	O
finish	O
by	O
post-time	O
.	O

Have	O
you	O
lighted	O
the	O
fire	O
in	O
my	O
room	O
as	O
I	O
told	O
you	O
?	O

Yes	O
,	O
m	O
'm	O
.	O

Then	O
I	O
'll	O
go	O
to	O
bed	O
directly	O
after	O
supper	O
.	O

She	O
went	O
into	O
the	O
boudoir	O
again	O
,	O
and	O
Cynthia	B-PER
stared	O
after	O
her	O
.	O

Goodness	O
gracious	O
!	O

I	O
wonder	O
what	O
's	O
up	O
?	O

she	O
said	O
to	O
Lawrence	B-PER
.	O

He	O
did	O
not	O
seem	O
to	O
have	O
heard	O
her	O
,	O
for	O
without	O
a	O
word	O
he	O
turned	O
on	O
his	O
heel	O
and	O
went	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
house	O
.	O

I	O
suggested	O
a	O
quick	O
game	O
of	O
tennis	O
before	O
supper	O
and	O
,	O
Cynthia	B-PER
agreeing	O
,	O
I	O
ran	O
upstairs	O
to	O
fetch	O
my	O
racquet	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
was	O
coming	O
down	O
the	O
stairs	O
.	O

It	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
my	O
fancy	O
,	O
but	O
she	O
,	O
too	O
,	O
was	O
looking	O
odd	O
and	O
disturbed	O
.	O

Had	O
a	O
good	O
walk	O
with	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
?	O

I	O
asked	O
,	O
trying	O
to	O
appear	O
as	O
indifferent	O
as	O
I	O
could	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
n't	O
go	O
,	O
she	O
replied	O
abruptly	O
.	O

Where	O
is	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
?	O

In	O
the	O
boudoir	O
.	O

Her	O
hand	O
clenched	O
itself	O
on	O
the	O
banisters	O
,	O
then	O
she	O
seemed	O
to	O
nerve	O
herself	O
for	O
some	O
encounter	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
rapidly	O
past	O
me	O
down	O
the	O
stairs	O
across	O
the	O
hall	O
to	O
the	O
boudoir	O
,	O
the	O
door	O
of	O
which	O
she	O
shut	O
behind	O
her	O
.	O

As	O
I	O
ran	O
out	O
to	O
the	O
tennis	O
court	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
later	O
,	O
I	O
had	O
to	O
pass	O
the	O
open	O
boudoir	O
window	O
,	O
and	O
was	O
unable	O
to	O
help	O
overhearing	O
the	O
following	O
scrap	O
of	O
dialogue	O
.	O

Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
was	O
saying	O
in	O
the	O
voice	O
of	O
a	O
woman	O
desperately	O
controlling	O
herself	O
:	O
Then	O
you	O
wo	O
n't	O
show	O
it	O
to	O
me	O
?	O

To	O
which	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
replied	O
:	O
My	O
dear	O
Mary	B-PER
,	O
it	O
has	O
nothing	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
that	O
matter	O
.	O

Then	O
show	O
it	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

I	O
tell	O
you	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
what	O
you	O
imagine	O
.	O

It	O
does	O
not	O
concern	O
you	O
in	O
the	O
least	O
.	O

To	O
which	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
replied	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
rising	O
bitterness	O
:	O
Of	O
course	O
,	O
I	O
might	O
have	O
known	O
you	O
would	O
shield	O
him	O
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
was	O
waiting	O
for	O
me	O
,	O
and	O
greeted	O
me	O
eagerly	O
with	O
:	O
I	O
say	O
!	O

There	O
's	O
been	O
the	O
most	O
awful	O
row	O
!	O

I	O
've	O
got	O
it	O
all	O
out	O
of	O
Dorcas	B-PER
.	O

What	O
kind	O
of	O
a	O
row	O
?	O

Between	O
Aunt	B-PER
Emily	I-PER
and	O
him	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
hope	O
she	O
's	O
found	O
him	O
out	O
at	O
last	O
!	O

Was	O
Dorcas	B-PER
there	O
,	O
then	O
?	O

Of	O
course	O
not	O
.	O

She	O
`	O
happened	O
to	O
be	O
near	O
the	O
door	O
'	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
real	O
old	O
bust-up	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
wish	O
I	O
knew	O
what	O
it	O
was	O
all	O
about	O
.	O

I	O
thought	O
of	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Raikes	I-PER
's	O
gipsy	O
face	O
,	O
and	O
Evelyn	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
's	O
warnings	O
,	O
but	O
wisely	O
decided	O
to	O
hold	O
my	O
peace	O
,	O
whilst	O
Cynthia	B-PER
exhausted	O
every	O
possible	O
hypothesis	O
,	O
and	O
cheerfully	O
hoped	O
,	O
Aunt	B-PER
Emily	I-PER
will	O
send	O
him	O
away	O
,	O
and	O
will	O
never	O
speak	O
to	O
him	O
again	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
anxious	O
to	O
get	O
hold	O
of	O
John	B-PER
,	O
but	O
he	O
was	O
nowhere	O
to	O
be	O
seen	O
.	O

Evidently	O
something	O
very	O
momentous	O
had	O
occurred	O
that	O
afternoon	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
tried	O
to	O
forget	O
the	O
few	O
words	O
I	O
had	O
overheard	O
;	O
but	O
,	O
do	O
what	O
I	O
would	O
,	O
I	O
could	O
not	O
dismiss	O
them	O
altogether	O
from	O
my	O
mind	O
.	O
''	O

What	O
was	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
's	O
concern	O
in	O
the	O
matter	O
?	O

Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
was	O
in	O
the	O
drawing-room	O
when	O
I	O
came	O
down	O
to	O
supper	O
.	O

His	O
face	O
was	O
impassive	O
as	O
ever	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
strange	O
unreality	O
of	O
the	O
man	O
struck	O
me	O
afresh	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
came	O
down	O
last	O
.	O

She	O
still	O
looked	O
agitated	O
,	O
and	O
during	O
the	O
meal	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
somewhat	O
constrained	O
silence	O
.	O

Inglethorp	B-PER
was	O
unusually	O
quiet	O
.	O

As	O
a	O
rule	O
,	O
he	O
surrounded	O
his	O
wife	O
with	O
little	O
attentions	O
,	O
placing	O
a	O
cushion	O
at	O
her	O
back	O
,	O
and	O
altogether	O
playing	O
the	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
devoted	O
husband	O
.	O

Immediately	O
after	O
supper	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
retired	O
to	O
her	O
boudoir	O
again	O
.	O

Send	O
my	O
coffee	O
in	O
here	O
,	O
Mary	B-PER
,	O
she	O
called	O
.	O

I	O
've	O
just	O
five	O
minutes	O
to	O
catch	O
the	O
post	O
.	O

Cynthia	B-PER
and	O
I	O
went	O
and	O
sat	O
by	O
the	O
open	O
window	O
in	O
the	O
drawing-room	O
.	O

Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
brought	O
our	O
coffee	O
to	O
us	O
.	O

She	O
seemed	O
excited	O
.	O

Do	O
you	O
young	O
people	O
want	O
lights	O
,	O
or	O
do	O
you	O
enjoy	O
the	O
twilight	O
?	O

she	O
asked	O
.	O

Will	O
you	O
take	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
her	O
coffee	O
,	O
Cynthia	B-PER
?	O

I	O
will	O
pour	O
it	O
out	O
.	O

Do	O
not	O
trouble	O
,	O
Mary	B-PER
,	O
said	O
Inglethorp	B-PER
.	O

I	O
will	O
take	O
it	O
to	O
Emily	B-PER
.	O

He	O
poured	O
it	O
out	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
room	O
carrying	O
it	O
carefully	O
.	O

Lawrence	B-PER
followed	O
him	O
,	O
and	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
sat	O
down	O
by	O
us	O
.	O

We	O
three	O
sat	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
in	O
silence	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
a	O
glorious	O
night	O
,	O
hot	O
and	O
still	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
fanned	O
herself	O
gently	O
with	O
a	O
palm	O
leaf	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
almost	O
too	O
hot	O
,	O
she	O
murmured	O
.	O

We	O
shall	O
have	O
a	O
thunderstorm	O
.	O

Alas	O
,	O
that	O
these	O
harmonious	O
moments	O
can	O
never	O
endure	O
!	O

My	O
paradise	O
was	O
rudely	O
shattered	O
by	O
the	O
sound	O
of	O
a	O
well	O
known	O
,	O
and	O
heartily	O
disliked	O
,	O
voice	O
in	O
the	O
hall	O
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
!	O

exclaimed	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

What	O
a	O
funny	O
time	O
to	O
come	O
.	O

I	O
glanced	O
jealously	O
at	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
,	O
but	O
she	O
seemed	O
quite	O
undisturbed	O
,	O
the	O
delicate	O
pallor	O
of	O
her	O
cheeks	O
did	O
not	O
vary	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
,	O
Alfred	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
had	O
ushered	O
the	O
doctor	O
in	O
,	O
the	O
latter	O
laughing	O
,	O
and	O
protesting	O
that	O
he	O
was	O
in	O
no	O
fit	O
state	O
for	O
a	O
drawing-room	O
.	O

In	O
truth	O
,	O
he	O
presented	O
a	O
sorry	O
spectacle	O
,	O
being	O
literally	O
plastered	O
with	O
mud	O
.	O

What	O
have	O
you	O
been	O
doing	O
,	O
doctor	O
?	O

cried	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
.	O

I	O
must	O
make	O
my	O
apologies	O
,	O
said	O
the	O
doctor	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
not	O
really	O
mean	O
to	O
come	O
in	O
,	O
but	O
Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
insisted	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
Bauerstein	B-PER
,	O
you	O
are	O
in	O
a	O
plight	O
,	O
said	O
John	B-PER
,	O
strolling	O
in	O
from	O
the	O
hall	O
.	O

Have	O
some	O
coffee	O
,	O
and	O
tell	O
us	O
what	O
you	O
have	O
been	O
up	O
to	O
.	O

Thank	O
you	O
,	O
I	O
will	O
.	O

He	O
laughed	O
rather	O
ruefully	O
,	O
as	O
he	O
described	O
how	O
he	O
had	O
discovered	O
a	O
very	O
rare	O
species	O
of	O
fern	O
in	O
an	O
inaccessible	O
place	O
,	O
and	O
in	O
his	O
efforts	O
to	O
obtain	O
it	O
had	O
lost	O
his	O
footing	O
,	O
and	O
slipped	O
ignominiously	O
into	O
a	O
neighbouring	O
pond	O
.	O

The	O
sun	O
soon	O
dried	O
me	O
off	O
,	O
he	O
added	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
'm	O
afraid	O
my	O
appearance	O
is	O
very	O
disreputable	O
.	O

At	O
this	O
juncture	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
called	O
to	O
Cynthia	B-PER
from	O
the	O
hall	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
girl	O
ran	O
out	O
.	O

Just	O
carry	O
up	O
my	O
despatch-case	O
,	O
will	O
you	O
,	O
dear	O
?	O

I	O
'm	O
going	O
to	O
bed	O
.	O

The	O
door	O
into	O
the	O
hall	O
was	O
a	O
wide	O
one	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
risen	O
when	O
Cynthia	B-PER
did	O
,	O
John	B-PER
was	O
close	O
by	O
me	O
.	O

There	O
were	O
therefore	O
three	O
witnesses	O
who	O
could	O
swear	O
that	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
was	O
carrying	O
her	O
coffee	O
,	O
as	O
yet	O
untasted	O
,	O
in	O
her	O
hand	O
.	O

My	O
evening	O
was	O
utterly	O
and	O
entirely	O
spoilt	O
by	O
the	O
presence	O
of	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
.	O

It	O
seemed	O
to	O
me	O
the	O
man	O
would	O
never	O
go	O
.	O

He	O
rose	O
at	O
last	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
breathed	O
a	O
sigh	O
of	O
relief	O
.	O

I	O
'll	O
walk	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
village	O
with	O
you	O
,	O
said	O
Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
.	O

I	O
must	O
see	O
our	O
agent	O
over	O
those	O
estate	O
accounts	O
.	O

He	O
turned	O
to	O
John	B-PER
.	O

No	O
one	O
need	O
sit	O
up	O
.	O

I	O
will	O
take	O
the	O
latch-key	O
.	O

To	O
make	O
this	O
part	O
of	O
my	O
story	O
clear	O
,	O
I	O
append	O
the	O
following	O
plan	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
floor	O
of	O
Styles	B-LOC
.	O

The	O
servants	O
'	O
rooms	O
are	O
reached	O
through	O
the	O
door	O
B	O
.	O

They	O
have	O
no	O
communication	O
with	O
the	O
right	O
wing	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
Inglethorps	O
'	O
rooms	O
were	O
situated	O
.	O

It	O
seemed	O
to	O
be	O
the	O
middle	O
of	O
the	O
night	O
when	O
I	O
was	O
awakened	O
by	O
Lawrence	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
.	O

He	O
had	O
a	O
candle	O
in	O
his	O
hand	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
agitation	O
of	O
his	O
face	O
told	O
me	O
at	O
once	O
that	O
something	O
was	O
seriously	O
wrong	O
.	O

What	O
's	O
the	O
matter	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
,	O
sitting	O
up	O
in	O
bed	O
,	O
and	O
trying	O
to	O
collect	O
my	O
scattered	O
thoughts	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
afraid	O
my	O
mother	O
is	O
very	O
ill	O
.	O

She	O
seems	O
to	O
be	O
having	O
some	O
kind	O
of	O
fit	O
.	O

Unfortunately	O
she	O
has	O
locked	O
herself	O
in	O
.	O

I	O
'll	O
come	O
at	O
once	O
.	O

``	O
I	O
sprang	O
out	O
of	O
bed	O
;	O
and	O
,	O
pulling	O
on	O
a	O
dressing-gown	O
,	O
followed	O
Lawrence	B-PER
along	O
the	O
passage	O
and	O
the	O
gallery	O
to	O
the	O
right	O
wing	O
of	O
the	O
house	O
.	O
''	O

John	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
joined	O
us	O
,	O
and	O
one	O
or	O
two	O
of	O
the	O
servants	O
were	O
standing	O
round	O
in	O
a	O
state	O
of	O
awe-stricken	O
excitement	O
.	O

Lawrence	B-PER
turned	O
to	O
his	O
brother	O
.	O

What	O
do	O
you	O
think	O
we	O
had	O
better	O
do	O
?	O

Never	O
,	O
I	O
thought	O
,	O
had	O
his	O
indecision	O
of	O
character	O
been	O
more	O
apparent	O
.	O

John	B-PER
rattled	O
the	O
handle	O
of	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
door	O
violently	O
,	O
but	O
with	O
no	O
effect	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
obviously	O
locked	O
or	O
bolted	O
on	O
the	O
inside	O
.	O

The	O
whole	O
household	O
was	O
aroused	O
by	O
now	O
.	O

The	O
most	O
alarming	O
sounds	O
were	O
audible	O
from	O
the	O
interior	O
of	O
the	O
room	O
.	O

Clearly	O
something	O
must	O
be	O
done	O
.	O

Try	O
going	O
through	O
Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
room	O
,	O
sir	O
,	O
cried	O
Dorcas	B-PER
.	O

Oh	O
,	O
the	O
poor	O
mistress	O
!	O

Suddenly	O
I	O
realized	O
that	O
Alfred	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
was	O
not	O
with	O
us	O
...	O
that	O
he	O
alone	O
had	O
given	O
no	O
sign	O
of	O
his	O
presence	O
.	O

John	B-PER
opened	O
the	O
door	O
of	O
his	O
room	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
pitch	O
dark	O
,	O
but	O
Lawrence	B-PER
was	O
following	O
with	O
the	O
candle	O
,	O
and	O
by	O
its	O
feeble	O
light	O
we	O
saw	O
that	O
the	O
bed	O
had	O
not	O
been	O
slept	O
in	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
sign	O
of	O
the	O
room	O
having	O
been	O
occupied	O
.	O

We	O
went	O
straight	O
to	O
the	O
connecting	O
door	O
.	O

That	O
,	O
too	O
,	O
was	O
locked	O
or	O
bolted	O
on	O
the	O
inside	O
.	O

What	O
was	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
?	O

Oh	O
,	O
dear	O
,	O
sir	O
,	O
cried	O
Dorcas	B-PER
,	O
wringing	O
her	O
hands	O
,	O
what	O
ever	O
shall	O
we	O
do	O
?	O

We	O
must	O
try	O
and	O
break	O
the	O
door	O
in	O
,	O
I	O
suppose	O
.	O

It	O
'll	O
be	O
a	O
tough	O
job	O
,	O
though	O
.	O

Here	O
,	O
let	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
maids	O
go	O
down	O
and	O
wake	O
Baily	B-PER
and	O
tell	O
him	O
to	O
go	O
for	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
at	O
once	O
.	O

Now	O
then	O
,	O
we	O
'll	O
have	O
a	O
try	O
at	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

Half	O
a	O
moment	O
,	O
though	O
,	O
is	O
n't	O
there	O
a	O
door	O
into	O
Miss	B-PER
Cynthia	I-PER
's	O
rooms	O
?	O

Yes	O
,	O
sir	O
,	O
but	O
that	O
's	O
always	O
bolted	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
never	O
been	O
undone	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
we	O
might	O
just	O
see	O
.	O

He	O
ran	O
rapidly	O
down	O
the	O
corridor	O
to	O
Cynthia	B-PER
's	O
room	O
.	O

Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
was	O
there	O
,	O
shaking	O
the	O
girl	O
,	O
who	O
must	O
have	O
been	O
an	O
unusually	O
sound	O
sleeper	O
,	O
and	O
trying	O
to	O
wake	O
her	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
moment	O
or	O
two	O
he	O
was	O
back	O
.	O

No	O
good	O
.	O

That	O
's	O
bolted	O
too	O
.	O

We	O
must	O
break	O
in	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

I	O
think	O
this	O
one	O
is	O
a	O
shade	O
less	O
solid	O
than	O
the	O
one	O
in	O
the	O
passage	O
.	O

We	O
strained	O
and	O
heaved	O
together	O
.	O

The	O
framework	O
of	O
the	O
door	O
was	O
solid	O
,	O
and	O
for	O
a	O
long	O
time	O
it	O
resisted	O
our	O
efforts	O
,	O
but	O
at	O
last	O
we	O
felt	O
it	O
give	O
beneath	O
our	O
weight	O
,	O
and	O
finally	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
resounding	O
crash	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
burst	O
open	O
.	O

We	O
stumbled	O
in	O
together	O
,	O
Lawrence	B-PER
still	O
holding	O
his	O
candle	O
.	O

Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
was	O
lying	O
on	O
the	O
bed	O
,	O
her	O
whole	O
form	O
agitated	O
by	O
violent	O
convulsions	O
,	O
in	O
one	O
of	O
which	O
she	O
must	O
have	O
overturned	O
the	O
table	O
beside	O
her	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
entered	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
her	O
limbs	O
relaxed	O
,	O
and	O
she	O
fell	O
back	O
upon	O
the	O
pillows	O
.	O

John	B-PER
strode	O
across	O
the	O
room	O
,	O
and	O
lit	O
the	O
gas	O
.	O

Turning	O
to	O
Annie	B-PER
,	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
housemaids	O
,	O
he	O
sent	O
her	O
downstairs	O
to	O
the	O
dining-room	O
for	O
brandy	O
.	O

Then	O
he	O
went	O
across	O
to	O
his	O
mother	O
whilst	O
I	O
unbolted	O
the	O
door	O
that	O
gave	O
on	O
the	O
corridor	O
.	O

I	O
turned	O
to	O
Lawrence	B-PER
,	O
to	O
suggest	O
that	O
I	O
had	O
better	O
leave	O
them	O
now	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
further	O
need	O
of	O
my	O
services	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
words	O
were	O
frozen	O
on	O
my	O
lips	O
.	O

Never	O
have	O
I	O
seen	O
such	O
a	O
ghastly	O
look	O
on	O
any	O
man	O
's	O
face	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
white	O
as	O
chalk	O
,	O
the	O
candle	O
he	O
held	O
in	O
his	O
shaking	O
hand	O
was	O
sputtering	O
onto	O
the	O
carpet	O
,	O
and	O
his	O
eyes	O
,	O
petrified	O
with	O
terror	O
,	O
or	O
some	O
such	O
kindred	O
emotion	O
,	O
stared	O
fixedly	O
over	O
my	O
head	O
at	O
a	O
point	O
on	O
the	O
further	O
wall	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
as	O
though	O
he	O
had	O
seen	O
something	O
that	O
turned	O
him	O
to	O
stone	O
.	O

I	O
instinctively	O
followed	O
the	O
direction	O
of	O
his	O
eyes	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
could	O
see	O
nothing	O
unusual	O
.	O

The	O
still	O
feebly	O
flickering	O
ashes	O
in	O
the	O
grate	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
row	O
of	O
prim	O
ornaments	O
on	O
the	O
mantelpiece	O
,	O
were	O
surely	O
harmless	O
enough	O
.	O

The	O
violence	O
of	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
attack	O
seemed	O
to	O
be	O
passing	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
able	O
to	O
speak	O
in	O
short	O
gasps	O
.	O

Better	O
now	O
...	O
very	O
sudden	O
...	O
stupid	O
of	O
me	O
...	O
to	O
lock	O
myself	O
in	O
.	O

A	O
shadow	O
fell	O
on	O
the	O
bed	O
and	O
,	O
looking	O
up	O
,	O
I	O
saw	O
Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
standing	O
near	O
the	O
door	O
with	O
her	O
arm	O
around	O
Cynthia	B-PER
.	O

She	O
seemed	O
to	O
be	O
supporting	O
the	O
girl	O
,	O
who	O
looked	O
utterly	O
dazed	O
and	O
unlike	O
herself	O
.	O

Her	O
face	O
was	O
heavily	O
flushed	O
,	O
and	O
she	O
yawned	O
repeatedly	O
.	O

Poor	O
Cynthia	B-PER
is	O
quite	O
frightened	O
,	O
said	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
in	O
a	O
low	O
clear	O
voice	O
.	O

She	O
herself	O
,	O
I	O
noticed	O
,	O
was	O
dressed	O
in	O
her	O
white	O
land	O
smock	O
.	O

Then	O
it	O
must	O
be	O
later	O
than	O
I	O
thought	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
that	O
a	O
faint	O
streak	O
of	O
daylight	O
was	O
showing	O
through	O
the	O
curtains	O
of	O
the	O
windows	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
clock	O
on	O
the	O
mantelpiece	O
pointed	O
to	O
close	O
upon	O
five	O
o'clock	O
.	O

A	O
strangled	O
cry	O
from	O
the	O
bed	O
startled	O
me	O
.	O

A	O
fresh	O
access	O
of	O
pain	O
seized	O
the	O
unfortunate	O
old	O
lady	O
.	O

The	O
convulsions	O
were	O
of	O
a	O
violence	O
terrible	O
to	O
behold	O
.	O

Everything	O
was	O
confusion	O
.	O

We	O
thronged	O
round	O
her	O
,	O
powerless	O
to	O
help	O
or	O
alleviate	O
.	O

A	O
final	O
convulsion	O
lifted	O
her	O
from	O
the	O
bed	O
,	O
until	O
she	O
appeared	O
to	O
rest	O
upon	O
her	O
head	O
and	O
her	O
heels	O
,	O
with	O
her	O
body	O
arched	O
in	O
an	O
extraordinary	O
manner	O
.	O

In	O
vain	O
Mary	B-PER
and	O
John	B-PER
tried	O
to	O
administer	O
more	O
brandy	O
.	O

The	O
moments	O
flew	O
.	O

Again	O
the	O
body	O
arched	O
itself	O
in	O
that	O
peculiar	O
fashion	O
.	O

At	O
that	O
moment	O
,	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
pushed	O
his	O
way	O
authoritatively	O
into	O
the	O
room	O
.	O

For	O
one	O
instant	O
he	O
stopped	O
dead	O
,	O
staring	O
at	O
the	O
figure	O
on	O
the	O
bed	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
instant	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
cried	O
out	O
in	O
a	O
strangled	O
voice	O
,	O
her	O
eyes	O
fixed	O
on	O
the	O
doctor	O
:	O
Alfred	B-PER
...	O
Alfred	B-PER
...	O
.	O

Then	O
she	O
fell	O
back	O
motionless	O
on	O
the	O
pillows	O
.	O

With	O
a	O
stride	O
,	O
the	O
doctor	O
reached	O
the	O
bed	O
,	O
and	O
seizing	O
her	O
arms	O
worked	O
them	O
energetically	O
,	O
applying	O
what	O
I	O
knew	O
to	O
be	O
artificial	O
respiration	O
.	O

He	O
issued	O
a	O
few	O
short	O
sharp	O
orders	O
to	O
the	O
servants	O
.	O

An	O
imperious	O
wave	O
of	O
his	O
hand	O
drove	O
us	O
all	O
to	O
the	O
door	O
.	O

We	O
watched	O
him	O
,	O
fascinated	O
,	O
though	O
I	O
think	O
we	O
all	O
knew	O
in	O
our	O
hearts	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
too	O
late	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
nothing	O
could	O
be	O
done	O
now	O
.	O

I	O
could	O
see	O
by	O
the	O
expression	O
on	O
his	O
face	O
that	O
he	O
himself	O
had	O
little	O
hope	O
.	O

Finally	O
he	O
abandoned	O
his	O
task	O
,	O
shaking	O
his	O
head	O
gravely	O
.	O

At	O
that	O
moment	O
,	O
we	O
heard	O
footsteps	O
outside	O
,	O
and	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
own	O
doctor	O
,	O
a	O
portly	O
,	O
fussy	O
little	O
man	O
,	O
came	O
bustling	O
in	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
few	O
words	O
DrBauerstein	B-PER
explained	O
how	O
he	O
had	O
happened	O
to	O
be	O
passing	O
the	O
lodge	O
gates	O
as	O
the	O
car	O
came	O
out	O
,	O
and	O
had	O
run	O
up	O
to	O
the	O
house	O
as	O
fast	O
as	O
he	O
could	O
,	O
whilst	O
the	O
car	O
went	O
on	O
to	O
fetch	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
.	O

With	O
a	O
faint	O
gesture	O
of	O
the	O
hand	O
,	O
he	O
indicated	O
the	O
figure	O
on	O
the	O
bed	O
.	O

Very	O
sad	O
.	O

Very	O
sad	O
,	O
murmured	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
.	O

Poor	O
dear	O
lady	O
.	O

Always	O
did	O
far	O
too	O
much	O
...	O
far	O
too	O
much	O
...	O
against	O
my	O
advice	O
.	O

I	O
warned	O
her	O
.	O

Her	O
heart	O
was	O
far	O
from	O
strong	O
.	O

Take	O
it	O
easy	O
,	O
'	O
I	O
said	O
to	O
her	O
,	O
Take	O
...	O
it	O
...	O
easy	O
'	O
.	O

But	O
no	O
...	O
her	O
zeal	O
for	O
good	O
works	O
was	O
too	O
great	O
.	O

Nature	O
rebelled	O
.	O

Nature	O
...	O
rebelled	O
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
,	O
I	O
noticed	O
,	O
was	O
watching	O
the	O
local	O
doctor	O
narrowly	O
.	O

He	O
still	O
kept	O
his	O
eyes	O
fixed	O
on	O
him	O
as	O
he	O
spoke	O
.	O

The	O
convulsions	O
were	O
of	O
a	O
peculiar	O
violence	O
,	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
.	O

I	O
am	O
sorry	O
you	O
were	O
not	O
here	O
in	O
time	O
to	O
witness	O
them	O
.	O

They	O
were	O
quite	O
...	O
tetanic	O
in	O
character	O
.	O

Ah	O
!	O

said	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
wisely	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
speak	O
to	O
you	O
in	O
private	O
,	O
said	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
.	O

He	O
turned	O
to	O
John	B-PER
.	O

You	O
do	O
not	O
object	O
?	O

Certainly	O
not	O
.	O

We	O
all	O
trooped	O
out	O
into	O
the	O
corridor	O
,	O
leaving	O
the	O
two	O
doctors	O
alone	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
heard	O
the	O
key	O
turned	O
in	O
the	O
lock	O
behind	O
us	O
.	O

We	O
went	O
slowly	O
down	O
the	O
stairs	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
violently	O
excited	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
a	O
certain	O
talent	O
for	O
deduction	O
,	O
and	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
's	O
manner	O
had	O
started	O
a	O
flock	O
of	O
wild	O
surmises	O
in	O
my	O
mind	O
.	O

Mary	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
laid	O
her	O
hand	O
upon	O
my	O
arm	O
.	O

What	O
is	O
it	O
?	O

Why	O
did	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
seem	O
so	O
...	O
peculiar	O
?	O

I	O
looked	O
at	O
her	O
.	O

Do	O
you	O
know	O
what	O
I	O
think	O
?	O

What	O
?	O

Listen	O
!	O

I	O
looked	O
round	O
,	O
the	O
others	O
were	O
out	O
of	O
earshot	O
.	O

I	O
lowered	O
my	O
voice	O
to	O
a	O
whisper	O
.	O

I	O
believe	O
she	O
has	O
been	O
poisoned	O
!	O

I	O
'm	O
certain	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
suspects	O
it	O
.	O

What	O
?	O

She	O
shrank	O
against	O
the	O
wall	O
,	O
the	O
pupils	O
of	O
her	O
eyes	O
dilating	O
wildly	O
.	O

Then	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
sudden	O
cry	O
that	O
startled	O
me	O
,	O
she	O
cried	O
out	O
:	O
No	O
,	O
no	O
...	O
not	O
that	O
...	O
not	O
that	O
!	O

And	O
breaking	O
from	O
me	O
,	O
fled	O
up	O
the	O
stairs	O
.	O

I	O
followed	O
her	O
,	O
afraid	O
that	O
she	O
was	O
going	O
to	O
faint	O
.	O

I	O
found	O
her	O
leaning	O
against	O
the	O
bannisters	O
,	O
deadly	O
pale	O
.	O

She	O
waved	O
me	O
away	O
impatiently	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
no	O
...	O
leave	O
me	O
.	O

I	O
'd	O
rather	O
be	O
alone	O
.	O

Let	O
me	O
just	O
be	O
quiet	O
for	O
a	O
minute	O
or	O
two	O
.	O

Go	O
down	O
to	O
the	O
others	O
.	O

I	O
obeyed	O
her	O
reluctantly	O
.	O

John	B-PER
and	O
Lawrence	B-PER
were	O
in	O
the	O
dining-room	O
.	O

I	O
joined	O
them	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
all	O
silent	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
suppose	O
I	O
voiced	O
the	O
thoughts	O
of	O
us	O
all	O
when	O
I	O
at	O
last	O
broke	O
it	O
by	O
saying	O
:	O
Where	O
is	O
Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
?	O

John	B-PER
shook	O
his	O
head	O
.	O

He	O
's	O
not	O
in	O
the	O
house	O
.	O

Our	O
eyes	O
met	O
.	O

Where	O
was	O
Alfred	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
?	O

His	O
absence	O
was	O
strange	O
and	O
inexplicable	O
.	O

I	O
remembered	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
dying	O
words	O
.	O

What	O
lay	O
beneath	O
them	O
?	O

What	O
more	O
could	O
she	O
have	O
told	O
us	O
,	O
if	O
she	O
had	O
had	O
time	O
?	O

At	O
last	O
we	O
heard	O
the	O
doctors	O
descending	O
the	O
stairs	O
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
was	O
looking	O
important	O
and	O
excited	O
,	O
and	O
trying	O
to	O
conceal	O
an	O
inward	O
exultation	O
under	O
a	O
manner	O
of	O
decorous	O
calm	O
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
remained	O
in	O
the	O
background	O
,	O
his	O
grave	O
bearded	O
face	O
unchanged	O
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
was	O
the	O
spokesman	O
for	O
the	O
two	O
.	O

He	O
addressed	O
himself	O
to	O
John	B-PER
:	O
Mr.	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
,	O
I	O
should	O
like	O
your	O
consent	O
to	O
a	O
postmortem	O
.	O

Is	O
that	O
necessary	O
?	O

asked	O
John	B-PER
gravely	O
.	O

A	O
spasm	O
of	O
pain	O
crossed	O
his	O
face	O
.	O

Absolutely	O
,	O
said	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
.	O

You	O
mean	O
by	O
that	O
...	O
?	O

That	O
neither	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
nor	O
myself	O
could	O
give	O
a	O
death	O
certificate	O
under	O
the	O
circumstances	O
.	O

John	B-PER
bent	O
his	O
head	O
.	O

In	O
that	O
case	O
,	O
I	O
have	O
no	O
alternative	O
but	O
to	O
agree	O
.	O

Thank	O
you	O
,	O
said	O
Dr	B-PER
Wilkins	I-PER
briskly	O
.	O

We	O
propose	O
that	O
it	O
should	O
take	O
place	O
tomorrow	O
night	O
...	O
or	O
rather	O
tonight	O
.	O

And	O
he	O
glanced	O
at	O
the	O
daylight	O
.	O

Under	O
the	O
circumstances	O
,	O
I	O
am	O
afraid	O
an	O
inquest	O
can	O
hardly	O
be	O
avoided	O
...	O
these	O
formalities	O
are	O
necessary	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
beg	O
that	O
you	O
wo	O
n't	O
distress	O
yourselves	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
a	O
pause	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
drew	O
two	O
keys	O
from	O
his	O
pocket	O
,	O
and	O
handed	O
them	O
to	O
John	B-PER
.	O

These	O
are	O
the	O
keys	O
of	O
the	O
two	O
rooms	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
locked	O
them	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
my	O
opinion	O
,	O
they	O
would	O
be	O
better	O
kept	O
locked	O
for	O
the	O
present	O
.	O

The	O
doctors	O
then	O
departed	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
been	O
turning	O
over	O
an	O
idea	O
in	O
my	O
head	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
felt	O
that	O
the	O
moment	O
had	O
now	O
come	O
to	O
broach	O
it	O
.	O

Yet	O
I	O
was	O
a	O
little	O
chary	O
of	O
doing	O
so	O
.	O

John	B-PER
,	O
I	O
knew	O
,	O
had	O
a	O
horror	O
of	O
any	O
kind	O
of	O
publicity	O
,	O
and	O
was	O
an	O
easygoing	O
optimist	O
,	O
who	O
preferred	O
never	O
to	O
meet	O
trouble	O
half-way	O
.	O

It	O
might	O
be	O
difficult	O
to	O
convince	O
him	O
of	O
the	O
soundness	O
of	O
my	O
plan	O
.	O

Lawrence	B-PER
,	O
on	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
being	O
less	O
conventional	O
,	O
and	O
having	O
more	O
imagination	O
,	O
I	O
felt	O
I	O
might	O
count	O
upon	O
as	O
an	O
ally	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
no	O
doubt	O
that	O
the	O
moment	O
had	O
come	O
for	O
me	O
to	O
take	O
the	O
lead	O
.	O

John	B-PER
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
I	O
am	O
going	O
to	O
ask	O
you	O
something	O
.	O

Well	O
?	O

You	O
remember	O
my	O
speaking	O
of	O
my	O
friend	O
Poirot	B-PER
?	O

The	O
Belgian	O
who	O
is	O
here	O
?	O

He	O
has	O
been	O
a	O
most	O
famous	O
detective	O
.	O

Yes	O
.	O

I	O
want	O
you	O
to	O
let	O
me	O
call	O
him	O
in	O
...	O
to	O
investigate	O
this	O
matter	O
.	O

What	O
...	O
now	O
?	O

Before	O
the	O
post-mortem	O
?	O

Yes	O
,	O
time	O
is	O
an	O
advantage	O
if	O
...	O
if	O
...	O
there	O
has	O
been	O
foul	O
play	O
.	O

Rubbish	O
!	O

cried	O
Lawrence	B-PER
angrily	O
.	O

In	O
my	O
opinion	O
the	O
whole	O
thing	O
is	O
a	O
mare	O
's	O
nest	O
of	O
Bauerstein	B-PER
's	O
!	O

Wilkins	B-PER
had	O
n't	O
an	O
idea	O
of	O
such	O
a	O
thing	O
,	O
until	O
Bauerstein	B-PER
put	O
it	O
into	O
his	O
head	O
.	O

But	O
,	O
like	O
all	O
specialists	O
,	O
Bauerstein	B-PER
's	O
got	O
a	O
bee	O
in	O
his	O
bonnet	O
.	O

Poisons	O
are	O
his	O
hobby	O
,	O
so	O
of	O
course	O
he	O
sees	O
them	O
everywhere	O
.	O

I	O
confess	O
that	O
I	O
was	O
surprised	O
by	O
Lawrence	B-PER
's	O
attitude	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
so	O
seldom	O
vehement	O
about	O
anything	O
.	O

John	B-PER
hesitated	O
.	O

I	O
ca	O
n't	O
feel	O
as	O
you	O
do	O
,	O
Lawrence	B-PER
,	O
he	O
said	O
at	O
last	O
.	O

I	O
'm	O
inclined	O
to	O
give	O
Hastings	B-PER
a	O
free	O
hand	O
,	O
though	O
I	O
should	O
prefer	O
to	O
wait	O
a	O
bit	O
.	O

We	O
do	O
n't	O
want	O
any	O
unnecessary	O
scandal	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
no	O
,	O
I	O
cried	O
eagerly	O
,	O
you	O
need	O
have	O
no	O
fear	O
of	O
that	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
is	O
discretion	O
itself	O
.	O

Very	O
well	O
,	O
then	O
,	O
have	O
it	O
your	O
own	O
way	O
.	O

I	O
leave	O
it	O
in	O
your	O
hands	O
.	O

Though	O
,	O
if	O
it	O
is	O
as	O
we	O
suspect	O
,	O
it	O
seems	O
a	O
clear	O
enough	O
case	O
.	O

God	O
forgive	O
me	O
if	O
I	O
am	O
wronging	O
him	O
!	O

I	O
looked	O
at	O
my	O
watch	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
six	O
o'clock	O
.	O

I	O
determined	O
to	O
lose	O
no	O
time	O
.	O

Five	O
minutes	O
'	O
delay	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
I	O
allowed	O
myself	O
.	O

I	O
spent	O
it	O
in	O
ransacking	O
the	O
library	O
until	O
I	O
discovered	O
a	O
medical	O
book	O
which	O
gave	O
a	O
description	O
of	O
strychnine	O
poisoning	O
.	O

The	O
house	O
which	O
the	O
Belgians	O
occupied	O
in	O
the	O
village	O
was	O
quite	O
close	O
to	O
the	O
park	O
gates	O
.	O

One	O
could	O
save	O
time	O
by	O
taking	O
a	O
narrow	O
path	O
through	O
the	O
long	O
grass	O
,	O
which	O
cut	O
off	O
the	O
detours	O
of	O
the	O
winding	O
drive	O
.	O

So	O
I	O
,	O
accordingly	O
,	O
went	O
that	O
way	O
.	O

I	O
had	O
nearly	O
reached	O
the	O
lodge	O
,	O
when	O
my	O
attention	O
was	O
arrested	O
by	O
the	O
running	O
figure	O
of	O
a	O
man	O
approaching	O
me	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
Mr.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
.	O

Where	O
had	O
he	O
been	O
?	O

How	O
did	O
he	O
intend	O
to	O
explain	O
his	O
absence	O
?	O

He	O
accosted	O
me	O
eagerly	O
.	O

My	O
God	O
!	O

This	O
is	O
terrible	O
!	O

My	O
poor	O
wife	O
!	O

I	O
have	O
only	O
just	O
heard	O
.	O

Where	O
have	O
you	O
been	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
.	O

Denby	B-PER
kept	O
me	O
late	O
last	O
night	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
one	O
o'clock	O
before	O
we	O
'd	O
finished	O
.	O

Then	O
I	O
found	O
that	O
I	O
'd	O
forgotten	O
the	O
latch-key	O
after	O
all	O
.	O

I	O
did	O
n't	O
want	O
to	O
arouse	O
the	O
household	O
,	O
so	O
Denby	B-PER
gave	O
me	O
a	O
bed	O
.	O

How	O
did	O
you	O
hear	O
the	O
news	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
.	O

Wilkins	B-PER
knocked	O
Denby	B-PER
up	O
to	O
tell	O
him	O
.	O

My	O
poor	O
Emily	B-PER
!	O

She	O
was	O
so	O
self-sacrificing	O
...	O
such	O
a	O
noble	O
character	O
.	O

She	O
over-taxed	O
her	O
strength	O
.	O

A	O
wave	O
of	O
revulsion	O
swept	O
over	O
me	O
.	O

What	O
a	O
consummate	O
hypocrite	O
the	O
man	O
was	O
!	O

I	O
must	O
hurry	O
on	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
thankful	O
that	O
he	O
did	O
not	O
ask	O
me	O
whither	O
I	O
was	O
bound	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
few	O
minutes	O
I	O
was	O
knocking	O
at	O
the	O
door	O
of	O
Leastways	O
Cottage	O
.	O

Getting	O
no	O
answer	O
,	O
I	O
repeated	O
my	O
summons	O
impatiently	O
.	O

A	O
window	O
above	O
me	O
was	O
cautiously	O
opened	O
,	O
and	O
Poirot	B-PER
himself	O
looked	O
out	O
.	O

He	O
gave	O
an	O
exclamation	O
of	O
surprise	O
at	O
seeing	O
me	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
few	O
brief	O
words	O
,	O
I	O
explained	O
the	O
tragedy	O
that	O
had	O
occurred	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
I	O
wanted	O
his	O
help	O
.	O

Wait	O
,	O
my	O
friend	O
,	O
I	O
will	O
let	O
you	O
in	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
shall	O
recount	O
to	O
me	O
the	O
affair	O
whilst	O
I	O
dress	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
few	O
moments	O
he	O
had	O
unbarred	O
the	O
door	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
followed	O
him	O
up	O
to	O
his	O
room	O
.	O

There	O
he	O
installed	O
me	O
in	O
a	O
chair	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
related	O
the	O
whole	O
story	O
,	O
keeping	O
back	O
nothing	O
,	O
and	O
omitting	O
no	O
circumstance	O
,	O
however	O
insignificant	O
,	O
whilst	O
he	O
himself	O
made	O
a	O
careful	O
and	O
deliberate	O
toilet	O
.	O

I	O
told	O
him	O
of	O
my	O
awakening	O
,	O
of	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
dying	O
words	O
,	O
of	O
her	O
husband	O
's	O
absence	O
,	O
of	O
the	O
quarrel	O
the	O
day	O
before	O
,	O
of	O
the	O
scrap	O
of	O
conversation	O
between	O
Mary	B-PER
and	O
her	O
mother-in-law	O
that	O
I	O
had	O
overheard	O
,	O
of	O
the	O
former	O
quarrel	O
between	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
and	O
Evelyn	B-PER
Howard	I-PER
,	O
and	O
of	O
the	O
latter	O
's	O
innuendoes	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
hardly	O
as	O
clear	O
as	O
I	O
could	O
wish	O
.	O

I	O
repeated	O
myself	O
several	O
times	O
,	O
and	O
occasionally	O
had	O
to	O
go	O
back	O
to	O
some	O
detail	O
that	O
I	O
had	O
forgotten	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
smiled	O
kindly	O
on	O
me	O
.	O

The	O
mind	O
is	O
confused	O
?	O

Is	O
it	O
not	O
so	O
?	O

Take	O
time	O
,	O
mon	O
ami	O
.	O

``	O
You	O
are	O
agitated	O
;	O
you	O
are	O
excited	O
...	O
it	O
is	O
but	O
natural	O
.	O
''	O

Presently	O
,	O
when	O
we	O
are	O
calmer	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
arrange	O
the	O
facts	O
,	O
neatly	O
,	O
each	O
in	O
his	O
proper	O
place	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
examine	O
...	O
and	O
reject	O
.	O

``	O
Those	O
of	O
importance	O
we	O
will	O
put	O
on	O
one	O
side	O
;	O
those	O
of	O
no	O
importance	O
,	O
pouf	O
!	O

...	O
he	O
screwed	O
up	O
his	O
cherub-like	O
face	O
,	O
and	O
puffed	O
comically	O
enough	O
...	O
blow	O
them	O
away	O
!	O
''	O

That	O
's	O
all	O
very	O
well	O
,	O
I	O
objected	O
,	O
but	O
how	O
are	O
you	O
going	O
to	O
decide	O
what	O
is	O
important	O
,	O
and	O
what	O
is	O
n't	O
?	O

That	O
always	O
seems	O
the	O
difficulty	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
shook	O
his	O
head	O
energetically	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
now	O
arranging	O
his	O
moustache	O
with	O
exquisite	O
care	O
.	O

Not	O
so	O
.	O

Voyons	O
!	O

One	O
fact	O
leads	O
to	O
another	O
...	O
so	O
we	O
continue	O
.	O

Does	O
the	O
next	O
fit	O
in	O
with	O
that	O
?	O

A	O
merveille	O
!	O

Good	O
!	O

We	O
can	O
proceed	O
.	O

This	O
next	O
little	O
fact	O
...	O
no	O
!	O

Ah	O
,	O
that	O
is	O
curious	O
!	O

There	O
is	O
something	O
missing	O
...	O
a	O
link	O
in	O
the	O
chain	O
that	O
is	O
not	O
there	O
.	O

We	O
examine	O
.	O

We	O
search	O
.	O

And	O
that	O
little	O
curious	O
fact	O
,	O
that	O
possibly	O
paltry	O
little	O
detail	O
that	O
will	O
not	O
tally	O
,	O
we	O
put	O
it	O
here	O
!	O

He	O
made	O
an	O
extravagant	O
gesture	O
with	O
his	O
hand	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
significant	O
!	O

It	O
is	O
tremendous	O
!	O

Y.	O
.	O

.	O

es	O
...	O
Ah	O
!	O

Poirot	B-PER
shook	O
his	O
forefinger	O
so	O
fiercely	O
at	O
me	O
that	O
I	O
quailed	O
before	O
it	O
.	O

Beware	O
!	O

Peril	O
to	O
the	O
detective	O
who	O
says	O
:	O
`	O
It	O
is	O
so	O
small	O
...	O
it	O
does	O
not	O
matter	O
.	O

It	O
will	O
not	O
agree	O
.	O

I	O
will	O
forget	O
it	O
.	O
'	O

That	O
way	O
lies	O
confusion	O
!	O

Everything	O
matters	O
.	O

I	O
know	O
.	O

You	O
always	O
told	O
me	O
that	O
.	O

That	O
's	O
why	O
I	O
have	O
gone	O
into	O
all	O
the	O
details	O
of	O
this	O
thing	O
whether	O
they	O
seemed	O
to	O
me	O
relevant	O
or	O
not	O
.	O

And	O
I	O
am	O
pleased	O
with	O
you	O
.	O

You	O
have	O
a	O
good	O
memory	O
,	O
and	O
you	O
have	O
given	O
me	O
the	O
facts	O
faithfully	O
.	O

Of	O
the	O
order	O
in	O
which	O
you	O
present	O
them	O
,	O
I	O
say	O
nothing	O
...	O
truly	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
deplorable	O
!	O

But	O
I	O
make	O
allowances	O
...	O
you	O
are	O
upset	O
.	O

To	O
that	O
I	O
attribute	O
the	O
circumstance	O
that	O
you	O
have	O
omitted	O
one	O
fact	O
of	O
paramount	O
importance	O
.	O

What	O
is	O
that	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
.	O

You	O
have	O
not	O
told	O
me	O
if	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
ate	O
well	O
last	O
night	O
.	O

I	O
stared	O
at	O
him	O
.	O

Surely	O
the	O
war	O
had	O
affected	O
the	O
little	O
man	O
's	O
brain	O
.	O

He	O
was	O
carefully	O
engaged	O
in	O
brushing	O
his	O
coat	O
before	O
putting	O
it	O
on	O
,	O
and	O
seemed	O
wholly	O
engrossed	O
in	O
the	O
task	O
.	O

I	O
do	O
n't	O
remember	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
.	O

And	O
,	O
anyway	O
,	O
I	O
do	O
n't	O
see	O
...	O
.	O

You	O
do	O
not	O
see	O
?	O

But	O
it	O
is	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
importance	O
.	O

I	O
ca	O
n't	O
see	O
why	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
rather	O
nettled	O
.	O

As	O
far	O
as	O
I	O
can	O
remember	O
,	O
she	O
did	O
n't	O
eat	O
much	O
.	O

She	O
was	O
obviously	O
upset	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
had	O
taken	O
her	O
appetite	O
away	O
.	O

That	O
was	O
only	O
natural	O
.	O

Yes	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
thoughtfully	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
only	O
natural	O
.	O

He	O
opened	O
a	O
drawer	O
,	O
and	O
took	O
out	O
a	O
small	O
despatch-case	O
,	O
then	O
turned	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

Now	O
I	O
am	O
ready	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
proceed	O
to	O
the	O
chateau	O
,	O
and	O
study	O
matters	O
on	O
the	O
spot	O
.	O

Excuse	O
me	O
,	O
mon	O
ami	O
,	O
you	O
dressed	O
in	O
haste	O
,	O
and	O
your	O
tie	O
is	O
on	O
one	O
side	O
.	O

Permit	O
me	O
.	O

With	O
a	O
deft	O
gesture	O
,	O
he	O
rearranged	O
it	O
.	O

Ca-y-est	O
!	O

Now	O
,	O
shall	O
we	O
start	O
?	O

We	O
hurried	O
up	O
the	O
village	O
,	O
and	O
turned	O
in	O
at	O
the	O
lodge	O
gates	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
stopped	O
for	O
a	O
moment	O
,	O
and	O
gazed	O
sorrowfully	O
over	O
the	O
beautiful	O
expanse	O
of	O
park	O
,	O
still	O
glittering	O
with	O
morning	O
dew	O
.	O

So	O
beautiful	O
,	O
so	O
beautiful	O
,	O
and	O
yet	O
,	O
the	O
poor	O
family	O
,	O
plunged	O
in	O
sorrow	O
,	O
prostrated	O
with	O
grief	O
.	O

He	O
looked	O
at	O
me	O
keenly	O
as	O
he	O
spoke	O
,	O
and	O
I	O
was	O
aware	O
that	O
I	O
reddened	O
under	O
his	O
prolonged	O
gaze	O
.	O

Was	O
the	O
family	O
prostrated	O
by	O
grief	O
?	O

Was	O
the	O
sorrow	O
at	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
death	O
so	O
great	O
?	O

I	O
realized	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
an	O
emotional	O
lack	O
in	O
the	O
atmosphere	O
.	O

The	O
dead	O
woman	O
had	O
not	O
the	O
gift	O
of	O
commanding	O
love	O
.	O

Her	O
death	O
was	O
a	O
shock	O
and	O
a	O
distress	O
,	O
but	O
she	O
would	O
not	O
be	O
passionately	O
regretted	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
seemed	O
to	O
follow	O
my	O
thoughts	O
.	O

He	O
nodded	O
his	O
head	O
gravely	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
you	O
are	O
right	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
as	O
though	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
blood	O
tie	O
.	O

She	O
has	O
been	O
kind	O
and	O
generous	O
to	O
these	O
Cavendishes	O
,	O
but	O
she	O
was	O
not	O
their	O
own	O
mother	O
.	O

Blood	O
tells	O
...	O
always	O
remember	O
that	O
...	O
blood	O
tells	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
I	O
wish	O
you	O
would	O
tell	O
me	O
why	O
you	O
wanted	O
to	O
know	O
if	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
ate	O
well	O
last	O
night	O
?	O

I	O
have	O
been	O
turning	O
it	O
over	O
in	O
my	O
mind	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
ca	O
n't	O
see	O
how	O
it	O
has	O
anything	O
to	O
do	O
with	O
the	O
matter	O
?	O

He	O
was	O
silent	O
for	O
a	O
minute	O
or	O
two	O
as	O
we	O
walked	O
along	O
,	O
but	O
finally	O
he	O
said	O
:	O
I	O
do	O
not	O
mind	O
telling	O
you	O
...	O
though	O
,	O
as	O
you	O
know	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
my	O
habit	O
to	O
explain	O
until	O
the	O
end	O
is	O
reached	O
.	O

The	O
present	O
contention	O
is	O
that	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
died	O
of	O
strychnine	O
poisoning	O
,	O
presumably	O
administered	O
in	O
her	O
coffee	O
.	O

Yes	O
?	O

Well	O
,	O
what	O
time	O
was	O
the	O
coffee	O
served	O
?	O

About	O
eight	O
o'clock	O
.	O

Therefore	O
she	O
drank	O
it	O
between	O
then	O
and	O
half-past	O
eight	O
...	O
certainly	O
not	O
much	O
later	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
strychnine	O
is	O
a	O
fairly	O
rapid	O
poison	O
.	O

Its	O
effects	O
would	O
be	O
felt	O
very	O
soon	O
,	O
probably	O
in	O
about	O
an	O
hour	O
.	O

Yet	O
,	O
in	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
case	O
,	O
the	O
symptoms	O
do	O
not	O
manifest	O
themselves	O
until	O
five	O
o'clock	O
the	O
next	O
morning	O
:	O
nine	O
hours	O
!	O

But	O
a	O
heavy	O
meal	O
,	O
taken	O
at	O
about	O
the	O
same	O
time	O
as	O
the	O
poison	O
,	O
might	O
retard	O
its	O
effects	O
,	O
though	O
hardly	O
to	O
that	O
extent	O
.	O

Still	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
a	O
possibility	O
to	O
be	O
taken	O
into	O
account	O
.	O

But	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
you	O
,	O
she	O
ate	O
very	O
little	O
for	O
supper	O
,	O
and	O
yet	O
the	O
symptoms	O
do	O
not	O
develop	O
until	O
early	O
the	O
next	O
morning	O
!	O

Now	O
that	O
is	O
a	O
curious	O
circumstance	O
,	O
my	O
friend	O
.	O

Something	O
may	O
arise	O
at	O
the	O
autopsy	O
to	O
explain	O
it	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
meantime	O
,	O
remember	O
it	O
.	O

As	O
we	O
neared	O
the	O
house	O
,	O
John	B-PER
came	O
out	O
and	O
met	O
us	O
.	O

His	O
face	O
looked	O
weary	O
and	O
haggard	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
very	O
dreadful	O
business	O
,	O
Monsieur	B-PER
Poirot	I-PER
,	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

Hastings	B-PER
has	O
explained	O
to	O
you	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
anxious	O
for	O
no	O
publicity	O
?	O

I	O
comprehend	O
perfectly	O
.	O

You	O
see	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
only	O
suspicion	O
so	O
far	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
nothing	O
to	O
go	O
upon	O
.	O

Precisely	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
matter	O
of	O
precaution	O
only	O
.	O

John	B-PER
turned	O
to	O
me	O
,	O
taking	O
out	O
his	O
cigarette-case	O
,	O
and	O
lighting	O
a	O
cigarette	O
as	O
he	O
did	O
so	O
.	O

You	O
know	O
that	O
fellow	O
Inglethorp	B-PER
is	O
back	O
?	O

Yes	O
.	O

I	O
met	O
him	O
.	O

John	B-PER
flung	O
the	O
match	O
into	O
an	O
adjacent	O
flower	O
bed	O
,	O
a	O
proceeding	O
which	O
was	O
too	O
much	O
for	O
Poirot	B-PER
's	O
feelings	O
.	O

He	O
retrieved	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
buried	O
it	O
neatly	O
.	O

It	O
's	O
jolly	O
difficult	O
to	O
know	O
how	O
to	O
treat	O
him	O
.	O

That	O
difficulty	O
will	O
not	O
exist	O
long	O
,	O
pronounced	O
Poirot	B-PER
quietly	O
.	O

John	B-PER
looked	O
puzzled	O
,	O
not	O
quite	O
understanding	O
the	O
portent	O
of	O
this	O
cryptic	O
saying	O
.	O

He	O
handed	O
the	O
two	O
keys	O
which	O
Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
had	O
given	O
him	O
to	O
me	O
.	O

Show	O
Monsieur	B-PER
Poirot	I-PER
everything	O
he	O
wants	O
to	O
see	O
.	O

The	O
rooms	O
are	O
locked	O
?	O

asked	O
Poirot	B-PER
.	O

Dr	B-PER
Bauerstein	I-PER
considered	O
it	O
advisable	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
nodded	O
thoughtfully	O
.	O

Then	O
he	O
is	O
very	O
sure	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
that	O
simplifies	O
matters	O
for	O
us	O
.	O

We	O
went	O
up	O
together	O
to	O
the	O
room	O
of	O
the	O
tragedy	O
.	O

For	O
convenience	O
I	O
append	O
a	O
plan	O
of	O
the	O
room	O
and	O
the	O
principal	O
articles	O
of	O
furniture	O
in	O
it	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
locked	O
the	O
door	O
on	O
the	O
inside	O
,	O
and	O
proceeded	O
to	O
a	O
minute	O
inspection	O
of	O
the	O
room	O
.	O

He	O
darted	O
from	O
one	O
object	O
to	O
the	O
other	O
with	O
the	O
agility	O
of	O
a	O
grasshopper	O
.	O

I	O
remained	O
by	O
the	O
door	O
,	O
fearing	O
to	O
obliterate	O
any	O
clues	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
,	O
however	O
,	O
did	O
not	O
seem	O
grateful	O
to	O
me	O
for	O
my	O
forbearance	O
.	O

What	O
have	O
you	O
,	O
my	O
friend	O
,	O
he	O
cried	O
,	O
that	O
you	O
remain	O
there	O
like	O
...	O
how	O
do	O
you	O
say	O
it	O
?	O

...	O
ah	O
,	O
yes	O
,	O
the	O
stuck	O
pig	O
?	O

I	O
explained	O
that	O
I	O
was	O
afraid	O
of	O
obliterating	O
any	O
foot-marks	O
.	O

Foot-marks	O
?	O

But	O
what	O
an	O
idea	O
!	O

There	O
has	O
already	O
been	O
practically	O
an	O
army	O
in	O
the	O
room	O
!	O

What	O
foot-marks	O
are	O
we	O
likely	O
to	O
find	O
?	O

No	O
,	O
come	O
here	O
and	O
aid	O
me	O
in	O
my	O
search	O
.	O

I	O
will	O
put	O
down	O
my	O
little	O
case	O
until	O
I	O
need	O
it	O
.	O

``	O
He	O
did	O
so	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
round	O
table	O
by	O
the	O
window	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
was	O
an	O
ill-advised	O
proceeding	O
;	O
for	O
,	O
the	O
top	O
of	O
it	O
being	O
loose	O
,	O
it	O
tilted	O
up	O
,	O
and	O
precipitated	O
the	O
despatch-case	O
on	O
the	O
floor	O
.	O
''	O

Eh	O
voila	O
une	O
table	O
!	O

cried	O
Poirot	B-PER
.	O

Ah	O
,	O
my	O
friend	O
,	O
one	O
may	O
live	O
in	O
a	O
big	O
house	O
and	O
yet	O
have	O
no	O
comfort	O
.	O

After	O
which	O
piece	O
of	O
moralizing	O
,	O
he	O
resumed	O
his	O
search	O
.	O

A	O
small	O
purple	O
despatch-case	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
key	O
in	O
the	O
lock	O
,	O
on	O
the	O
writing-table	O
,	O
engaged	O
his	O
attention	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
.	O

He	O
took	O
out	O
the	O
key	O
from	O
the	O
lock	O
,	O
and	O
passed	O
it	O
to	O
me	O
to	O
inspect	O
.	O

I	O
saw	O
nothing	O
peculiar	O
,	O
however	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
an	O
ordinary	O
key	O
of	O
the	O
Yale	B-ORG
type	O
,	O
with	O
a	O
bit	O
of	O
twisted	O
wire	O
through	O
the	O
handle	O
.	O

Next	O
,	O
he	O
examined	O
the	O
framework	O
of	O
the	O
door	O
we	O
had	O
broken	O
in	O
,	O
assuring	O
himself	O
that	O
the	O
bolt	O
had	O
really	O
been	O
shot	O
.	O

Then	O
he	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
door	O
opposite	O
leading	O
into	O
Cynthia	B-PER
's	O
room	O
.	O

That	O
door	O
was	O
also	O
bolted	O
,	O
as	O
I	O
had	O
stated	O
.	O

``	O
However	O
,	O
he	O
went	O
to	O
the	O
length	O
of	O
unbolting	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
opening	O
and	O
shutting	O
it	O
several	O
times	O
;	O
this	O
he	O
did	O
with	O
the	O
utmost	O
precaution	O
against	O
making	O
any	O
noise	O
.	O
''	O

Suddenly	O
something	O
in	O
the	O
bolt	O
itself	O
seemed	O
to	O
rivet	O
his	O
attention	O
.	O

He	O
examined	O
it	O
carefully	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
,	O
nimbly	O
whipping	O
out	O
a	O
pair	O
of	O
small	O
forceps	O
from	O
his	O
case	O
,	O
he	O
drew	O
out	O
some	O
minute	O
particle	O
which	O
he	O
carefully	O
sealed	O
up	O
in	O
a	O
tiny	O
envelope	O
.	O

On	O
the	O
chest	O
of	O
drawers	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
tray	O
with	O
a	O
spirit	O
lamp	O
and	O
a	O
small	O
saucepan	O
on	O
it	O
.	O

A	O
small	O
quantity	O
of	O
a	O
dark	O
fluid	O
remained	O
in	O
the	O
saucepan	O
,	O
and	O
an	O
empty	O
cup	O
and	O
saucer	O
that	O
had	O
been	O
drunk	O
out	O
of	O
stood	O
near	O
it	O
.	O

I	O
wondered	O
how	O
I	O
could	O
have	O
been	O
so	O
unobservant	O
as	O
to	O
overlook	O
this	O
.	O

Here	O
was	O
a	O
clue	O
worth	O
having	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
delicately	O
dipped	O
his	O
finger	O
into	O
liquid	O
,	O
and	O
tasted	O
it	O
gingerly	O
.	O

He	O
made	O
a	O
grimace	O
.	O

cocoa	O
...	O
with	O
...	O
I	O
think	O
...	O
rum	O
in	O
it	O
.	O

He	O
passed	O
on	O
to	O
the	O
debris	O
on	O
the	O
floor	O
,	O
where	O
the	O
table	O
by	O
the	O
bed	O
had	O
been	O
overturned	O
.	O

A	O
reading-lamp	O
,	O
some	O
books	O
,	O
matches	O
,	O
a	O
bunch	O
of	O
keys	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
crushed	O
fragments	O
of	O
a	O
coffee-cup	O
lay	O
scattered	O
about	O
.	O

Ah	O
,	O
this	O
is	O
curious	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
.	O

I	O
must	O
confess	O
that	O
I	O
see	O
nothing	O
particularly	O
curious	O
about	O
it	O
.	O

You	O
do	O
not	O
?	O

``	O
Observe	O
the	O
lamp	O
...	O
the	O
chimney	O
is	O
broken	O
in	O
two	O
places	O
;	O
they	O
lie	O
there	O
as	O
they	O
fell	O
.	O
''	O

But	O
see	O
,	O
the	O
coffee-cup	O
is	O
absolutely	O
smashed	O
to	O
powder	O
.	O

Well	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
wearily	O
,	O
I	O
suppose	O
some	O
one	O
must	O
have	O
stepped	O
on	O
it	O
.	O

Exactly	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
,	O
in	O
an	O
odd	O
voice	O
.	O

Some	O
one	O
stepped	O
on	O
it	O
.	O

He	O
rose	O
from	O
his	O
knees	O
,	O
and	O
walked	O
slowly	O
across	O
to	O
the	O
mantelpiece	O
,	O
where	O
he	O
stood	O
abstractedly	O
fingering	O
the	O
ornaments	O
,	O
and	O
straightening	O
them	O
...	O
a	O
trick	O
of	O
his	O
when	O
he	O
was	O
agitated	O
.	O

Mon	O
ami	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
turning	O
to	O
me	O
,	O
somebody	O
stepped	O
on	O
that	O
cup	O
,	O
grinding	O
it	O
to	O
powder	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
reason	O
they	O
did	O
so	O
was	O
either	O
because	O
it	O
contained	O
strychnine	O
or	O
...	O
which	O
is	O
far	O
more	O
serious	O
...	O
because	O
it	O
did	O
not	O
contain	O
strychnine	O
!	O

I	O
made	O
no	O
reply	O
.	O

I	O
was	O
bewildered	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
knew	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
no	O
good	O
asking	O
him	O
to	O
explain	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
moment	O
or	O
two	O
he	O
roused	O
himself	O
,	O
and	O
went	O
on	O
with	O
his	O
investigations	O
.	O

He	O
picked	O
up	O
the	O
bunch	O
of	O
keys	O
from	O
the	O
floor	O
,	O
and	O
twirling	O
them	O
round	O
in	O
his	O
fingers	O
finally	O
selected	O
one	O
,	O
very	O
bright	O
and	O
shining	O
,	O
which	O
he	O
tried	O
in	O
the	O
lock	O
of	O
the	O
purple	O
despatch-case	O
.	O

It	O
fitted	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
opened	O
the	O
box	O
,	O
but	O
after	O
a	O
moment	O
's	O
hesitation	O
,	O
closed	O
and	O
relocked	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
slipped	O
the	O
bunch	O
of	O
keys	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
the	O
key	O
that	O
had	O
originally	O
stood	O
in	O
the	O
lock	O
,	O
into	O
his	O
own	O
pocket	O
.	O

I	O
have	O
no	O
authority	O
to	O
go	O
through	O
these	O
papers	O
.	O

But	O
it	O
should	O
be	O
done	O
...	O
at	O
once	O
!	O

He	O
then	O
made	O
a	O
very	O
careful	O
examination	O
of	O
the	O
drawers	O
of	O
the	O
wash-stand	O
.	O

Crossing	O
the	O
room	O
to	O
the	O
left-hand	O
window	O
,	O
a	O
round	O
stain	O
,	O
hardly	O
visible	O
on	O
the	O
dark	O
brown	O
carpet	O
,	O
seemed	O
to	O
interest	O
him	O
particularly	O
.	O

He	O
went	O
down	O
on	O
his	O
knees	O
,	O
examining	O
it	O
minutely	O
...	O
even	O
going	O
so	O
far	O
as	O
to	O
smell	O
it	O
.	O

Finally	O
,	O
he	O
poured	O
a	O
few	O
drops	O
of	O
the	O
cocoa	O
into	O
a	O
test	O
tube	O
,	O
sealing	O
it	O
up	O
carefully	O
.	O

His	O
next	O
proceeding	O
was	O
to	O
take	O
out	O
a	O
little	O
notebook	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
found	O
in	O
this	O
room	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
writing	O
busily	O
,	O
six	O
points	O
of	O
interest	O
.	O

Shall	O
I	O
enumerate	O
them	O
,	O
or	O
will	O
you	O
?	O

Oh	O
,	O
you	O
,	O
I	O
replied	O
hastily	O
.	O

Very	O
well	O
,	O
then	O
.	O

``	O
One	O
,	O
a	O
coffee-cup	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
ground	O
into	O
powder	O
;	O
two	O
,	O
a	O
despatch-case	O
with	O
a	O
key	O
in	O
the	O
lock	O
;	O
three	O
,	O
a	O
stain	O
on	O
the	O
floor	O
.	O
''	O

That	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
done	O
some	O
time	O
ago	O
,	O
I	O
interrupted	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
for	O
it	O
is	O
still	O
perceptibly	O
damp	O
and	O
smells	O
of	O
coffee	O
.	O

Four	O
,	O
a	O
fragment	O
of	O
some	O
dark	O
green	O
fabric	O
...	O
only	O
a	O
thread	O
or	O
two	O
,	O
but	O
recognizable	O
.	O

Ah	O
!	O

I	O
cried	O
.	O

That	O
was	O
what	O
you	O
sealed	O
up	O
in	O
the	O
envelope	O
.	O

Yes	O
.	O

It	O
may	O
turn	O
out	O
to	O
be	O
a	O
piece	O
of	O
one	O
of	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
own	O
dresses	O
,	O
and	O
quite	O
unimportant	O
.	O

We	O
shall	O
see	O
.	O

Five	O
,	O
...	O
this	O
...	O
!	O

With	O
a	O
dramatic	O
gesture	O
,	O
he	O
pointed	O
to	O
a	O
large	O
splash	O
of	O
candle	O
grease	O
on	O
the	O
floor	O
by	O
the	O
writing-table	O
.	O

It	O
must	O
have	O
been	O
done	O
since	O
yesterday	O
,	O
otherwise	O
a	O
good	O
housemaid	O
would	O
have	O
at	O
once	O
removed	O
it	O
with	O
blotting-paper	O
and	O
a	O
hot	O
iron	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
my	O
best	O
hats	O
once	O
...	O
but	O
that	O
is	O
not	O
to	O
the	O
point	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
very	O
likely	O
done	O
last	O
night	O
.	O

We	O
were	O
very	O
agitated	O
.	O

Or	O
perhaps	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
herself	O
dropped	O
her	O
candle	O
.	O

You	O
brought	O
only	O
one	O
candle	O
into	O
the	O
room	O
?	O

Yes	O
.	O

Lawrence	B-PER
Cavendish	I-PER
was	O
carrying	O
it	O
.	O

But	O
he	O
was	O
very	O
upset	O
.	O

He	O
seemed	O
to	O
see	O
something	O
over	O
here	O
...	O
I	O
indicated	O
the	O
mantelpiece	O
...	O
that	O
absolutely	O
paralysed	O
him	O
.	O

That	O
is	O
interesting	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
quickly	O
.	O

``	O
Yes	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
suggestive	O
...	O
his	O
eye	O
sweeping	O
the	O
whole	O
length	O
of	O
the	O
wall	O
...	O
but	O
it	O
was	O
not	O
his	O
candle	O
that	O
made	O
this	O
great	O
patch	O
,	O
for	O
you	O
perceive	O
that	O
this	O
is	O
white	O
grease	O
;	O
whereas	O
Monsieur	B-PER
Lawrence	I-PER
's	O
candle	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
still	O
on	O
the	O
dressing-table	O
,	O
is	O
pink	O
.	O
''	O

On	O
the	O
other	O
hand	O
,	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
had	O
no	O
candlestick	O
in	O
the	O
room	O
,	O
only	O
a	O
reading-lamp	O
.	O

Then	O
,	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
what	O
do	O
you	O
deduce	O
?	O

To	O
which	O
my	O
friend	O
only	O
made	O
a	O
rather	O
irritating	O
reply	O
,	O
urging	O
me	O
to	O
use	O
my	O
own	O
natural	O
faculties	O
.	O

And	O
the	O
sixth	O
point	O
?	O

I	O
asked	O
.	O

I	O
suppose	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
sample	O
of	O
cocoa	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
thoughtfully	O
.	O

I	O
might	O
have	O
included	O
that	O
in	O
the	O
six	O
,	O
but	O
I	O
did	O
not	O
.	O

No	O
,	O
the	O
sixth	O
point	O
I	O
will	O
keep	O
to	O
myself	O
for	O
the	O
present	O
.	O

He	O
looked	O
quickly	O
round	O
the	O
room	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
nothing	O
more	O
to	O
be	O
done	O
here	O
,	O
I	O
think	O
,	O
unless	O
...	O
he	O
stared	O
earnestly	O
and	O
long	O
at	O
the	O
dead	O
ashes	O
in	O
the	O
grate	O
.	O

The	O
fire	O
burns	O
...	O
and	O
it	O
destroys	O
.	O

But	O
by	O
chance	O
...	O
there	O
might	O
be	O
...	O
let	O
us	O
see	O
!	O

Deftly	O
,	O
on	O
hands	O
and	O
knees	O
,	O
he	O
began	O
to	O
sort	O
the	O
ashes	O
from	O
the	O
grate	O
into	O
the	O
fender	O
,	O
handling	O
them	O
with	O
the	O
greatest	O
caution	O
.	O

Suddenly	O
,	O
he	O
gave	O
a	O
faint	O
exclamation	O
.	O

The	O
forceps	O
,	O
Hastings	B-PER
!	O

I	O
quickly	O
handed	O
them	O
to	O
him	O
,	O
and	O
with	O
skill	O
he	O
extracted	O
a	O
small	O
piece	O
of	O
half	O
charred	O
paper	O
.	O

There	O
,	O
mon	O
ami	O
!	O

he	O
cried	O
.	O

What	O
do	O
you	O
think	O
of	O
that	O
?	O

I	O
scrutinized	O
the	O
fragment	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
an	O
exact	O
reproduction	O
of	O
it	O
:	O
...	O
I	O
was	O
puzzled	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
unusually	O
thick	O
,	O
quite	O
unlike	O
ordinary	O
notepaper	O
.	O

Suddenly	O
an	O
idea	O
struck	O
me	O
.	O

Poirot	B-PER
!	O

I	O
cried	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
a	O
fragment	O
of	O
a	O
will	O
!	O

Exactly	O
.	O

I	O
looked	O
up	O
at	O
him	O
sharply	O
.	O

You	O
are	O
not	O
surprised	O
?	O

No	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
gravely	O
,	O
I	O
expected	O
it	O
.	O

I	O
relinquished	O
the	O
piece	O
of	O
paper	O
,	O
and	O
watched	O
him	O
put	O
it	O
away	O
in	O
his	O
case	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
same	O
methodical	O
care	O
that	O
he	O
bestowed	O
on	O
everything	O
.	O

My	O
brain	O
was	O
in	O
a	O
whirl	O
.	O

What	O
was	O
this	O
complication	O
of	O
a	O
will	O
?	O

Who	O
had	O
destroyed	O
it	O
?	O

The	O
person	O
who	O
had	O
left	O
the	O
candle	O
grease	O
on	O
the	O
floor	O
?	O

Obviously	O
.	O

But	O
how	O
had	O
anyone	O
gained	O
admission	O
?	O

All	O
the	O
doors	O
had	O
been	O
bolted	O
on	O
the	O
inside	O
.	O

Now	O
,	O
my	O
friend	O
,	O
said	O
Poirot	B-PER
briskly	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
go	O
.	O

I	O
should	O
like	O
to	O
ask	O
a	O
few	O
questions	O
of	O
the	O
parlourmaid	O
...	O
Dorcas	B-PER
,	O
her	O
name	O
is	O
,	O
is	O
it	O
not	O
?	O

We	O
passed	O
through	O
Alfred	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
room	O
,	O
and	O
Poirot	B-PER
delayed	O
long	O
enough	O
to	O
make	O
a	O
brief	O
but	O
fairly	O
comprehensive	O
examination	O
of	O
it	O
.	O

We	O
went	O
out	O
through	O
that	O
door	O
,	O
locking	O
both	O
it	O
and	O
that	O
of	O
Mrs.	B-PER
Inglethorp	I-PER
's	O
room	O
as	O
before	O
.	O
